<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>LSU History Oral History Project: SGA Past Presidents</title>
      <subTitle>Roger Houston Ogden oral history interview, 1994</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="">
      <namePart xmlns:lsu="http://lsu.edu">Dean, Pamela</namePart>
      <namePart xmlns:lsu="http://lsu.edu" type="date">1946-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewer</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ivr</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description/>
   </name>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary">
      <namePart>Ogden, Roger Houston</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewee</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ive</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description>Roger Ogden was born in 1946 in Denver, Colorado to Roger Hadfield Ogden
            and Mary Catherine Schneider. His parents moved to Shreveport, Louisiana, just after his
            birth. Ogden started his elementary education at A.C. Steere School in Shreveport, and
            continued in Lafayette at Hamilton Laboratory School, part of Southwestern Louisiana
            Institute. He graduated from Lafayette High School in 1964 and entered LSU that same
            year, joining Kappa Sigma Fraternity and serving as Freshman Class President. He served
            as a Senatorial Intern to Russell Long in the summer of 1967 and was LSU Student Body
            President from 1967-1968. He graduated from LSU in 1968 with a B.S. in Business. He was
            awarded the Rotary International Fellowship for Graduate Study at the University of
            London School of Economics and Political Science, but was unable to pursue the
            fellowship due to the Selective Service Board denying him permission to travel abroad.
            He soon went on to Tulane University Law School, graduating in 1971. He worked in
            corporate litigation for several years with Lemle, Kelleher, Kohlmeyer and Matthews Law
            Firm in New Orleans. In 1975, with LSU classmate James Maurin, he founded Maurin-Ogden,
            Inc., a real estate development company. Ogden served on the LSU Board of Supervisors,
            LSU Alumni Association, LSU Foundation, and was involved with the university in many
            other ways. He is active in countless civic and professional organizations, and has a
            large art collection that was the basis for the Ogden Museum of Southern Art in New
            Orleans. Ogden is divorced from Ann Waits; the couple had one son,
            Field.</description>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1994</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">5 sound cassettes</note>
      <extent>10 hours, 32 minutes</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">
            Transcript</note>
      <extent>272 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>sound recording</typeOfResource>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Ogden, Roger Houston--Interviews.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Long, Russell B.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Louisiana State University
            (Baton Rouge, La.)--Students.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.).--Board of
            Supervisors.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.).--College of Business
            Administration.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">LSU Alumni Association.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">African Americans--Civil rights--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Art, American--Southern States.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Art--Collectors and collecting--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Civic
            improvement--Louisiana--New Orleans.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">College sports--Louisiana--Baton Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">College
            student government--Louisiana--Baton Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Greek letter societies--Louisiana--Baton
            Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Lawyers--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Real estate developers--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Real estate
            development--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest movements--Louisiana--Baton
            Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <identifier>Mss. 4700.0519</identifier>
   <note type="ownership">Louisiana State University Libraries Special Collections
            (http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special)</note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained by
            Louisiana State University in accordance with U.S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See
            instructions for ordering reprints of this audio here:
            http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special/services/duplication.html Mention the ""Item number"" or
            ""Item URL"" in your request. "</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Hill Memorial Library, Special
                        Collections</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>L:
                        4700.0519</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <abstract xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu/services/oralhistory/abstracts/university/sga/Ogden_Roger_AllTapes.pdf">Ogden provides a detailed biography of his life, from his early years and education
            in Shreveport and Lafayette, Louisiana, through his time at Louisiana State University,
            to his successes as a lawyer and later as a real estate developer. He focuses primarily
            on his undergraduate years at LSU, discussing his campaigns and tenures as Freshman
            Class and Student Body President; procedures of Student Government Association and
            Student Assembly; the end of compulsory ROTC for male students; the political climate on
            campus in the mid to late 1960s; Vietnam War protests on campus; student leaders; Greek
            organizations; fraternity houses; fraternity hazing and pledging; dormitories; student
            activities on and off campus; athletics; university administrators; his favorite
            professors, and much more. Ogden goes into great detail about his experiences as
            Senatorial intern to Russell Long in the summer of 1967, and gives his insights into
            Long's character and motivations. He recounts his time as a lawyer in New Orleans in the
            early 1970s, his transition into real estate development, and his first few residential
            and commercial development projects. Ogden discusses the origin of his collection of
            southern art and touches on many other topics such as racism, integration and
            desegregation, civil rights; the oil and gas business in Texas and Louisiana; his
            parents' backgrounds, LSU's Business School, civic improvement projects in New Orleans,
            and his continued involvement with LSU through the Alumni Association and as a member of
            the Board of Supervisors.</abstract>
</mods>
