<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>LSU History Oral History Project: Alumni</title>
      <subTitle>Thomas Fuller Ruffin oral history interview, 2000-2005.</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="">
      <namePart>Abraham, Jennifer,</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewer</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ivr</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description/>
   </name>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary">
      <namePart>Ruffin, Thomas F. </namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewee</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ive</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description>"Thomas Fuller Ruffin was born in Shreveport, La., in 1925, and graduated
            from C.E. Byrd High School. He served with the U.S. Navy during World War II in the
            Atlantic, Caribbean, and Pacific, and continued to serve in China after the war. Ruffin
            graduated from Louisiana State University with a B.S. in Mechanical Engineering in 1947.
            He was the president of Ruffin Brick Co. and Ruffin Transportation, Inc., then worked
            for four decades in the stock brokerage industry, retiring as Vice President of Smith
            Barney, Inc. Ruffin served on the board of many organizations during his lifetime,
            including the Volunteers of America, the LSU Athletic Council, and the Louisiana
            Historical Association. He also served as National Vice President of the U.S. Jaycees.
            Ruffin published over 75 articles on the history of the Ark-La-Tex area, and was the
            author of ""Under Stately Oaks: A Pictorial History of LSU."" He was married to Joyce
            Lucille Toler and after her death married Carol Miller Baker. Ruffin and Baker were
            married for thirteen years until his death on April 30, 2009."</description>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>2000-2005.</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">5 sound cassettes</note>
      <extent>6 hours, 23 minutes</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">2 digital audio files</note>
      <extent>2
            hours, 16 minutes</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Abstract</note>
      <extent>9 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Transcript</note>
      <extent>214 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Index</note>
      <extent>16
            leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>sound recording</typeOfResource>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Ruffin, Thomas F.--Interviews.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Ruffin, Joyce Lucille Toler.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">United
            States.--Navy--Military life.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Louisiana State University and Agricultural and
            Mechanical College--Students.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Louisiana State University and Agricultural and
            Mechanical College.--Reserve Officers Training Corps.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Acme Brick Company--Employees.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Redman Industries--Employees.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Merrill Lynch &amp; Co. (1973- )--Employees.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Frances I.
            du Pont Company--Employees.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Jaycees International.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">LSU Alumni Association.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Business
            brokerage--Louisiana--Shreveport.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Depressions--1929--Louisiana--Shreveport.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Depressions--1929--Texas--Dallas.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Education--Louisiana--Shreveport.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Military
            education--Louisiana--Baton Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Voluntarism--Louisiana--Shreveport.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Volunteer
            workers in community development--Louisiana--Shreveport.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">World War,
            1939-1945--China--Personal narratives, American.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">World War, 1939-1945--Veterans--United
            States.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Baton Rouge (La.)--Social life and customs--20th century.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">China--Social
            conditions--1912-1949.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Dallas (Tex.)--Social conditions--20th century.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Dallas
            (Tex.)--Social life and customs--20th century.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Shreveport (La.)--Social
            conditions--20th century.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Shreveport (La.)--Social life and customs--20th century.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">West (U.S.)--Description and travel.</topic>
   </subject>
   <identifier>Mss. 4700.1364</identifier>
   <note type="ownership">Louisiana State University Libraries Special Collections
            (http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special)</note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained by
            Louisiana State University in accordance with U.S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See
            instructions for ordering reprints of this audio here:
            http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special/services/duplication.html Mention the ""Item number"" or
            ""Item URL"" in your request. "</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Hill Memorial Library, Special
                        Collections</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>L:
                        4700.1364</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <abstract xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu/services/oralhistory/abstracts/university/distinguished_alumni/Ruffin_Thomas_all_tapes.abs.pdf">"Session I, which is transcribed, describes Ruffin's family and early life in
            Shreveport and Dallas, an incident where he was severely burned as a child when his
            nightgown caught on fire, his favorite teachers and subjects in elementary and high
            school, traveling for school clubs and on a trip through the West with his extended
            family, his hearing about the bombing of Pearl Harbor and losing friends in World War
            II, and his attending LSU and the activities he participated in as a student there.;
            Session II, which is transcribed, describes his youth and experience of the Depression
            in Shreveport and Dallas, his father's employment with Acme Brick Company, recreation
            and shopping in Shreveport and Dallas, transportation, his diverse neighborhood and
            classmates at Alexander School in Shreveport, religious beliefs, downtown Shreveport,
            Louisiana politicians and governors, C.E. Byrd and Fair Park High Schools in Shreveport,
            his coursework at LSU and student life there in the early to mid-1940s, ROTC and
            military service with the Navy, radar school and engineering classes at the University
            of Illinois and Columbia University, his experiences in Los Angeles and New York while
            enlisted, the perks of being in uniform during the war, his involvement with the
            Jaycees, accounts of veterans from the Civil War and World Wars I &amp; II, and the
            devastation in Europe after World War II.; Session III, which is transcribed, describes
            classes and experiences at LSU before and after he served in World War II, military
            training at LSU, campus buildings, dining and recreation around campus, downtown Baton
            Rouge, urban transportation, the effect of students leaving for the war, dances, his
            favorite classes and professors, military leaders at LSU, daily life in ROTC, and how
            ROTC prepared him for the Navy.; Session IV, which is transcribed, relates recollections
            of Navy service in Los Angeles, Honolulu, Shanghai, and Hong Kong; political strife in
            China between Nationalists and Communists; people he befriended or helped in Hong Kong
            and Shanghai, including a man who wrote on scrolls and a little boy who helped him
            escape a fire fight; prostitution in China; people living on the streets and the high
            death rate; his view of Chinese culture and customs; his duties on board ship and on
            shore patrol; the process of being discharged from the Navy; providing medical aid to a
            boy who later died of cholera; trying to resolve fights among enlisted men and between
            enlisted men and locals; receiving mail on the ship; and his feelings on veterans of
            different wars.; Session V, which is transcribed, describes his work for the Acme Brick
            Company in Fort Worth and Shreveport; his involvement with the Jaycees in Shreveport and
            the community issues they tackled; marrying his wife, Joyce Toler, and their honeymoon;
            service as Jaycees state president then national vice president, including campaigning
            for positions and campaigns he undertook like teen driving safety and anti-fly and
            mosquito spraying; his meetings with several U.S. presidents; a story about Earl Long;
            his positive experiences from the Jaycees and feeling that the organization has
            weakened; and understanding other cultures and getting along with people he meets.;
            Session VI, which is indexed, discusses his work with Redman Industries in California,
            Merrill Lynch in San Antonio, and the Frances I. du Pont Company in Shreveport; his
            experiences in the brokerage business, including changes over time, technology, buyouts
            from other companies, female and minority employees, and stock strategies; service with
            the LSU Alumni Association; his perception that Louisiana lags behind; service with
            other organizations and boards; incidents of racism he's witnessed; information about
            his family; his interest in history, articles he's written, and the research and
            publishing of ""Under Stately Oaks; "" and interesting facts from LSU's
            history."</abstract>
</mods>
