<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Bayou Lafourche Oral History Project</title>
      <subTitle>John Doucet oral history interview, 2010</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="">
      <namePart>Branton, Ryan,</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewer</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ivr</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description/>
   </name>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary">
      <namePart>Doucet, John P. </namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewee</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ive</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description>John Doucet was born in 1962 in Golden Meadow, La., the son of Herman
            Joseph Doucet, an oil field worker, and Dora Rebstock Doucet, a homemaker; he is one of
            five children. In his youth he spent a significant amount of time with his
            French-speaking grandparents, and a good deal of time with his family, but was rather
            isolated from the larger community. His father passed away when Doucet was twelve, but
            before his death encouraged Doucet to study science. Mentorship in middle school and
            high school, along with a local, regional, and national recognition, laid the groundwork
            for Doucet's scientific career. As a first-generation college student, Doucet studied
            chemistry at Nicholls State University. After completing his doctoral studies in
            biochemistry and molecular biology at Louisiana State University Medical Center in New
            Orleans, he received a National Institute of Health fellowship to study genetics, also
            at LSUMC. His team conducted research on Usher's syndrome, which disproportionately
            affects people of Acadian descent. His team identified the genetic mutation that causes
            Usher's, and his research has continued to focus on people of Acadian descent. Doucet
            joined the biology department of Nicholls State in 1999. He has served as the head of
            the Biology Department (three years) and honors program (nine years), and in 2012 was
            selected to serve as Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences. Doucet became Louisiana's
            first certified public health geneticist in 2010, and the first to serve on the national
            Education Board of the American Society of Human Genetics. He has written over a dozen
            plays about Louisiana's Cajun culture, and a number of history texts about Bayou
            Lafourche. A practicing Catholic, Doucet served as an altar boy; as an adult he
            continues to have a strong faith in God, which he believes can coexist with his
            scientific research. He and his wife, also a Bayou Lafourche native, have two
            children.</description>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>2010</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">1 digital audio file</note>
      <extent>1 hour, 3 minutes</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Abstract</note>
      <extent>5 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Index
           </note>
      <extent>7 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>sound recording</typeOfResource>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Doucet, John P.--Interviews.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Catholic Church--Louisiana--Lafourche Parish.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Nicholls State University--Faculty.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Cajun French dialect--Louisiana--Lafourche Parish.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Cajuns--Health and hygiene--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Cajuns--Louisiana--Social life and customs.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Catholic scientists--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Dramatists, American--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Geneticists--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Grandparent and child--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Hurricane Betsy, 1965.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Religion and science--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Usher's syndrome--Research--Louisiana.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Golden Meadow
            (La.)--Social life and customs.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Lafourche Parish (La.)--Social life and
            customs.</topic>
   </subject>
   <identifier>Mss. 4700.2099</identifier>
   <note type="ownership">Louisiana State University Libraries Special Collections
            (http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special)</note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained by
            Louisiana State University in accordance with U.S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See
            instructions for ordering reprints of this audio here:
            http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special/services/duplication.html Mention the ""Item number"" or
            ""Item URL"" in your request. "</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Hill Memorial Library, Special
                        Collections</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>L:
                        4700.2099</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <abstract xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu/services/oralhistory/abstracts/bayoulafourche/Doucet_John_T3945.pdf">"Doucet discusses his childhood growing up in Golden Meadow, how he interacted with
            his father, who was often gone because of his work on the oil rigs, and losing his
            father at age twelve. Doucet acknowledges how the community rallied to support him and
            his brother, including mentors at school and in the extended family, but his family was
            a close-knit one, and they rarely spent time with the larger community. Growing up
            Doucet spent a good deal of time with his grandparents, who spoke Cajun French, and he
            internalized their language such that he could reproduce many of their characteristics
            in plays he wrote as an adult. He also discusses the role and history of French in his
            family and on the bayou. The Doucets were very involved in the church, and Doucet served
            as an altar boy. Science was important from an early age. After making a perfect score
            in a third-grade science exam, Doucet's father, and later teachers, encouraged him to
            pursue a career in science, which led him to many science fairs and eventually, a
            doctorate in molecular biology at LSU Medical Center in New Orleans. He recalls his
            first memories are of the 1965 Hurricane Betsy, which nearly flooded their house. His
            post-doctoral genetic research of Usher's syndrome, which disproportionally affects
            Acadians, led to the discovery of the genetic mutation responsible, and brought him back
            to Acadian culture. He discusses how he got the job at Nicholls and how, since arriving
            he has continued to conduct genetic research with Acadians and with other subjects of
            South Louisiana interest, including local animals like love bugs and crawfish. Doucet
            discusses the role of religion in his life, with particular emphasis on its intersection
            with science, and the importance and definition of ""home"" in his life."</abstract>
</mods>
