<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>LSU History Oral History Project: Faculty &amp; Adminstrators</title>
      <subTitle>Miles Edward Richardson oral history interview, 2000-2006.</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="">
      <namePart>Abraham, Jennifer,</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewer</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ivr</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description/>
   </name>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary">
      <namePart xmlns:lsu="http://lsu.edu">Richardson, Miles</namePart>
      <namePart xmlns:lsu="http://lsu.edu" type="date">1932-2011</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewee</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ive</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description>Miles Edward Richardson was born in Palestine, Tex., to Mark Carl and
            Florence Adams Richardson in 1932. He dropped out of high school in December 1949, a few
            months before he was due to graduate, and immediately joined the U.S. Air Force.
            Richardson stayed in the Air Force for four years, serving in the Korean War while he
            was stationed in Okinawa, Japan, for two years. After leaving the service, he slowly
            began taking college classes and eventually wound up at Stephen F. Austin State College,
            where he completed his B.S. in biology and history in 1957. That same year, he started
            the master's program in anthropology at Louisiana State University. After only one year
            there, Richardson transferred to the Ph.D. program at Tulane University. While a student
            at Tulane, he married a fellow student, Valerie Woodger. Richardson was able to go to
            Colombia on a medical grant and he did his dissertation fieldwork in San Pedro,
            Colombia, in 1962-63. For the next two years, while completing his Ph.D. at Tulane in
            the summers, he taught at Indiana State College (now Indiana University of
            Pennsylvania). Richardson earned his Ph.D. from Tulane in the spring of 1965 and started
            teaching at LSU that fall. He remained at LSU as a professor of anthropology for the
            next forty years. He was Departmental Chair (1970-72) and Acting Chair (1986-87). He
            held the Fred B. Kniffen Professorship and the Doris Z. Stone Professorship and served
            in numerous professional organizations including the Society for Humanistic Anthropology
            and the Southern Anthropological Society. Throughout his career, he conducted fieldwork
            in the southern U.S. and Latin America and authored several books and numerous scholarly
            articles, as well as several poems and short stories. Richardson died at the age of 79
            on November 14, 2011.</description>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>2000-2006.</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">2 sound cassettes</note>
      <extent>1 hour, 30 minutes</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">3digital audio files</note>
      <extent>3 hours,
            12 minutes</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Abstract</note>
      <extent>6 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Transcript</note>
      <extent>50 p</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>sound recording</typeOfResource>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Richardson, Miles, 1932-2011--Interviews.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Richardson, Valerie Thorn Woodger,
            1937-</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">La Violette, Forrest Emmanuel, 1904-</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Haag, William George, 1910-2000.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Louisiana
            State University and Agricultural and Mechanical College--Faculty.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Louisiana State
            University and Agricultural and Mechanical College--Students.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Stephen F. Austin State
            College--Students.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Tulane University--Students.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">United States.--Air
            Force--History--Korean War, 1950-1953.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Anthropology--Research--Colombia.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Anthropology--Research--Louisiana--New Orleans.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">African Americans--Civil
            rights--Louisiana--Baton Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Farm life--Texas--Palestine.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Civil rights
            movements--Louisiana--Baton Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">College students--Political
            activity--Louisiana--Baton Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest
            movements--Louisiana--Baton Rouge.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Palestine (Tex.)--Social life and customs--20th
            century.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Baton Rouge (La.)--Social life and customs--20th century.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Cali
            (Colombia)--Description and travel.</topic>
   </subject>
   <identifier>Mss. 4700.1503</identifier>
   <note type="ownership">Louisiana State University Libraries Special Collections
            (http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special)</note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained by
            Louisiana State University in accordance with U.S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See
            instructions for ordering reprints of this audio here:
            http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special/services/duplication.html Mention the ""Item number"" or
            ""Item URL"" in your request. "</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Hill Memorial Library, Special
                        Collections</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>L:
                        4700.1503</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <abstract xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu/services/oralhistory/abstracts/university/distinguished_faculty/Richardson_Miles_alltapes.abs.pdf">"Session I, which is transcribed, describes Richardson's early life in Palestine,
            Tex., between the 1930s and 1950s, including his father's work for the railroad, his
            mother's domestic duties, life on their farm, animals they kept, their garden, the use
            of well water and pumps, planting by the moon, folk remedies, the local lumber industry
            and ""sawmill kids,"" local pageants and events, his mother's death, his crisis of
            faith, and his first thoughts of becoming an anthropologist. He also discusses his
            service in the U.S. Air Force during the Korean War (1950-1954) and his ideas on
            evolution and anthropology.; Session II, which is indexed, describes his completing a
            bachelor's degree at Stephen F. Austin State College and starting the master's program
            at LSU (1957), including duties he had as part of his assistantship, classes and
            professors, his love of cultural geography, and anthropological theory of cultural
            evolution. He gives his recollections of LSU circa 1957-58, especially segregation and
            mandatory ROTC and civil rights activities. Richardson describes the doctoral program at
            Tulane (1958-1965), including work with Dr. Forrest La Violette on political activism of
            African-American ministers, fellow grad students including his wife Valerie, the
            popularity of folk music, and the difficulty in finding funding for research. He also
            discusses medical and dissertation research in Cali and San Pedro, Colombia in the early
            1960s with accounts of life in the local communities and the difficulty of fieldwork.;
            Session III, which is indexed, gives Richardson's recollections of Cali, Colombia (1962
            or 1963), his experiences while teaching at Indiana State College in Pennsylvania, his
            acknowledgment of the profound influence of Dr. La Violette, prominent theories in
            anthropology from the 1960s thru 1980s, the role of the Vietnam War and Civil Rights
            Movement on theories, and a discussion of his anthropological writing, fiction and
            poetry.; Session IV, which is indexed, discusses Richardson's first years teaching at
            LSU in the late 1960s, including reactions to the first African-American football
            players at LSU, campus protests on civil rights, the Vietnam War, the involvement of
            English Department faculty in the protests, the creation of Free Speech Alley, the
            reaction to the death of Martin Luther King Jr., Student Government President Ted
            Schirmer, and the cancellation of the homecoming queen crowning. He also discusses
            different reactions to New Archeology by Richardson and William Haag."</abstract>
</mods>
