<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Bayou Lafourche Oral History Project</title>
      <subTitle>Richard Thomas Gibbens Robichaux oral history interview, 2010</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="">
      <namePart>Foltz, Kristin,</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewer</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ivr</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description/>
   </name>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary">
      <namePart xmlns:lsu="http://lsu.edu">Robichaux, Richard Thomas Gibbens</namePart>
      <namePart xmlns:lsu="http://lsu.edu" type="date">1930-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewee</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ive</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description>R. Gibbens Robichaux was born in 1930 in Thibodaux, Louisiana, son of
            Alfred G. Robichaux, Sr. and Sara Day Gibbens Robichaux. He had one brother, Alfred G.
            Robichaux, Jr. (ca. 1928-2012) and was raised in Thibodaux, growing up in a house across
            the street from his grandparents (Eugene Godfrey Robichaux and Brigeitte Emma Thibodaux
            Robichaux) and a few blocks from Bayou Lafourche. He attended parochial school; first
            Mt. Carmel Convent Academy (now the Carmel Inn), and then Brothers of the Sacred Heart
            School, from which he graduated at sixteen. He met his future wife, Joann, as a
            teenager. He attended Spring Hill College in Mobile, Alabama (his father is also an
            alumnus); both he and his dad played piano and had bands in college. Robichaux enlisted
            in the US Air Force and was stationed for twenty-five months in Okinawa, Japan, where he
            was a chaplain's assistant and learned to play the organ. He returned to the States,
            married his wife, and was stationed in Marietta, Georgia. After he returned to Thibodaux
            he taught briefly (seventh grade), then worked for the welfare office, before becoming
            the organist of St. Joseph Co-Cathedral in Thibodaux, where he worked for twenty years.
            He is still involved in the church and music communities in his retirement. He has
            written a number of children's books, wrote a regular column for the Thibodaux Chamber
            of Commerce newsletter, and has released three CDs of music.</description>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>2010</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">1 digital audio file</note>
      <extent>1 hour, 3 minutes</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Abstract</note>
      <extent>5 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Index
           </note>
      <extent>7 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>sound recording</typeOfResource>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Robichaux, Richard Thomas Gibbens, 1930---Interviews.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Catholic
            Church--Louisiana--Thibodaux.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">St. Joseph Co-Cathedral (Thibodaux, La.)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">United
            States.--Air Force--Chaplain's assistants.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Organists--Louisiana--Thibodaux.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Thibodaux
            (La.)--History.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Thibodaux (La.)--Social life and customs.</topic>
   </subject>
   <identifier>Mss. 4700.2094</identifier>
   <note type="ownership">Louisiana State University Libraries Special Collections
            (http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special)</note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained by
            interviewer and interviewee in accordance with U.S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See
            instructions for ordering reprints of this audio here:
            http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special/services/duplication.html Mention the ""Item number"" or
            ""Item URL"" in your request. "</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Hill Memorial Library, Special
                        Collections</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>L:
                        4700.2094</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <abstract xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu/services/oralhistory/abstracts/bayoulafourche/Robichaux_Gibbens_T3940.pdf">"Robichaux discusses his childhood in Thibodaux, including his semi-rural home life
            (animals in the backyard), places to eat in Thibodaux (including a discussion of home
            cooking), and the group of boys he termed the ""Hinkety-dinkety Club."" He discusses his
            musical and parochial education, and how it led to his career as a chaplain's assistant
            in the Air Force (stationed in Okinawa, Japan), and eventually to playing organ at St.
            Joseph Co-Cathedral in Thibodaux. Robichaux reflects on Thibodaux's early days (even
            before he was born, ca. 1900 through the 1940s), and how the damming of Bayou Lafourche
            at Donaldsonville (1904) has changed the culture of the bayou. Robichaux briefly
            discusses the sugarcane industry (the family was involved), and how World War II,
            technology, and television changed the culture of Thibodaux from ""the simple life."" He
            discusses the construction, growth, and restoration of St. Joseph Co-Cathedral, and also
            enumerates the events (Masses, weddings, funerals) at which he has played the
            organ."</abstract>
</mods>
