<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Louisiana Cooperative Extension Oral History Project</title>
      <subTitle>William Richardson oral history interview, 2014</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="">
      <namePart>Cramer, Jennifer A.,</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewer</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ivr</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description/>
   </name>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary">
      <namePart>Richardson, William B., 1944-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">Interviewee</roleTerm>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator">ive</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <description>William Richardson was born in southeast Missouri in 1944 to William
            Richardson, Sr. and Pauline Gunnin. He was raised on a soybean-cotton farm near Kennett,
            Missouri. He attended Dearing public schools until he graduated from high school. After
            high school, he attended Arkansas State University, where he earned a B.S. degree in
            1966, and a master's degree in 1968. He received his doctorate degree in agricultural
            education from the University of Missouri in 1972. From 1972 until 1984, he taught at
            Purdue University, where he was recognized twice as an Outstanding Teacher, and once as
            an Outstanding Academic Advisor by the University's Department of Education. He joined
            the faculty of Louisiana State University as a professor in 1984. He has served in
            various national and international leadership capacities as well as in numerous
            administrative capacities and on many boards and committees. He's published numerous
            articles and textbooks, and has served as the chairperson for various master's theses
            and doctoral dissertations. He currently serves as Director of Louisiana Cooperative
            Extension Service and LSU Vice-President for Agriculture and Dean for the College of
            Agriculture.</description>
   </name>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>2014</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">1 digital audio file</note>
      <extent>47 minutes</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Index</note>
      <extent>9 leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <physicalDescription>
      <note type="content">Abstract</note>
      <extent>3
            leaves</extent>
      <form>Oral History</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>sound recording</typeOfResource>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Richardson, William B., 1944---Interviews.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Arkansas State University--Students.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Arkansas State University--Sports.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Farm life--Missouri.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Agricultural extension
            work--United States.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">County agricultural agents--United States.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">College
            students--Political activity--United States.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">College athletes--United States.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Discrimination in sports--Arkansas--Jonesboro.</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic authority="LoC">Kennett (Mo.)--Social life and
            customs--20th century.</topic>
   </subject>
   <identifier>Mss. 4700.2387</identifier>
   <note type="ownership">Louisiana State University Libraries Special Collections
            (http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special)</note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">Physical rights are retained by the LSU Libraries. Copyright is retained by
            Louisiana State University in accordance with U.S. copyright laws.</accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">"E-mail lsudiglib@lsu.edu with questions or comments. See
            instructions for ordering reprints of this audio here:
            http://www.lib.lsu.edu/special/services/duplication.html Mention the ""Item number"" or
            ""Item URL"" in your request. "</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Hill Memorial Library, Special
                        Collections</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>L:
                        4700.2387</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <abstract xlink:href="http://lib.lsu.edu/services/oralhistory/abstracts/historycoopexten/Richardson_William_T4316.abs.pdf">Richardson begins the interview by speaking about his grandparents. He also
            discusses life in rural Missouri and what it was like to live on a farm in the Kennett
            area. This includes social outlets such as cruising, going to the movies, basic farm
            chores, crops, and a typical workday on the farm. He also details his time at Arkansas
            State University. He discusses mandatory ROTC service, the basketball team, and what
            college campuses were like during the sixties and the Vietnam War era. Richardson notes
            the differences between college athletes today and when he was in school, the political
            awareness of students today versus his time in school, and what it was like to play with
            the first black basketball player at Arkansas State University. He notes how those
            experiences helped him to be more diverse as an administrator later in his career.
            Richardson also discusses how people depended on extension agents for information.
            County agents helped deliver information to the people in a much different manner than
            today. Today's agents have more technology and other avenues to disseminate information,
            though their motivations remain the same.</abstract>
</mods>
