<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cues>

    <!-- At least one 'transcript' or 'annotation' emlement must present in a 'cue' element. -->
    <cue>
        <speaker>Alexander P. Tureaud, Jr.</speaker>
        <!-- 'start' and 'end' elements are start time and end time in seconds for the cue. -->
        <start>0.000</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>I am A. P. Tureaud. South Salem, New York, and it's a beautiful sunny
            day.</transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
       <speaker> Rachel Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>Interview with A. P. Tureaud, Jr., April 25, 1993.
            You were the first [African American] student to be enrolled in the undergraduate
            program at LSU [Louisiana State University] in Baton Rouge in 1953. How . . . Describe
            the steps before you entered the campus.</transcript>
        <annotation/>
        </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>In terms of selection or in terms of
            the legal procedures?</transcript>
        </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>Legal procedures.</transcript>
        <annotation/>
        </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>[0:54]</start>
        <end>[2:50]</end>
        <transcript>Well, as I recall . . . because that's been a long time ago. When I was a junior
            . . . I'll make this sort of brief, but when I was a junior in high school, I had
            dreamed of college from the time I was very little because my mom and dad talked about
            the fun they had and their wonderful experiences at Howard [University]. And there was a
            natural expectation that all of us would go to college. My oldest sister was in college
            at Xavier [University]. I was the second child, so my turn was coming up. I was always
            very sensitive to the fact that . . . I knew that although my father was a busy man and
            had a . . . was known for his legal work, I always felt that there wasn't a lot of money
            to spend, and he had to make do. So, I kept thinking about, well, what would be the
            appropriate thing to do because I had another sister coming behind me in two years and
            then there were three more behind her. So, I was always thinking what would be the best
            college at the best price and so forth and so on. My dream, and I didn't say this to
            anyone, may have been to go to Howard because they were both Howard graduates. But, I
            had also always been involved with him. With all of the other cases that he petitioned
            LSU for, he would always take us with him. You know, with the other law suits and we
            were always around Southern's campus [Southern University] and always around LSU. He
            used to say, "Boy, LSU is a wonderful school. Look at these buildings. Look at the
            faculty. Look at . . . We should have some of this. We should be here!” You know, “Why
            should this not be ours just as well? Why couldn't we benefit from these
            things?"</transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>[2:51]</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript> So, I thought, well heck, the best school closest home to me is LSU, at a
            terrific price. I could have gone to Xavier. I could have gone to Dillard [University].
            I could have gone . . . I guess I could have even gone to Howard, but I didn't want to,
            I guess, make it difficult for them financially. We never discussed it a lot. I just
            said, "I’d like to apply to LSU." He never asked me. He never recruited me, and I don't
            think he was displeased when I said it. When I said it, I didn't think it was going to
            be an issue. My father always gave you the feeling that you could do what you wanted to
            do and it was going to be okay. When I said, "Is this possible?" He said, "Oh yeah,
            we'll work it out." And that was it. Being the person he was, we always worked it out,
            or he always helped you work it out or made things possible. So I thought, well it'll be
            a little problem for a few days and then it'll go away and I'll be able to go to LSU. We
            were in New York. He filed the petition . . . I applied, he filed the petition, and we
            were in New York at a Knights of Peter Claver, or some kind of business I know we were
            on. Then the stuff hit the newspaper and we had to go back and start the trial. When I
            was in high school, my guidance counselor heard that. He called me to the side one day.
            He was a very nice man, Mr. Blakeley[?]. He said, "What is this a joke? [laughs] You're
            applying to LSU?" I said, "No, it's not a joke."</transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>What high school was that?</transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>[5:00}</end>
        <transcript>This was Clark. Joyce and Joseph Clark High School [Joseph S. Clark High School]
            in New Orleans [Louisiana]. He had to work with all of the kids in their junior year to
            get them ready for the senior year for applications. I told him, I said, "No it's not a
            joke. I'm going to LSU." He said, "Well, you know the problems there?" I said, "Yeah,” I
            said, “but things are changing,” and so forth. He knew my dad and so forth, so he
            supported that. But, it wasn't a big deal. </transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker> Tureaud </speaker>
        <start>[5:01]</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>I sent the papers in. Then, of course, I got the letter back that said they
            wouldn't take me because I was a Negro or colored, and I should go to one of the black
            state schools at the state . . . the excellent state schools for black kids and so
            forth. That's how it got started. I really never felt it was a big deal. But, my father
            never said, "Gee, we're proud . . . This is a big deal, we want you . . ." No, it was
            just like, “Okay that's great." He never . . . He never made a big deal out of these
            things. He felt that this is the course things should take. This is the way it should
            happen. There wasn't a whole lot of discussion about it. We never discussed it a lot.
            Even my mom never discussed it a whole lot. </transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>Saying that you knew of his previous lawsuits against LSU, or Roy Wilson and
            Daryle Foister and Lutrill Payne. Something . . . I mean, you knew that the
            undergraduate programs had not been integrated. Because of your . . . seeing your dad
            work, you don't think that had an influence on it? </transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>Oh sure, yeah. I think by seeing it work . . . Also, I think [Ernest N. "Dutch"]
            Morial and [Robert] Collins had also been admitted to law school, and some of the other
            graduate programs people had . . . He had helped them get into graduate
            school.</transcript>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>Were you aware of, once these students were enrolled, of their contact with your
            father on what . . . how things were going for them?</transcript>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>[6:42]</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>Oh yes, he constantly maintained contact with them. He would also drive up to
            the campus if they were having problems of one kind or another and needed support. He
            was more than . . . more than just their lawyer. He was like a support system. In some
            ways, without sounding mushy, he was really like a parent supporting their kid in an
            environment or young person in an environment. Because a lot of those graduate students
            were well into their adulthood, they weren't right out of high school. He was very
            supportive.</transcript>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>In other words, you had seen the campus. Now a student coming onto a college
            campus, they do a visit. They go look at the dorms. They usually have tours, campus
            tours. Of course, this is out now and even then for white students there was a staff
            person or students on the campus that introduced you. When you were making your
            selection, you had been on the campus before with your father, but, of course, these
            courtesies weren't afforded to black students that may be thinking about coming to LSU.
            What was your feeling when you arrived on the campus knowing that you were getting ready
            to enroll in a program?</transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>You mean prior to the legal . . . to the suit?</transcript>
        <annotation/>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript> No after you were admitted.</transcript>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>?</end>
        <transcript>Oh, after I was admitted, oh well . . . </transcript>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <transcript>The first day.</transcript>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>[8:26]</start>
        <transcript>Well that was a . . . That was horror story because what happened was, we packed
            the car from New Orleans and you know the typical excitement. The other thing, too, is
            that I didn't have the opportunity, as you said, to go . . . to be oriented, to be
            recruited, and to be courted by the university or encouraged to come. It was, "No, don't
            come. You're not welcome, go somewhere else," so that all of the other social amenities
            and support systems that other students had, I didn't have. The only support system I
            had were my parents, and they were right there. We loaded up the car with all the
            typical things including a typewriter and a pillow and all that stuff, got to LSU, and
            then were refused . . . I was refused admittance. They told me to come back the
            following day, so I had to go all the way back. I don't remember now exactly why. There
            was some legal glitch, or whatever. Also, I was met by the president of the university
            or the chancellor, whatever he was called, and then the vice-president or the
            vice-chancellor. You knew that you weren't going to be having a typical orientation. The
            press was there to get the maximum amount of publicity out of it. It was . . . that was
            the most difficult part was the beginning. We went back the next day and I was admitted.
            I did live in the dormitory. The students did . . . had queued up outside of my room. I
            had been escorted from the president's office to the stadium where I lived and . . .
        </transcript>
    </cue>
    <cue>
        <speaker> Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
        <start>?</start>
        <end>10:27</end>
        <transcript>By . . .</transcript>
    </cue>
    
        <cue><speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
        <start>[10:28]</start>
        <transcript>By the president or the vice-president I
            think it was . . . whatever. No policemen involved. When I got to the room they had
            assigned me to, which was the top floor of the stadium, which was the third or fourth
            floor up, there must have been fifty students standing, waiting outside of my door with
            scissors to clip your hair. Because it . . . the freshmen thing is they cut all your
            hair off. They were joking and laughing and carrying . . . having a good time. I
            thought, oh, this is great. This is just what I wanted. I thought, they're going to be
            my friends. They came in. My father was very excited. He thought this . . . We all
            thought this was a welcome party. They came in a talked and cut my hair and talked,
            joked to each other and so forth. After I thought about it, I realized they were not
            talking to me, they were talking about me. It was like I was an inanimate object
            [laughs] that they were performing this ritual on. I was trying to say, "Well, what's
            your name?” and “Where do you eat?" And I . . . Well, they just ignored that. They were
            just engaging with each other. I didn't realize it until after. Of course, I looked like
            Ichabod Crane or some waif by the time they finished chopping all my hair off. I had to
            go to a barber shop to have it evened out, and my parents took me. We found a barber
            shop nearby. Of course, we realized there were white barber shops, so we had to find a
            black barber shop in town. We went to a black barber shop, the guy buzzed my head
            through. Then I went back. I was anxious to get back to the campus and find all of these
            guys who had been cutting my hair and start making some friends. They were gone. They
            were gone. The idea was, we did what we had to do and we're out of here. None of them
            spoke to me and none of them acknowledged that they were there. I shooed my parents
            away. "Oh go! Go home quick! I got to get back!” And, “All those guys are there, and I'm
            going to start making friends." </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Turead</speaker>
            <start>[12:36]</start>
            <transcript>When I got back to the room and when my parents dropped me off, I was
                absolutely alone. That dormitory . . . the section I was in was totally deserted,
                and I sat there like in a funk about, well, where did everybody go? I thought, well,
                they probably had something to do, I must have missed some event or something and
                maybe . . . Well no, I . . . that was a . . . That was a severe blow. Then as I
                thought about it, they really didn't engage in any activity with me. That was . . .
                That was hard. Then the next . . . I think it was the next day the vice-president
                came around and said he was taking me to my classes to make sure that everything
                would be okay. I said, "You don't have to do that." He said, "No it's . . . I'm
                going to do this," and so forth and so on. "If you have any problems, come directly
                to me." I kept saying to him, "Don't treat me this way. Just let me blend in and be
                like everybody else." He did take me around, and I'm sure the professors didn't want
                me in the class because I'm sure it was going to be disruptive. From that moment on,
                the nightmare began. I was there, like, six weeks.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>Did you know about the tradition of shaving . . . </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript>Yes. I knew about the head business. I had read all I could and I mean I had
                . . . You know, LSU was always in the news. You always saw pictures of the pajama
                parties for the freshmen at football games and all these traditions that they had
                then and the little purple and gold beanies that they wore. I wanted to have mine. I
                was very much into getting into the social activities of college life which I had
                heard was so much fun because my parents were both in sororities and fraternities
                and all the social . . . Everybody had always told you, "College is the best time of
                your life. You grow so much. You learn so much." I was anticipating that in addition
                to the academic stuff. But it just didn't happen. From that moment on, I realized
                that I was in for a very unusual experience.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>Describe your teachers, the professors.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[14:49]</start>
            <transcript>Well, I remember I was taking liberal arts law, and I remember I was taking
                Spanish, and I had math, and writing, and I was in the Air Force ROTC, which I chose
                because I had to. I didn't have any interest in it. I remember I also was taking . .
                . I had a physical education course. And, ugh, I had to pass . . . everybody had to
                pass a swimming test. This was the old student union, I don't remember the name of
                it, but it was an outdoor pool. You got directions on paper about doing everything.
                You had to report . . . when you had your P.E. class, you had to report to the
                swimming pool, and you had to either swim the pool successfully or you had to take
                swimming. It was like a big deal, "First Black to Swim in Pool," [ laughs] splashed
                all over the front pages of the . . . What's the school newspaper?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>The Reveille.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> The Reveille, yeah. So every day . . . It must have been boring for some of
                those students, there was something about this black undergraduate who was the first
                to swim in the pool. Then there were things like people writing letters to the
                editor because my dorm room was right across from where Mike the Tiger, the school
                mascot's cage was because it was near the stadium, and somebody wrote an article,
                "Let's have a Roman Holiday. We'll put Tureaud in the stadium and bring Mike in and
                feed him to the lions.” That kind of thing, and a great deal of
                isolation.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[16:25]</start>
            <transcript>The professors were . . . It was like I didn't exist. One woman was
                particularly awful. She was an older woman. She announced my first day that . . .
                Not to me, she never . . . People talked about me as though, as I said, I was an
                inanimate object. She said to her class this was the first time she had ever taught
                a nigra. I was shocked. And she just didn't know how she was going to get through
                this experience. She taught me math. Nobody sat near me. The kids sat all around me.
                If I sat in the corner, they would move to the opposite side of the room. If I sat
                in the middle, they would move to the sides. I never sat in the same place or
                whatever. But it . . . You were just playing head trips all the time. You were
                trying to figure out how you were going to make today work. It got to be very, very
                lonely and depressing. Most of the professors just ignored me. One or two of them .
                . . then this particular woman, she didn't even want to correct my papers. She
                didn't want to touch the papers. I noticed that she would . . . It seemed that she
                was being more critical. I guess in math you're either right or wrong, but she
                seemed to be more critical of my work. I got some help with my math and before the
                six weeks was over, did very well. I was doing very poorly in the beginning in the
                math. I also had to partner up with somebody in gym because the first part of the
                semester . . . I had passed the swimming test. We were playing racquet ball, and you
                had to have a partner. I remember this guy . . . If they didn't . . . If the
                professor or the teacher didn't mention my name, many of them didn't know who I was
                because there were a lot of international students at LSU, and many of them looked
                more swarthy than I did. Of course with your hair all shaved off you couldn't tell
                too much anyway. I remember this guy standing next to me saying, "I've been looking
                around here waiting for that nigger to come in, and I don't see him. I hope I don't
                get him as my partner. My friends will give me a hard time." I said, "Well, there
                are a few niggers here, but they're not black." He didn't know what I was talking
                about. [Tureaud and Wallace laugh] He ended up getting me, and I don't know if he
                ever heard the name. I wasn't going to say, "Well, I'm the black person here." I
                just thought, "Goodness gracious, how long is it going to take for this to, for them
                to get over this thing?"</transcript>
        </cue> 
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[19:04]</start>
            <transcript> But the professors were very disinterested, and nobody was supportive. The
                only people that were supportive was the Newman Club, the Catholic Center. They made
                contact with me and asked me to come over, and I'd go over once or twice a week, but
                nobody in the dorm was. There was Dutch Morial and Robert Collins there. There was
                also a few graduate students. There was a couple, a very wonderful couple, husband
                and wife, that lived on campus, and they knew who I was and we made contact. She was
                pregnant at the time, very pregnant. They were getting a master's. I used to pal
                around with them. They lived in the Quonset huts they had on the back side of the
                campus by the back . . . by the stadium. There were two apartments in a Quonset hut,
                back-to-back apartments. She said that people used to bang on the walls for them,
                and they were both getting master's degrees in music. I know she was. Maybe he was
                getting something in business. They were lovely. I used to go over to their
                apartment, and we would have dinner sometimes. She was really abused. They called
                her black cow, and, "What are you having a baby mule or a gorilla?" She was afraid
                that she wasn't going to get to go the hospital soon enough. She used to joke and
                say, "There is a pair of scissors on the table. If I'm delivering my baby tie a knot
                around the umbilical cord." I used to say, "I don't know nothing about birthing
                babies." [laughs] But I lost track of them. But it was . . . It was a terrible . . .
                It was probably the hardest thing I've ever done. </transcript>

        </cue> 
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <start> ? </start>
            <end>[20:50]</end>
            <transcript> Now, you talk about her being afraid, and you mention the loneliness and
                isolation, were you afraid?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[20:51]</start>
            <transcript>No, I wasn't afraid. Somehow or another, I never felt physical harm.
                Although the students were vocal in the dorm and did things in the dorm like banging
                on the walls and playing radios. Somebody tied a part of a dead cat's body to my
                door knob on Halloween. But I was . . . I never felt afraid for my life or that
                somebody would try to hurt me. She, as a woman, did. I didn't get the same sense of
                fear from her husband. Guys would particularly follow her and say all kinds of nasty
                things to her. She said sometimes she was so upset she couldn't go to class. She was
                a beautiful woman but . . . . No, I was never afraid, I was just so lonely all the
                time. I was accustomed to being around people. I came from a big family and I liked
                interacting with people. I always liked talking to the professors and having an
                experience, and I never had that. I didn't know how long I could . . . I just didn't
                know how long I could take it. Yet, I felt the pressure to stay and see the thing
                through. I just kept thinking I can't go through . . . I was in a five year liberal
                arts law program. I couldn't take five . . . I just kept saying, "I'm not going to
                be able to make this for five years, but it'll get better." It didn't get much
                better. I required a lot of support from my family, and they were there for me. They
                also . . . My mother and father came up. We had friends in Baton Rouge, friends who
                had friends in Baton Rouge. I could go visit with them, and through Kara Russo[?]
                who was in . . . She's got a master's in social work. She had some cousins or
                whatever, and I met a young man my age who is now a dentist in Chicago, Mark Smith.
                I used to go over to his house. It wasn't far from campus, and have dinner with
                them. Sometimes he'd come stay on campus. But it wasn't . . . I was never
                comfortable . . . I was never . . . I never made any friends at LSU. The professors
                . . . I wasn't . . . I couldn't concentrate on the academic parts the way I should
                have. I was just distracted all the time, and then the noise in the dorm.
            </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <start>[23:15]</start>
            <transcript> And you say you made no friends at all, no professor. You said just the
                Newman Center.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <annotation>[Agrees]</annotation>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>As a . . . something white . . . </transcript>
        </cue> 
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> Yeah, right, right.</transcript>
        </cue> 
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> . . . on the campus. Contact with white people, that was . . .
            </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> The only place that . . .</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>[?]</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[23:31]</start>
            <transcript> Yeah. No, I made no . . . I made no friends. I mean people . . . Even the
                professors . . . I would go . . . I remember, I was having some trouble in Spanish.
                They were going too fast for me. I used to have to go listen to the tapes and all of
                that. I know a lot of it was I couldn't concentrate. I was trying to . . . I like
                getting to know people . . . I feel much more comfortable. I can do better in a
                course if I develop a relationship with the professor and try to understand what
                they want and what . . . to help me. It was like, “Well, go listen to the tapes,”
                or, “Find a study group.” How was I going to make a study group? Nobody wanted to be
                near me. Or, “do this,” or, “do that.” There wasn't the same kind of reaching out or
                whatever. Some of them were younger people who had come from other parts of the
                country. They weren't all just southerners. It was a very . . . It was a very lonely
                experience.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>Did you get called on in class to answer questions or . . . </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript>No, I wasn't badgered or I wasn't . . . I wasn't highlighted. If I
                volunteered . . . Sometimes, I know, I would raise my hand and depending upon the
                professor, they would ignore me or call on me. I was trying to think of one . . . if
                there was any one experience, one course that I liked. I think . . . Oh, I had this
                terrible course in world history or civilizations of the world or something, one of
                these big survey courses with . . . It goes all the way back to Egyptians and all of
                that. All those names, Amenhotep[?] and all that stuff. It was a big lecture hall
                with about two or three hundred students in it, and you had the TAs [teaching
                assistants] there and everything. A lot of it was just unconnected. I mean, I
                expected an enriching, warm experience. Maybe it got to be that later on, but the
                whole thing was not what I expected it to be. Now, maybe it was just too large. Of
                course, I wasn't connected to anything, so I felt even more isolated. It wasn't my
                greatest academic moment.</transcript>
            <annotation> [break in tape]</annotation>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <start>[25:47]</start>
            <transcript>Later black students in the whole process of desegregation that I've talked
                to mentioned that their parents told them when they talked about social problems or
                the fact that they had no interaction on the campus, they would mention, "Well,
                you're going there to get an education." Was that . . . How did your parents talk
                about . . . talk to you if . . . when you told them about the social problems you
                were having?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript>[Agrees] They were . . . They were first very supportive. I knew that I
                could call upon them anytime of the day. We didn't talk a lot about it. You were
                just expected to do what you had to do. I can remember one . . . several things. One
                was that . . . I remember one time I must have been there several weeks or two or
                three weeks, I hadn't spoke, nobody had spoken to me for days. I was just very
                lonely and I called my mom. She actually got on the bus and came to Baton Rouge and
                spent the day with me. She left five kids at home. [pause] That meant a lot to me
                because I knew they were there. I knew that I couldn't keep demanding that kind of
                support from them. But they also . . . For example, my dad. I had bought a little
                jalopy, in my . . . the summer before I went to LSU. The car was really just . . .
                wasn't adequate. He felt that it was important for me then to have the ability to
                leave when I wanted to. We only had one car, so he switched cars. [laughs] I got his
                little car, and he got my little jalopy. Now, can you imagine my family of . . . all
                those kids, five more kids, my mom and dad, trying to use the little jalopy that I
                had bought? My father had to go to court. He had to go to work. They had to do
                shopping. For like two or three weeks, I had their car and they had my car. [laughs]
                But that's what . . . And everybody . . . It was okay because they knew I had to get
                out of there when I needed to. I could come home to Baton Rouge . . . from Baton
                Rouge whenever I wanted to. It wasn't discussed, or it wasn't said, "Oh, grow up and
                accept your responsibility." It was, "No, you need the best car you can have right
                now." I felt like, wait a minute I can't take the family car and leave this little
                car. But that's what they did. They just did what had to be done, and it was
                important. It got me through.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[29:06]</start>
            <transcript>I'd come home on Fridays. I remember one time I even cut a few Saturday
                classes because I just couldn't stay any longer. There was just no way . . . Then, I
                dreaded going back. I mean, going back was like going back into a firing squad. But
                I met Kara Russo, and we'd go back together. She lived off campus with friends and
                with some relatives or cousins or whatever. I thought, well maybe that's . . . that
                would be helpful for me. That's when I got to meet Mark Smith, and I'd go over to
                his house. So . . . Maybe if I had had to stay there longer, I could have worked
                some of these things out, but the first six weeks were . . . Then I was asked to
                leave but . . . That was the roughest time of my life and it was the social pieces.
                They . . . My parents never separated the social development from the academic
                development. You're a whole person and you grow. College is a time where . . . All
                of life is growth, but college was a time to grow and to be interested in lots of
                things and to meet lots of people. That was the richness of LSU that I went there
                for. And I was not, at that point, able to participate in it. My parents had a very
                interesting approach to things. They didn't . . . There wasn't a whole lot of
                sitting down analyzing the situation. They just . . . They were very simple people
                with simple taste, very direct. They were people who just did it. They just . . .
                And we grew up . . . I grew up in that expectation. Just go ahead and do what you
                have to do. </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>Had you had white friends before that in New Orleans?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[30:54]</start>
            <transcript> Well, not . . . I never had any really . . . any really close white friends
                because first of all, I didn't go to school with white children. The few white
                children that lived in the neighborhood . . . There was one white family that lived
                where our properties backed up to one another. Either the fence had blown down or
                there was no fence. I remember, at one point, the fence had blown down from a
                hurricane or something. We were then ten, eleven, and twelve, we played together,
                but that family moved out. The other thing was the neighborhood I lived in, and the
                community in which I grew up, there were so many children. There were so many social
                experiences. Our house was the neighborhood youth center. Everybody came to play
                there. We had pool table, ping pong table, a paved back yard. There was basketball,
                there was skating, there were just . . . There must have been thirty kids on my
                block. Then plus my own friends in the neighborhood and my sister's friends and all
                of that stuff. So, no, I didn't have close white friends. We had also travelled all
                of our lives. We had been east, we had been to the West Coast, we had been all
                around. My father was very involved, so was my mother, with other people. They
                weren't all black people. So, I was accustomed to being in a mixed environment, not
                as a steady social experience, but I wasn't intimidated or uncomfortable around
                people of diverse backgrounds or even people from other countries. I think I had a
                good preparation for that.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[32:41]</start>
            <transcript> Also, from the time I was very little, my father became more active
                politically in the community and in town. I was taken to all of these events with
                him where there would be the mayor and there would be politicians who were white or
                black ministers. I was always . . . I was like the son who was always being groomed
                to be sort of a social person. You were expected to be able to say hello to people
                and be polite and be gracious from the time I was little. Then, I travelled out of
                the area to Philadelphia, New York, sometimes by myself from the time I was eight or
                nine years old. So, that was not an issue and I . . . We were all experienced in a
                broader social circle and that was the fun of it. My parents loved meeting people
                from different places, and they had also been people who had travelled themselves
                when they were young and had gone away to school. So, that was never an issue. New
                Orleans is a very international community, so the meeting of people at LSU and all
                that was not an issue. </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>Were there . . . Did you come across any black employees on the
                campus?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start> [34:15]</start>
            <transcript> Yeah. That was a very interesting experience and in many ways touching. I
                particularly remember the women who worked in the cafeteria where I ate. They were
                very quiet, but they were very supportive. They would smile or wink at you. Some of
                them would actually come up and say, "We're very happy you're here." But quietly,
                they didn't want any of the white staff to hear it or the white kids to hear it, I
                guess. But they were proud and very supportive. My most touching moment - I don't
                know if I can say this because it chokes me up - but my most touching moment at LSU,
                and I'll never forget it was . . . this . . . I told you . . . I mentioned this to
                you once before. One morning, I came out . . . I couldn't sleep, and I came out just
                to be outside and to get away from that crazy dormitory with all the noise and
                stuff. It was like six o'clock in the morning, and I was coming out of the dorm. I
                don't know where I was going, but there was this black man out there sitting in a
                truck. He had on bib overalls and he had a little boy with him. As I came out the
                entrance, he walked over to me and . . . big smile on his face and he said . . . He
                asked me if I was A. P. Tureaud. I said, "Yes." He said, "I thought you were." He
                said that he had been to the campus a few times, but he hadn't seen me. He lived
                somewhere in the Baton Rouge area, and he had brought his son who was six or seven
                years old to meet me because he wanted his kid to remember that this was
                possible.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[36:09]</start>
            <transcript> That also made me realize that I had a responsibility to help other people
                realize that what I was doing was possible for everyone. Because I didn't go into
                this thing with a mission, and I wasn't there to be a pioneer. I just wanted to go
                to school. But I realized . . . And I knew that would happen, that it would take on
                a different meaning for black people because people had come up to me . . . At home,
                people would say, "We're very proud of you," and things like that, but this was a .
                . . This man and this little boy, that just meant so much to me. It put more
                responsibility on me because I was trying to figure out how to get out of there. I
                mean, the experience was so bad. But then, I thought, "Well, I can't leave because
                I'll be disappointing everyone." It put me in a more . . . It created conflict for
                me. I then said to myself, "Well I just can't leave." My folks had told me I could
                leave any time I wanted to. My father said, "You are a person. You’re an individual.
                Yes, the case is important, but you're not a case; you're a person. We love you, and
                if it gets too rough, you just say you want out, and we'll get you out." I just
                couldn't figure that . . . I couldn't do that. I figured I don't know how I'm going
                to be able to take it. I then started to feel that I was in a conflictual situation
                that I couldn't resolve. I just said, "Time will tell. Something's got to get
                better. Something's got to change, but I shouldn't go. It sure would be nice to be
                at Xavier University in New Orleans with all my friends, enjoying themselves,
                working hard but having a good time, and not be under all this
                pressure."</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> Do you recall going to pay your fees?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[38:10]</start>
            <transcript> I think that was all taken care of through the admission with the vice-
                president. [laughs] My father signed a check. I filled out the . . . I mean all of
                that admission stuff was done as an exception to the rule. I didn't have a whole lot
                of that to do.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>You talked about the Reveille, the university press. During your six weeks
                there, were there other media persons that came? </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript>Yeah. I had a lot of contact with the black press. I used to get calls from
                Ebony. I remember . . . I had made up my mind that I was not going to be a media
                person. I didn't want media attention because I really felt that if I could let this
                thing settle in in a typical way, I would be accepted as a student more quickly than
                all of the publicity surrounding being the first black undergraduate. So, I avoided
                the white press. I avoided the black press. The Reveille did whatever they wanted to
                do because I didn't even know who they were half of them. I didn't know whether they
                were reporters or just students, and so they kind of made up their own things as
                they went along. Because nobody sat around and interviewed me, because I was not
                interested in that. I wasn't available to them.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[39:45]</start>
            <transcript> The same thing happened. I wasn't hounded or followed around. The first few
                days there were people I knew were from the media. I could see them taking pictures,
                and sometimes they'd ask me questions. I said to a few of them, "Look, I would
                really like to make this work. Why don't you kindly just leave me alone? I don't
                want to be impolite, but just kindly leave me alone because as long as you follow me
                around, people aren't going to want to be a part of that." Even some white kids
                might want to be friendly but they couldn't have their friends . . . They would be
                ostracized if they got too close to me too quickly. Until people got to know me and
                so forth, many people were just standing back waiting. But I . . . that was
                something I decided to do. My parents supported me on that. I remember talking to
                some . . . a reporter kept calling me from Johnson Publications who wanted to do a
                spread in Ebony, or whatever, about my sitting in class and walking through the
                campus, you know how they do those feature stories. I told him I just didn't want to
                do that because that would just keep the thing going and keep me in an unnatural
                situation.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[41:00]</start>
            <transcript> Being the focus of that kind of attention is not what students do. Students
                go to school and students get into the campus life. And I . . . I was foolish enough
                to think I would be invited to join a fraternity. I mean, I wanted all of that. I
                wanted everything that everybody else had. I was so intimidated by the whole process
                because they started talking about . . . There was a game, it was homecoming or
                whatever and all the freshmen go there in pajamas. They still do that? Well, they
                did when I was there, and this got to be a big thing in the press. First time this
                would happen and, “Will he go? Won't he go?” I thought, I'm not going to put myself
                through that. I mean, if this was such a big deal to them, I just won't be there. I
                left the day of that event, and I went home because I just didn't want to have to do
                that . . . that was not . . . It wouldn't be pleasant for me, so I
                left.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> Do you remember talking to . . . trying to talk to any of the students
                yourself?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[42:08]</start>
            <transcript> Nobody even wanted to talk to me. Someone told me at the Newman Center . .
                . Oh, I know what it was. It was a priest at the Newman Center once gave . . . said
                mass after I had been there a few weeks. I did go to mass. He said that he . . . He
                did a sermon, and the idea was that I was getting the silent treatment. The word was
                out that the way you break it . . . or break his spirit is not talk to him. Just
                nobody engage in any conversation. It seemed like a reasonably well-organized
                conspiracy that nobody would talk to me. People just didn't talk. I'd go into the
                dining room, nobody would come over. I didn't force myself on people either. I
                didn't just go into a table where people were, whatever, and sit next to them. I'd
                kind of sit by myself. If people wanted to come over, they could come over. None of
                that ever happened. One or two of the . . . It was very nice. One or two of the
                black employees invited me to come spend the weekend with them. "If you're lonely
                come to our house, we'll take good care of you." I thanked them. Maybe I would have
                done that, but the idea was to make friends on campus where I was living, where I
                wanted to be a part of the school. And of course six weeks is not a long period of
                time, it seemed like an eternity to me. At seventeen, I thought this would never
                end. But I was very happy when that . . . there was a mistrial and I had to leave.
                My father came up and told me, "I've got some real good news for you." I said,
                "Hallelujah. Get me out of here." So, that was . . . </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>He just came to your dorm? There was no pre-announcement . . . </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> He called me.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> . . . that you knew about? Oh.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[43:54]</start>
            <end>[45:59}</end>
            <transcript> No, he called and he said, "I'm coming up to the university this evening
                after office hours, and I'll . . . if it's okay I'll spend the night." I said, "Oh,
                that'll be great." I said, "Why are you coming?" He said, "Well, I have some news
                for you." I thought, good news or bad news? He said, "Well, I think it's good news
                for you. I don't know about the case, but it's good news for you." I didn't ask him
                what it was. I was just happy he was coming, and he told me. We talked . . . We did
                talk about that, what it meant and if I left where was I going to go? I wanted to be
                in school. He said he had made arrangements for me to go to Xavier. This was like on
                a Friday or Thursday and that I could enter Xavier on a Monday. I thought, what are
                they going to think when I show up on Monday six weeks into the semester? I'm not
                going to be welcomed. I mean, I'll be welcomed there because I knew I would be
                welcome, but how am I going to catch up with all this work? What do the professors
                think? What kind of grades will I get trying to catch up after missing six weeks?"
                You're a freshman, school is all new and it's hard. It's not high school. That was a
                problem transferring into Xavier. Some of the professors, even though they were glad
                I was there or at least I'm sure were happy that I wasn't being so isolated and so
                forth, a few of them were like, "Who do you think you are?" I had to kind of . . . I
                really worked hard. That was the hardest time, to come . . . It was hard enough
                being at LSU. Then I was still . . . I was still really recovering from that
                emotional experience. It took me a whole year. I was afraid also, I had to go back.
                I mean, I kept saying, "What happens if I have to go back?" My father said, "Look .
                . ." My mother was the one who said . . . She used to always say this, "You cross
                that bridge when you get there. We're not there yet. Don't worry about it." I was so
                happy to be . . .</transcript>
            <annotation>[End Tape 375, Side A. Begin Tape 375, Side B.] </annotation>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <start> [46:00]</start>
            <transcript>You mentioned your fear about going . . . thinking that you might have to go
                back if the case was reversed or whatever. Obviously . . . and you said it took a
                year for you to get over that. You were emotionally scarred?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[46:29]</start>
            <transcript>Yeah, I was traumatized by the experience. It was just . . . It was just so
                hard to be in the middle of a college campus as lively, as enriched, as extensive as
                LSU is . . . or was and is, and to be almost treated like an alien. To see people
                rushing off to go some place together, just to go out to eat, a simple thing like
                that, or to be rushed by a fraternity, or to have a date, or to just sit around and
                talk and be silly. I had none of that.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>What about the international students?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript>Well . . .</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>Did you have any contact with them?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue><speaker>Tureaud</speaker><transcript> I had no contact with
            them. Now, they . . . First of all, the international students were not as . . . They
            weren't the same kind of international students they are there now. I'm sure there was
            some from certain countries. I don't know if there were Egyptians there and those kinds
            of people, but they were not basically black internationals. They were . . . I remember
            one thing, we had just come through the Korean [War] experience, and I was very angry
            that there were Koreans there who didn't have a problem. I was American citizen and a
            tax payer and here I am having the problem. I thought, gee, I didn't expect it to be . .
            . I mean, I don't think life is just fair because it's supposed to be fair, but it was
            just kind of a real injustice. That I was supporting . . . and my family was supporting
            foreign national kids by being there.</transcript></cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[48:34]</start>
            <transcript> No, they didn't become friendly, and yet I . . . they moved through the
                school with more ease than I did. I'm sure they had their rough moments too, people
                . . . Because I think a lot of times we're not as accepting of differences, but
                there were a large number of people from other countries there. And that's fine. I
                think that enriches the campus. But hey, how about me? I'm a citizen, I'm a
                taxpayer. [laughs] No, they didn't reach out to me. Now, maybe they were somewhat
                afraid to as well with all the publicity.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>You know, I was just thinking about something. You mentioned isolation. Was
                it any discussion on . . . I know that the cases were class action cases . . .
            </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> [Agrees] </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>It was not representing just one person. </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> One person, right, right.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> Had . . . Then, I think about Robert Collins coming with Ernest Morial, and
                then, later, six students coming.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[49:38]</start>
            <transcript> Came after me, yeah. They entered together, yeah.</transcript>
        </cue>
        
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> Was there any discussion of trying to find more than one person to go with
                you?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> With me? </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>Yeah.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> That never came up. That never came up. That would have been marvelous. In
                fact, I think they learned . . .</transcript>
        </cue>
                
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> From that experience. </transcript>
        </cue>
        
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> . . . from that experience and other experiences, that too much pressure on
                one person . . . I mean, you go through all this legal action and then the one
                person either drops out, or he can't take it, or he could get sick, or he could just
                say, “The heck with this.” Then you've got to start all over from scratch. I think
                they did learn from experience and also just recruiting someone to do
                this.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[50:20]</start>
            <transcript> You know, I just don't know why . . . I mean truly, I never . . . I never
                sat down and planned that I would do this and it would be all this . . . this
                traumatic experience. I just thought I would . . . this thing would be over in a few
                days. People would get to know me, I'd find friends, and it would all work out. I
                never expected the kind of . . . what it represented to white people in terms of
                maybe . . . the losing control in terms of the civil rights process. Of course, how
                hopeful it was to black people. I just didn't think people would pay that much
                attention to it, because things were happening all around. I mean, this wasn't a
                time when things were not happening, but yes, it was a traumatic
                experience.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> I wonder if . . . How could you feel about telling another black student to
                go through LSU? </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> Well. . . only . . . I mean, I wouldn't have encouraged anyone at that
                point to do that unless they were in a group and had a support system. I often
                thought of Dutch Morial and Robert Collins, at least they had each other. They may
                not have always agreed on things. I mean, you don't always just because you're
                roommates and so forth, but they had each other. They could share experiences. They
                could go out to eat together. They could talk to people. You had a support system,
                and they supported one another. They were also . . . They were also graduates. They
                had been through undergraduate school. They had had all of those nurturing,
                enriching, growing experiences as an undergraduate.</transcript>

        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[52:26]</start>
            <transcript> I was only seventeen years old, and it's enough just to get into college
                and to figure out how to make it work. I didn't know how to study. I didn't know how
                to manage my time. I was developing. This just consumed all my energy. I mean, just
                surviving from day to day, keeping yourself happy and motivated, and thinking
                tomorrow will be better. But that's not what I was there for. I mean, I wanted to be
                enriched by the experience, and the emotional pieces were just so great. You were
                never without this cloud over your head. I couldn't sleep at night. They were
                banging on the walls. Then you just figure, when will this stop? There were more of
                them then there were of me so they were persistent.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript> You mentioned one time about your math class and getting tutoring
                assistance in math, setting the curve . . . </transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <transcript> Yeah. This was this old lady who had talked about she had never had . . .
                She had never taught a nigra before and she didn't know how she was going to get
                through this semester. I came home asking for some help if they could find somebody
                to help me . . . tutor me in the math. Norman Francis, who's now president of Xavier
                University, was in law school at Loyola [University]. On the weekends when I was
                home trying to get up enough strength and to rebuild my energy, emotional energy to
                go back, my father asked him to give me some time, help me with my math. Norman is a
                wonderful teacher. He was a math major. He helped me, and it was so clear that . . .
                He was just a wonderful teacher. He explained the areas that I didn't understand.
                This woman didn't take any time to help explain anything to me.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[54:48]</start>
            <transcript> When they were taking . . . I don't know if it was a midterm or what, but
                it was . . . We used to have these exams every other week or so. I remember the last
                exam I took with her . . . took for her, she announced that I set the curve. My
                grade went up from, like, a D minus, and I was starting to get into the area of
                getting Bs. I was very pleased, and I noticed something that I kind of expected but
                it was a revelation in a sense . . . or confirmation of a revelation, because in her
                class the students sat the farthest away from me. As soon as she announced that I
                had set the curve, I noticed people starting to move closer in to where I was
                sitting. In fact, one person even asked me, "Could we study together?" He did it in
                such a way, I wouldn't . . . I would have loved it, but he did it in such a way
                like, “Oh, now you can help me." Not like, “You can be my friend,” or, “we can share
                experiences together.” "Oh, oh, come over here and you can help me and we'll meet
                and" . . . Well, I said, "No, thank you." If he had been friendlier and more in a
                typical way approached me about studying together I would have welcomed
                it.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <start>[56:10]</start>
            <transcript> There were people there who wanted to use you. You learn that lesson. I
                knew that anyway from human experience. It was curious to see how people would let
                the first black student help him if it's going to help their grade, they don't . . .
                Then they wouldn't care what their friends felt. You had that kind of push and pull.
                That was an interesting experience. The vice-president had sort of said to me, "If
                you have any problems, you can come to me." But he didn't say it in a way that I was
                convinced that he meant it. I think he said it in a way that he felt maybe he had to
                say it. Maybe I . . . the kind of problems he meant was if anybody really tries to
                hurt you physically. I don't think he meant about professors not treating you
                appropriately. The other thing is, I didn't want to start continually complaining
                about people because I figured I had to work it out at my level, not at his level. I
                avoided anything that was sort of official.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <annotation>[break in tape] [. . . ?]</annotation>
            <transcript> Pamela Dean, Director of the T. Harry Williams Center for Oral History at
                LSU, shared with me a letter . . . a copy of a letter from a former white
                administrator at LSU who wrote about knowing when you came on campus in '53, and
                described an incident where white students, male students threatened you with a
                knife. His role was to, as a staff person, was to monitor your activities in the
                dorm. So when he was called because of . . . He was notified that this was
                occurring. He described coming . . . going over to the dorm and then finding some
                guys and then later finding a knife in a lamp shade. Do you recall this
                incident?</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start> [58:24]</start>
            <transcript> I have no recollection of any incident involving a knife in the dormitory
                or even being told that students were considering doing something this way. Never,
                at any time. Never when I was at LSU was there any indication to me that anyone was
                considering any aggressive behavior towards me. I have no recollection or knowledge
                of that. In fact, the typical reaction to me in the dorm was, “Don't speak to him.
                When you go into the toilet, or the shaving area, or the shower, if he goes in, you
                come out.” I can remember always having this huge bathroom area to myself. If there
                were six guys in the shower . . . It was just a big room with shower heads all
                around, no partitions or anything, twelve people could shower in the space together.
                If there were four or five guys showering, they'd be talking and joking and
                laughing, and I walked in to take a shower, whether they were soaped down or not,
                they would stop the showers, take their towels, go somewhere else. I couldn't change
                that. I didn't say . . . I didn't make any comments or whatever. Or if I was shaving
                or whatever, they just disappeared.</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue>
            <start>[1:00:10]</start>
            <transcript> I have no recollection of any of that, and I never felt threatened in the
                dorm. They did make noise to keep me up, but I have no recollection of that, and I'm
                glad I didn't. Because that could have been another problem that would have . . . I
                don't know when this incident might have happened, but I think if that kind of thing
                had been know by me or by my family . . . Now, maybe they knew and they didn't share
                it with me, but I would kind of doubt that because I think if you have a child in a
                precarious situation, you prepare them for it, so maybe they never knew it either. I
                wouldn't image the university would tell them. But that could have meant . . . At
                least, when I left . . . I left because legally I couldn't stay. I didn't leave
                because I was intimidated or threatened or whatever, and that could have had a
                different kind of impact on the evolution of the case. So no, I never . . . I didn't
                know that, and I'm surprised to hear it now.</transcript>
        </cue>
                        
        <cue>
            <speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker>
            <transcript>LSU had a number of attorneys representing them on your case . . . to be
                admitted to the undergraduate school. Did you . . . You attended a deposition once,
                and you had an opportunity to be . . . to hear what the attorneys from LSU had to
                say about you and the case. Can you describe that?</transcript>
        </cue> 
        <cue>
            <speaker>Tureaud</speaker>
            <start>[1:01:52]</start>
            <transcript> Yes, I remember that deposition, very . . . I remember the one that I went
                to very well. I went with my father, and I think it was Bob Carter. I'm not sure who
                else went, but I think it was the only one that I went to. The thing that I remember
                most about it, because I didn't quite know what to expect, I'd never been to a
                deposition before, was the presentation that Leander Perez made. My mother went. My
                mother went. I remember that now. My mother went with me to that. Leander Perez in
                either summarizing some information or whatever . . . He was very colorful. He was
                dressed in a sort of a plantation beige outfit with a sort of a string tie, or
                whatever. He was a very colorful character and used a lot of flamboyant language. He
                was very dramatic and also could be very cruel and biting and sarcastic. He was
                known around New Orleans and around Louisiana for his hatred, hatred of black people
                and mistreatment of the people that worked for him or worked for his family and all
                that kind of stuff. I had an intense dislike for him from what I knew about his
                public image even before I saw him in court. When I saw him in court, I was
                intrigued by his performance during the depositions. He was sort of the lead lawyer
                in the case. I remember how many people there were representing the state. I mean,
                and there were . . . they weren't always all at these various hearings and
                depositions, but that day I think was the first day, there were a lot of them.
                [1:04:08] One statement that he made that I'd never forget, because this was a long
                time ago, was . . . He pointed to me, and walked in my direction, and looked right
                dead at me, and said that, "There sits the only ungrateful nigra in the state of
                Louisiana, because we have gone through great expense and trouble to build up fine
                black universities in this state. Why is Mr. Tureaud not willing to avail himself of
                this opportunity." He said it with such sarcasm and with such belief, it was just
                very intimidating and it made me angry. Maybe I was, as young as I was,
                personalizing that. Because a lot of what I did in this case, although it was me,
                was symbolic. My parents had to help me with that. At seventeen, you're very
                self-centered, and you think everything is you, you, you personally, you. They were
                saying to me you're . . . He is talking about you, but he is talking about all black
                people, and all black young men, and all black students. But you happen to represent
                that and you have to be willing to accept and understand that. My mother and dad
                said to me, "You don't have to go to this deposition. If they're going to upset you,
                or you can't understand the meaning of what the action is, then don't go." I said,
                "Okay for the time being I don't need to hear that because I'm not ready to deal
                with it, and I won't go." I didn't go. I liked the options they gave me because I
                didn't have to sit there and be, what I thought was, personally insulted. Now, as an
                adult, I understand a lot better what they were saying, and I can understand a lot
                better what he was trying to accomplish as a lawyer. But, at seventeen you just
                think, "He's talking about me, and I don't like that." [1:06:29] So, in many ways
                this experience at LSU helped mature me in a way that I would not have had the
                opportunity to be matured at that age. It's another step in a person's evolution. I
                always believe that adversity creates . . . builds character. Hopefully, that was a
                way that my character was being built and developed through these challenges. But
                seventeen, it was pretty hard to take, and since they told me I didn't have to go, I
                didn't go. [laughs]</transcript>
        </cue>
        <cue><speaker>Emanuel-Wallace</speaker><end>[1:07:10]</end><transcript>Alright</transcript><annotation>
                            [End Tape 375, Side B. End Session I.]</annotation></cue>
</cues>