<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Comparison of independent study to group study methods in Mississippi basic vocational agriculture programs</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>McCully, James S.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1950-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Vocational Education.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1981</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 214 leaves : map ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>226 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purpose of this study was to compare the independent study method to the lecture-discussion method in Mississippi basic vocational agriculture classes. Student achievement, time spent in study and student and teacher opinion were utilized as dependent variables. The pretest-posttest control group design was selected for the study.;Three units of instruction were compiled for use by the two treatment groups. A pretest and posttest were developed for each unit. Two student assignments were also developed to serve as measures of student achievement. A student and teacher opinionnaire utilizing the semantic differential method was administered to measure opinions. Additionally, a standardized reading test was given to provide a measure of reading ability.;Schools in the study were selected and assigned to treatment at random. One class of students in each school participated in the study. Nine schools containing a total of 175 students completed the independent study treatment. Seven schools containing 157 students completed the lecture-discussion treatment. In the control group, there were seven schools and a total of 123 students.;Data were analyzed by computer with the unit of analysis being the school mean. Descriptive statistics used in the study included means, standard deviations, and linear correlations. Inferential statistics chosen as appropriate for testing hypotheses included analysis of variance and Students t distribution.;In relation to student achievement as measured by posttests, no significant differences were detected between the two treatments on each of the three posttests. The lecture-discussion treatment produced posttest scores significantly higher than the control group scores on all three posttests. The independent study treatment yielded significantly higher scores on two of the posttests than the control treatment.;No significant difference between the two treatment groups was detected when the student assignment scores were analyzed.;The time spent in independent study of the units was significantly less for each unit than the time spent in lecture-discussion study.;No significant difference could be shown to exist in student and teacher opinion toward instructional method. Teachers and students in the independent study group did differ significantly in their opinions toward instructional content."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by James S. McCully, Jr.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 42-06, Section: A, page: 2445."</note>
   <note>Concentration: Vocational Agricultural Education.</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1981.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 87-91.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-ms</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Independent study</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Study skills</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Agriculture</topic>
      <geographic>Mississippi</geographic>
      <topic>Study and teaching</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8126968</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1981</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">8228250</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">820309</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u14530</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1981 MCCU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8126968</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1981 MCCU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
