<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Development and experimental validation of a predictive model for puffability of gelatinized rice</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Goodman, Donald Edward</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1944-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Food Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1981</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 359 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>371 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This investigation was performed to determine the extent to which selected endogenous parameters of rice effect the puffing of rice. The objectives were (1) to measure selected physicochemical properties of a variety of rice samples, (2) to identify where possible those parameters influencing the puffing of gelatinized rice, and (3) to develop and validate regression equations for the prediction of puffing.;Under laboratory conditions designed to simulate closely an industrial rice processing environment, 113 samples of several varieties and types of rice were milled. The resulting head rice was analyzed for selected physicochemical properties. The quantitative interrelationships of several of these properties were established. Empirical models were developed for predicting the hardness of milled rice and the puffing of gelatinized, dried rice.;The physical properties of length, width, area, and volume were determined for each of the head rice samples. Hardness was determined as was amylose and protein content and reaction in dilute alkali for each sample. The samples were cooked in excess water, air dried, and puffed in hot oil. Predictive models were developed using multiple regression techniques on a randomly selected subset of 83 samples. Each model was validated using the remaining 30 samples by comparing the predicted values for load and expansion to those actually observed.;Hardness could be predicted for 67% of the holdout samples to within (+OR-)10% of the observed value using rough rice moisture content, percent head rice yield, and area-volume ratio. Expansion was accurately predicted within (+OR-)10% of the observed value for over 70% of the holdout samples using protein content, alkali spreading value, and rough rice moisture content.;Long grain samples categorically expanded to a greater degree upon puffing than did either medium or short grain samples. Three varieties of medium grain rice, Nato, Brazos, and Vista, were found to expand comparably to long grain samples. This fact, coupled with higher yields and slightly lower cost per pound of medium grain varieties when compared to long grain varieties should maintain the incentive for industrial buyers to keep buying medium grain rice."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Donald Edward Goodman.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 42-06, Section: B, page: 2292."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1981.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 181-187.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rice</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8126959</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1981</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">8224702</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">820308</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u14465</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1981 GOOD</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8126959</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1981 GOOD</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
