<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Effects of a sex education workshop in an adolescent in-patient psychiatric population</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Angelloz, Christine E.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1981</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 95 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>104 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The present study was an experimental investigation of the effects of a sex education workshop in an adolescent in-patient psychiatric population. Eleven adolescent patients (seven males, four females) participated in the eight session sex education workshop (SEW). The attention control group was composed of eight patients (four males, four females) who participated in eight informal discussion (ID) sessions. The research utilized a pretest-posttest design. The dependent variables were sex knowledge as measured by the Sex Knowledge Inventory, self-concept as measured by the Total Positive, Self Criticism, and General Maladjustment scales of the Tennessee Self Concept Scale, and personal adjustment as measured by the K, D, Pt, Sc, and Es scales of the Minnesota Multiphasic Personality Inventory. The data was analyzed using a multivariate analysis of variance followed by univariate ANOVAS on each of the nine dependent measures. Results of these analyses indicated that participation in the sex education workshop led to neither positive changes in self-concept nor increased personal adjustment as predicted because the subjects as a group yielded pretest TSCS and MMPI scores within normal limits. However, the SEW subjects obtained statistically significant increases in sex knowledge compared to the ID subjects. A specially designed participant evaluation form was administered to SEW subjects at the posttest. Subjects' ratings of the workshop were positive in terms of the helpfulness of the workshop, teaching format, and changes in self acceptance, acceptance of others, and comfort in a variety of interpersonal situations. The results of the study were discussed, noting factors idiosyncratic to the particular population used, including psychiatric diagnoses of the subjects and familial and social factors. Suggestions for future research on the effects of sex education in adolescent psychiatric patients were offered."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Christine E. Angelloz.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 42-06, Section: B, page: 2513."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1981.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 63-69.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Sex instruction</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Adolescent psychotherapy</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Psychotherapy patients</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8126946</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1981</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">8213162</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">820304</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u14135</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1981 ANGE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8126946</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1981 ANGE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
