<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>status study of educational media services in selected institutions of higher education in the United States</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <titleInfo type="alternative">
      <title>Educational media services in selected institutions of higher education in the United States</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Hutchinson, Joseph Allen</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1948-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Curriculum &amp; Instruction.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1981</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 143 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>152 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purposes of this study were (1) to determine the present status of educational media services in institutions of higher education offering doctoral programs in instructional technology; (2) to compare levels of adequacy of educational media services as perceived by educational media directors; and (3) to identify innovative practices, concepts, and emerging trends of educational media services in higher education.;A descriptive survey instrument was developed to solicit data concerning staff, budget, educational media services, physical facilities, non-print materials collections, and audiovisual equipment inventories. Survey instruments were sent to the educational media directors of the forty-two universities offering doctoral programs in instructional technology. Twenty-four usable responses were received.;Data produced by the survey were compiled into two profiles:  (1) a profile of the individual university educational media services, and (2) a profile depicting the educational media services at universities offering doctoral programs in instructional technology.;Statistical results were entered before each survey item, and a coded list of institutions responding to each survey item was provided.;The current status of the educational media services at universities offering doctoral programs in instructional technology was discussed. Levels of adequacy were also noted. Observations and recommendations were based upon a comparison of the data gathered with the concepts for educational media services as proposed by authoritative sources found in the literature. No attempt was made to evaluate the educational media service programs of individual institutions.;Educational media services including basic audiovisual equipment, materials, producting facilities, and consultation were provided by all of the institutions responding to the survey. All media centers reported were centrally organized and administered.;The aspects of the service programs most often reported by the educational media directors to be inadequate were materials collections and facilities. The respondents were about equally divided concerning their opinions of the adequacy of their budgets.;Two recommendations from this study were:  (1) that educational media services be sufficiently funded in order to eliminate the necessity of charging fees for institutionally related services and (2) that educational media services to non-institutional users be restricted to those activities which are demonstrably beneficial to the university or its relationship to the community at large."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Joseph Allan Hutchinson.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 42-06, Section: A, page: 2450."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ed. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1981.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 60-64.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us---</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Instructional materials centers</topic>
      <geographic>United States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Media programs (Education)</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8126962</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1981</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">8224878</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">820308</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u14469</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1981 HUTC</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8126962</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1981 HUTC</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
