<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>influence of exogenous plant growth regulators on sucrose accumulation in sugarcane (Saccharum sp.)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Dill, Gerald Matthew</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1952-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Plant Pathology and Crop Physiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1981</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 137 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>151 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The effect of glyphosate on immature internodal tissue of three sugarcane varieties was examined. Sucrose content (mg/g dry wt) increased after treatment application throughout the 7 week period of sampling in the experiment in all varieties examined. Increases in sucrose percent and commercially recoverable sugar per ton (CRS/T) determined by whole stalk analysis were observed in NCo 310 and CP 61-37 4 weeks after glyphosate application. A greater percent increase in sucrose content of immature internodal tissues over control than that observed by whole stalk analysis was noted at this time.;The plant growth regulators glyphosine, ethephon, mefluidide and glyphosate applied to L 62-96 increased the sucrose content of immature internodal tissues examined. Glyphosate appeared to effect a larger increase in this response. The increase observed in sucrose content of these tissues was also observed in sucrose percent and CRS/T at 4 weeks after treatment application. The magnitude of the increase in sucrose content in immature internodal tissues was greater than that observed in whole stalk sugar analysis.;The effect of glyposate on endogenous glucose and fructose levels in CP 65-357, CP 61-37 and NCo 310 was evaluated. These levels of glucose and fructose declined throughout the 7 weeks of the experiment. Reducing sugar levels declined more rapidly in glyphosate treated tissues when compared to controls.;Sucrose uptake rates by slices of immature storage parenchyma tissue of sugarcane stalks were examined after glyphosate application. Increased sucrose uptake rates were observed in NCo 310 after glyphosate treatment. This response coincided with increased sucrose content of these same tissues in the experiment. Increases in the rate of sucrose uptake observed in tissue slices of CP 65-357 and CP 61-37 after glyphosate application were not statistically significant.;Neither sucrose percent, average stalk weight nor CRS/T as determined by whole stalk analysis were correlated with seedling in vivo nitrate reductase (NR) activity in the 18 varieties examined. NR activity of greenhouse grown sugarcane seedlings was not indicative of those same seedlings grown in the field. No differences in NR activity were observed between glyphosate treated and untreated commercial varieties throughout the experiment."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Gerald Matthew Dill, Jr.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 42-06, Section: B, page: 2162."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1981.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 93-98.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Sugarcane</topic>
      <topic>Growth</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Growth (Plants)</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8126954</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation / Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1981</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">8224459</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">820308</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u14448</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1981 DILL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8126954</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1981 DILL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
