<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Growth, Development and synchronization of larval Diatraea saccharalis and characterization of plasma juvenile hormone esterase</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Roe, Richard Michael</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1952-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Entomology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1981</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 89 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>99 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Male sugarcane borer, Diatraea saccharalis (F.), larvae at egg hatch were equal in weight to females, but on artificial diet, pupated in less time and achieved a smaller larval maximum and 1 day old pupal weight. The peak period for egg hatch and ecdysis was within a few hours after lights-on, and pupation occurred at random. Males completed larval development in 5 and 6 stadia and females in 6 stadia. Net larval growth was greater for males and females completing development in 6 stadia than in 5 stadia. Ecdysis to the last stadium occurred during the 12th to 14th day after egg hatch. By choosing last stadium 0 day old borers (GREATERTHEQ) 70 mg and 1 day old borers (GREATERTHEQ) 140 mg, a synchronous population of female sugarcane borers was obtained which completed the last stadium in 5 days. The prepupal stage occurred during the 5th day. Synchronous female borers were used in a physiological study of growth during the last stadium. The results were consistent with the literature and were reproducible even when tested as much as 1 year apart.;A peak in the plasma juvenile hormone esterase (JHE) activity occurred near the time when female last stadium borers reached their maximum weight, and a second peak of plasma JHE activity and a peak in the plasma (alpha)-naphthyl acetate esterase ((alpha)-NAE) activity occurred at the prepupal stage. The peak JHE activity was 1.73 nmoles/min/ml and the peak (alpha)-NAE activity was 123.6 nmoles/min/ml. The last stadium JHE and (alpha)-NAE activity pattern, the inhibition profile, enzyme stability, isoelectric focusing, gel filtration, and HPLC analysis indicated that JH I and JH III was metabolized by the same JH specific esterase(s) distinct from the (alpha)-NAE's. Juvenile hormone I was metabolized at twice the rate of JH III. Two JHE forms were resolved by isoelectric focusing and by HPLC analysis. The surgarcane borer JHE activity was not inhibited by paraoxon as it was in other Lepidoptera studied. The apparent K(,m) for the JHE metabolism of JH I was 2.80 uM."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Richard Michael Roe.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 42-06, Section: B, page: 2222."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1981.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 72-74.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Diatreae</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Sugarcane borer</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Sugarcane</topic>
      <topic>Diseases and pests</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8126977</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1981</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">8239012</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">820312</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u14737</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1981 ROE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8126977</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1981 ROE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
