<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Attitudes held by selected public school administrators in Louisiana towards vocational education</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Miller, Paul Gibson</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1944-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Vocational Education.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1981</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 237 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>247 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study was concerned with determining attitudes held by local school administrators in Louisiana towards vocational education and with comparing their attitudes towards specific vocational programs.;The descriptive method of research using an opinionnaire was used to gather data. Opinionnaires were mailed to the 66 public school superintendents, the supervisor for vocational education of each of the 66 public school systems, and to a stratified random sample of 186 public school principals in Louisiana. Two hundred ninety-five of 318 opinionnaires were returned representing 92.8 percent of the population.;Statistical procedures used for analysis were means, guidelines, developed by the researcher, to interpret practical significant differences, and the Spearman rho coefficient of correlation. Null hypotheses were tested and were accepted or rejected at the .05 level of confidence when testing for correlations.;All groups of administrators tended to respond favorably to selected statements towards vocational education and towards six specific vocational programs. ""Slight or low"" practical significant differences existed among the three groups in 10 of 25 selected statements towards vocational education. Significant differences existed in attitudes among the three groups towards all six specific vocational programs. Attitudes that each school administrator has towards the six vocational programs vary significantly and tend to be favorable. Population density and classroom teaching experiences affect the attitudes that school administrators have towards vocational education in general and towards all six specific vocational programs.;Significant relationships at the .05 level of confidence existed between school size and the attitudes that principals have towards vocational education.;Based on the findings, it was recommended that: training institutions provide opportunities for administrators to acquire a knowledge and understanding of vocational programs, better counseling practices and better scheduling procedures be established, attention be given by teachers to placing vocational students in jobs for which they have been trained, efforts be made to increase student interest in vocational programs, course content in Vocational Agriculture, Vocational Home Economics, and Health Occupations be revised, continued efforts be made to train the physically and/or mentally handicapped, viable youth clubs be maintained, findings of this research be desseminated among vocational leaders."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Paul Gibson Miller.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 42-06, Section: A, page: 2445."</note>
   <note>Concentration: Vocational Agricultural Education.</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1981.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 213-217.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>School administrators</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
      <topic>Attitudes</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Vocational education</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8126970</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1981</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">8228482</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">820309</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u14544</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1981 MILL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8126970</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1981 MILL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
