<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Construct validity of depression and anxiety in pre-adolescents and adolescents</title>
      <subTitle>a taxometric approach</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Carey, Michael P. (Michael Patrick)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1957-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 201 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>211 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The similarities and differences of the response classes of depression and anxiety were investigated with a sample of pre-adolescents and adolescents. The subjects were 412 pre-adolescents and adolescents from a local public school and a local psychiatric hospital. All of the participants were administered a battery of self-rating on two consecutive days. Two self-ratings of depression and two anxiety measures were utilized in order to adequately sample the content domains. Additionally, self-ratings were used to assess nine related response classes (i.e, fears, social skills, major life events, activity, hopelessness, depressed mood, anxious mood, parent-adolescent conflict, and dysfunctional thoughts). All assessment measures were evaluated in terms of their psychometric properties e.g., internal consistency, homogeneity, test-retest reliabilities, and criterion-related validity. The findings from these analyses indicated that all but one of the measures exhibited high internal consistency and homogeneity. Moreover, those measures for which test-retest reliability was assessed exhibited acceptable temporal stability. Regarding the criterion-related validity, as expected, the total scores from the depression and anxiety measures were moderately correlated. Additionally, only in a few instances did the demographic variables correlate significantly with one or more of the independent or dependent variables. Regarding the first primary analysis, the findings from the revised 2 (gender) x 2 (Trait; depression and anxiety present, depression and anxiety absent) extreme groups MANOVA indicated that the two traits could be significantly differentiated in the predicted direction, however, using this approach two Traits (anxiety present, depression present) were excluded due to zero cell sizes. The second primary analysis, cluster analysis, indicated that eight clusters could be reliably replicated across samples. These cluster(s) appear to represent each of the following response classes: depression and anxiety present, depression present, anxiety present, depression and anxiety absent. In summary, based on the findings from this study it appears that depression and anxiety can be significantly differentiated when a multivariate approach such as cluster analysis is used in an appropriate manner."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Michael P. Carey.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-02, Section: B, page: 7420."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 146-161).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Anxiety in children</topic>
      <topic>Testing</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Anxiety in adolescence</topic>
      <topic>Testing</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Depression in children</topic>
      <topic>Testing</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Depression in adolescence</topic>
      <topic>Testing</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Psychometrics</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8904528</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">22997451</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910122</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1017491</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 CARE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8904528</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 CARE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
