<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>study to investigate the effects of state taxation and plan type on small employer retirement plan cost</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <titleInfo type="alternative">
      <title>Effects of state taxation and plan type on small employer retirement plan cost</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Smith, W. Robert.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>E.J. Ourso College of Business</namePart>
      <namePart>Department of Accounting</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 154 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>165 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Congress enacted legislation in 1978 (Revenue Act of 1978) that created a new type of retirement plan, the simplified employee plan. Congress believed that the administration costs associated with existing plans, especially qualified plans, were an undesirable obstacle to plan adoption and maintenance among small employers. Qualified plan participants, i.e., employees, in many cases are able to receive substantial reductions in the amount of tax due on retirement plan distributions. One of the primary differences between qualified plans and the simplified employee plans mentioned above is that under certain circumstances the tax due on distributions from qualified plans may be computed using a special federal averaging computation. Some states allow similar tax relief for distributions from qualified retirement arrangements. Simplified employee plans do not qualify for this preferential federal tax treatment. Therefore, even if simplified employee plans reduce the administration costs incurred by employers, the amount actually available to plan participants after taxes under a simplified employee plan may be substantially lower than the amount available to participants in qualified retirement plans. This paper describes a computer simulation of the costs small employers incur to provide after-tax retirement benefits to employees. These costs were analyzed to determine if simplified employee plans actually lowered the costs small employers incur. In this study, the after-tax costs small employers incur under both qualified plans and simplified employee plans were compared to determine if the creation of simplified employee plans achieved the congressional objective of cost reduction for small employers. Of particular interest were the tax costs small employers incur because of the various methods of taxing plan participants at the state level."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by W. Robert Smith.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 49-12, Section: A, page: 3782."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 146-151).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Postemployment benefits</topic>
      <topic>Costs</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Postemployment benefits</topic>
      <topic>Taxation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Taxation, State</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8904568</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">22992856</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910121</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1017384</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 SMIT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8904568</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 SMIT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
