<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>toxic metabolite produced by Diaporthe phaseolorum var. caulivora, the causal organism of stem canker of soybean</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Burra, Lalitha</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1956-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Plant Pathology and Crop Physiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 69 leaves : col. ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>70 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The role of a toxic metabolite in the stem canker disease of soybean was investigated. Isolates of Dpc produced a metabolite in the culture filtrate which produced symptoms similar to stem canker on soybean plants. The severity of symptoms was dose dependent. The isolate from Opelousas, Louisiana produced significantly higher amounts of the toxin than the other isolates. A positive correlation was seen between the amount of toxin produced and the severity of disease produced by the Dpc isolates. Among twelve plant species tested, only soybean and lima bean, were sensitive to the toxin. Reaction of five soybean cultivars to the culture filtrates of the Dpc isolates did not reflect the resistance of the cultivars to the pathogen as seen in the field.;Spectral analyses indicated that the toxic metabolite is a low molecular weight aromatic compound, has one or more hydroxyl groups, methyl groups and C=C, and has a reducing nature. The trifoliates were not sensitive to cytochalasins H and B, but were sensitive to a toxic metabolite produced by a Phomopsis sp. isolated from wilted pine trees. Some of the chemical properties of Dpc toxin are similar to the Phomopsis/pine wilt toxin. Preliminary studies indicated a similar molecular ion peak of the two toxins.;The initial symptom of toxin action was a red discoloration of midrib and veins before chlorosis was observed. The toxin induced yellow autofluorescence of vascular bundles. The fluorescence was also associated with lesions on the plant parts. The discoloration of the midrib and veins, and lesions on the plant were due to accumulation of phenols which are alkali soluble, can be extracted and separated by thin layer chromatography, and react with Folin-Ciocalteu reagent and ferric chloride. Two phenolic compounds, and a compound showing yellow fluorescence, not seen in untreated samples were observed in the toxin treated and fungus inoculated samples suggesting a common host response to toxin action and fungal inoculation. The role of toxin in the stem canker disease appears to be as a virulence factor."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Lalitha Burra.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 49-12, Section: B, page: 5090.;Directors: Johnnie P. Snow; Gerard T. Berggren."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Diaporthe phaseolorum</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Canker (Plant disease)</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8904527</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">22837178</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">901211</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1012445</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 BURR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8904527</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 BURR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
