<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>DNA methylation, chromatin structure and expression of maize ribosomal RNA genes</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Jupe, Eldon Ralph</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1958-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Biochemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1988</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 104 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>115 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The restriction endonuclease HpaII was utilized to examine ribosomal RNA gene (rDNA) methylation in maize and teosinte leaf DNA. Much of the rDNA was inaccessible to HpaII cleavage indicating that these repeat units were completely methylated. In all of the DNAs examined, a significant fraction (10-25%) of the rDNA was cleaved at least once by HpaII into repeat unit length (9.1 kbp) fragments. The undermethylated HpaII sites mapped to the intergenic spacer (IGS) region of the rDNA. The major site of undermethylation was located in a region near the transcriptional start site.;An EcoRI polymorphism, present in the 26S gene of certain maize inbred lines, was utilized to correlate rDNA undermethylation, DNaseI sensitivity and expression. In double digest experiments with EcoRI and HpaII, the fragments originating from repeat units with two EcoRI sites (8.0 kbp) are sensitive to HpaII digestion, but the fragments originating from repeat units with a single EcoRI site (9.1 kbp) in polymorphic lines are resistant to HpaII digestion. To examine rDNA chromatin structure, intact nuclei were purified and digested briefly with increasing amounts of DNaseI. Analysis of this DNA with EcoRI showed that the 8.0 kbp fragments were extremely sensitive to DNaseI digestion, but the 9.1 kbp fragments were relatively resistant even at high levels of DNaseI. Specific sites hypersensitive to DNaseI cleavage were located in the IGS of the rDNA in a region near the major undermethylated site.;Experiments utilizing the polymerase chain reaction and direct rRNA sequencing indicated that the EcoRI polymorphism is due to sequence change in the rDNA. Oligonucleotide probes specific for the region surrounding and including the EcoRI polymorphic site were used to examine rRNA transcripts in inbred lines and hybrids created by crossing EcoRI polymorphic and nonpolymorphic inbred lines. Results from these experiments indicate that the majority of the rRNA transcripts in a hybrid originate from the EcoRI polymorphic arrays when the maternal parent is EcoRI polymorphic. In the reciprocal cross, the EcoRI nonpolymorphic rRNA transcripts seem to be predominate. This suggests that a transcription factor in the maternal genome may determine which rDNA arrays are transcribed."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Eldon Ralph Jupe.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-05, Section: B, page: 1909."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 83-95).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Corn</topic>
      <topic>Genetics</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Methylation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Chromatin</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Gene expression</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8917828</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24253111</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910819</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1061661</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 JUPE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8917828</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 JUPE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
