<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>An </nonSort>
      <title>initial identification of parasite specific immune responses in the jird (Meriones unguiculatus) infected with Brugia pahangi</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Farrar, Rita G.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1943-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1988</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vi, 178 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>185 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Brugia pahangi infections in the jird (Meriones unguiculatus) is an accepted experimental model for the study of human lymphatic filariasis. Initial identification of parasite specific immune responses in jirds infected with B. pahangi are reported here.;Antibody reactivity in sera from singly and multiply infected jirds against different stages of B. pahangi was determined using an indirect fluorescent antibody technique. All life cycle stages of the parasite were examined. Antibodies recognizing all stages were present in all serum samples. Removal of antibody reactivity by absorption of jird sera with B. pahangi antigen coated beads indicated that the antibodies were parasite specific. The surface was not recognized as immunogenic in jirds. Temporal occurrence of stage or organ specific antibody was not observed.;Antibody responses of infected jirds to a soluble somatic extract of B. pahangi were further characterized by Western blot analysis. Antibody recognition of parasite antigens appeared to be independent of ELISA antibody titlers, lymphatic lesion severity, microfilaremia levels, inoculum size or numbers of adult parasites recovered. However, antibody recognition of 37 kD, 21 kD, 17 kD and 15 kD protein bands appeared to correspond with certain parasitological and/or host interactive events. Chronological association of antibody responses to these proteins were identical in singly and multiply infected jirds. No association between antibody recognition of antigens and severity of lymphatic lesions suggests that antibody is not directly involved in the pathogenesis of lymphatic lesions.;The soluble somatic extract of B. pahangi was fractionated with lectin affinity chromatography and high performance liquid chromatography, yielding a glycoprotein pool and seven HPLC fractions. Pulmonary granulomatous inflammatory and in vitro lymphocyte blastogenic responses were measured and compared. Granulomas were induced by the glycoprotein pool and three HPLC fractions. A pulmonary eosinophilic perivascular inflammatory infiltrate appeared to be associated with granuloma size. Results indicate that the fractionation methods used yielded fractions that retained antigenicity and were both qualitatively and quantitatively different. Fractions containing antigens inducing a pulmonary granulomatous response were identified. Two fractions with suppressive properties were also identified. Some correlation between in vivo granulomatous responses and in vitro blastogenesis was observed."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Rita G. Farrar.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-05, Section: B, page: 1840."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 161-175.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Filariasis</topic>
      <topic>Animal models</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Filariasis</topic>
      <topic>Immunologial aspects</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8917813</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">19474891</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LBD</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">890329</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1063731</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 FARR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8917813</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 FARR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
