<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>An </nonSort>
      <title>investigation of the fungus, Balansia cyperi Edg., and its effect on purple nutsedge, Cyperus rotundus L</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Stovall, Mary Elizabeth</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1949-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Botany.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1988</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 157 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>165 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study was designed to investigate host specificity of the fungus Balansia cyperi Edg. on Cyperus rotundus L. (purple nutsedge) and to determine the effect of fungus presence on the biology and ecology of the sedge. Isolates of epiphytic Balansias from C. rotundus and C. virens had similar cultural characters, conidium morphology, and extracellular enzyme activity in artificial culture. However, B. cyperi from C. rotundus had a faster growth rate, greater conidium production, and higher temperature optimum than did the isolate from C. virens. Artificial infection of C. rotundus by B. cyperi from C. rotundus was far more successful than infection by the isolate from C. virens. These results suggest that host specificity may exist.;Evidence obtained in this study indicates that purple nutsedge gains three selective advantages from fungus infection. Non-choice and preference feeding experiments conducted in the laboratory showed that larval weight and to a lesser extent larval growth rate were significantly reduced when the fall armyworm was fed leaves from B.cyperi-infected purple nutsedge as compared to uninfected leaves; larvae also preferred uninfected leaves. Therefore one advantage is reduced herbivory on uninfected plants. A second advantage of infection to the sedge is escape from other infection. This is indicated by growth inhibition of fungi isolated from C. rotundus by B. cyperi mycelium, culture medium, and infected leaf extracts. Growth in culture of potentially pathogenic fungi was statistically reduced in the presence of extracts from infected sedges as compared to uninfected sedges. In greenhouse studies epiphyte infection accounted for increased vegetative growth--the third advantage. Vegetative shoot number and total dry weight were significantly greater while inflorescence number in infected plants decreases as compared to uninfected plants. Infected plants produced more, but smaller tubers than uninfected plants. Thus, the ecological status of the association between B. cyperi and purple nutsedge appears to be mutualistic."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Mary Elizabeth Stovall.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-05, Section: B, page: 1754.;Directors: Meredith Blackwell; Keith Clay."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Balansia</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Nutgrass</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Symbiosis</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8917860</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24307631</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910829</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1062559</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 STOV</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8917860</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 STOV</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
