<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Effectiveness of the healthy weight workshop on weight management practices of paraprofessional personnel of the Cooperative Extension Service</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Reames, Beth.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Vocational Education.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1988</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 136 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>146 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study was designed to investigate the effects of participation by black female paraprofessionals in a weight management workshop on selected indices including dietary intake, nutrition knowledge, exercise practices, eating behaviors, anthropometric measurements and sick leave hours used. Nineteen subjects from one urban site were selected to participate in the workshop and 18 subjects from another urban site served as the comparison group. Data were collected from both groups one week before, one week after and six months following the workshop.;Measurements obtained before the workshop showed that the two groups had similar characteristics and pretest scores. Anthropometric measurements indicated that both groups were obese, with an average weight of 185 pounds for the comparison group and 190 pounds for the treatment group.;Immediately following the workshop, significant improvements were noted for the treatment group in dietary intake, nutrition knowledge, exercise practices and eating behaviors. No significant changes were noted for the comparison group. Comparison of measurements between the two groups indicated that the treatment group's dietary intake, nutrition knowledge and exercise practices were significantly better than those of the comparison group.;The treatment group showed several significant improvements including dietary intake, nutrition knowledge, weight and BMI when measurements at six months were compared to those immediately following the workshop. When measurements at six months were compared to those immediately preceding the workshop, significant improvements were noted for the treatment group on seven of the eight measurements including dietary intake, nutrition knowledge, exercise practices, eating behaviors, weight, BMI and sick leave hours used. No significant improvements were found for the comparison group at either measurement period.;Comparison of the two groups six months after the workshop indicated that the treatment group had significantly better measurements for dietary intake, nutrition knowledge, exercise practices, eating behaviors, weight and BMI than the comparison group.;Based on these findings, it was concluded that participation in the workshop resulted in improvement of selected indices related to weight management for these subjects."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Elizabeth S. Reames.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-08, Section: A, page: 2408."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 100-106).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <name type="corporate">
         <namePart>Louisiana Cooperative Extension Service.</namePart>
         <role>
            <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
            <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
         </role>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Weight loss</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Nutrition extension work</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>African American women</topic>
      <topic>Health and hygiene</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8917847</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24307711</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910829</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1062578</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 REAM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8917847</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 REAM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
