<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Mastitis in single and multiple trait Holstein lines</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Vaamonde, Ricardo J. (Ricardo Jose)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1954-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Dairy Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1988</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xv, 195 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>211 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Cows diagnosed as having clinical mastitis and from two sire selection lines were compared to assess differences in somatic cell count scores, duration of clinical episode and number of antibiotic treatments applied. The effect of various environmental factors and type traits on somatic cell count score (SCCS) and on duration of episode was investigated and amount and cost of discarded milk was calculated.;Data consisted of multiple observations on cows diagnosed as clinically infected at least once during a lactation. Single trait (ST) cows were daughters of sires selected based on predicted differences for milk. Multiple trait (MT) cows were daughters of sires selected based on an index of milk, fat and type.;Single trait cows had significantly lower SCCS, had longer clinical episodes and received more antibiotic treatments than MT cows. Least squares mean estimates for SCCS were 1.71 for the ST line and 4.86 for the MT line. Means for days of discarded milk were 16.70 days for the ST line and 7.80 days for the MT line. Estimate for number of treatments were 24.58 for the ST line and 13.44 for the MT line. These differences increased across generations.;Results indicated that slower milking cows tended to have lower SCCS, longer episodes and receive more antibiotic treatments. Cows with larger udders before milking had shorter episodes and received less treatments. Cows with larger udders after milking had longer episodes and required more treatments. Taller cows and cows with high udders had higher SCCS and shorter episodes.;Single trait cows had significantly more milk discarded due to antibiotic treatment than MT cows. Means for amount of discarded milk for the ST and MT lines were 360.81 kg and 250.99 kg, respectively. The ST line was, however, significantly higher for milk production even after deducting milk losses. Amount of discarded milk was negatively associated with size of udder area before milking, udder height and wither height and positively associated with size of udder area after milking and machine time.;Use of some mastitis traits in selection and culling decisions may be necessary."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Ricardo J. Vaamonde.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-05, Section: B, page: 1708."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 163-176).</note>
   <note type="acquisition">Gift ; LSU Dept. of Dairy Science ; 2003 ; midl c.1.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Mastitis</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Dairy cattle</topic>
      <topic>Genetics</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8917866</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24307606</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910829</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1062552</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 VAAM 378.76 L930D 1988 VAAM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8917866</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 VAAM 378.76 L930D 1988 VAAM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
