<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Epidemiology of Campylobacter jejuni</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Yogasundram, Kanagasundaram</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1943-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1988</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1988</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 164 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>173 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A study was conducted to determine the prevalence of Campylobacter jejuni in various avian species and humans.;Cloacal swabs derived from birds submitted to the Louisiana Veterinary Medical Diagnostic Laboratory for necropsy examination during the period February 1987 through July 1988 were routinely cultured for C. jejuni using Butzler's selective medium. Campylobacter jejuni was isolated from 10.1% of the cases examined. The isolation rate was 25.2% in Galliformes, 12.9% in Anseriformes, 8.3% in Columbiformes, 7.7% in Falconiformes, and 0.6% in Psittaciformes. None of the other orders of birds examined yielded C. jejuni. Prevalence data demonstrated that Galliformes are important reservoirs of C. jejuni infection for humans and that Psittacines do not represent any significant risk to human contacts.;Prevalence of C. jejuni in diarrheic patients was studied during a one-year period, from August 1987 through July 1988. Of a total 1423 fecal samples cultured, 38 yielded C. jejuni giving an isolation rate of 2.7%. This is comparable to the 2.6% prevalence rate obtained in a similar study in Texas. Prevalence rate for Salmonella spp. during the same study was 2.0%. Seasonal fluctuation in prevalence of C. jejuni in humans was demonstrated, with a peak in Summer and a smaller increase in Winter. A high incidence was observed in children under 5 years, and in adults aged 21 to 25 and 31 to 40 years.;The Penner serotyping system was able to classify 91.1% of the isolates obtained from human patients and 96.7% from avian species. Fourteen of the 16 serotypes considered in the present study were identified among the isolates. Eight of the serotypes were common to both avian species and humans indicating the potential for zoonotic transmission of C. jejuni infection from birds. Serotype Penner 1 was isolated only from avian species indicating the low risk this serotype poses for humans while serotype Penner 10 was isolated mainly from humans suggesting that this serotype is transmitted by direct contact or acquired from non-avian species.;Two serotypes (Penner 5 and 10) showed consistent production of enterotoxins. Toxin was produced by 75% of human and 85% of avian isolates demonstrating the considerable potential for human infection with toxigenic strains of C. jejuni."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Kanagasundaram Yogasundram.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-05, Section: B, page: 1804."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1988.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 140-161.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Campylobacter infections</topic>
      <topic>Epidemiology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Foodborne diseases</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Birds</topic>
      <topic>Diseases</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:8917872</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1988</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">18895767</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LBD</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">881213</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1063469</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1988 YOGA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">8917872</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1988 YOGA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
