<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Toward an eschatological curriculum theory</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Slattery, George Patrick</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1953-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Curriculum &amp; Instruction.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1989</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 200 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>214 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study explores the relationship between eschatology and curriculum theory. Themes such as liberation, emancipatory knowledge, transformative pedagogy, concepts of time, impact of the future on present experience, and learning landscapes are traced in the emerging literature of theology and of curriculum theory. The mutual interest in these themes in both fields of study provides the basis for moving toward an eschatological curriculum theory. The reconceptualization which has occurred in curriculum theory and the new emphasis on eschatology in twentieth century theology both provide a foundation for this curriculum theory rooted in hope.;In contemporary theology there is a movement which parallels the reconceptualization in education. Jurgen Moltmann's work is at the forefront of the rediscovery of eschatology as the focus of the whole of theology. Also, Karl Rahner grounds eschatology in experiences of the present. The future is that which brings to completion what has already been set in motion.;The work of Moltmann and Rahner has laid the foundation for the appearance of a new framework for eschatological theology which is struggling to emerge in the 1980s. Identifying this new framework and relating it to contemporary curriculum discourses for the purpose of moving toward a postmodern eschatological curriculum theory is the focus of this study.;If the reconceptualization reflected in theological and educational theories is to transform society and alter the conception of school curriculum, then scholarly investigation into the various dimensions of the theories must be undertaken. This study explores contemporary eschatological theology and contemporary curriculum theory for the purpose of contributing to the development of a model of education for the third millennium rooted in liberation and hope. This study contends that modern educational movements which have envisioned a new world order based upon technological solutions have not only failed to liberate humanity, but have actually resulted in an impoverishment of the human spirit verging on despondency and self-destruction. Eschatology can provide curriculum theory with a dimension that will allow hope to replace apathy as the predominant ethos in the school culture."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by George Patrick Slattery.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-08, Section: A, page: 2378."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references  (leaves 178-198).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Education</topic>
      <topic>Philosophy</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Eschatology</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9002171</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24600158</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">911022</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1069841</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 SLAT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9002171</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 SLAT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
