<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Geomorphic and stratigraphic evolution of the middle Amite River valley, southeastern Louisiana</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Autin, Whitney J.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geology and Geophysics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1989</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 177 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>187 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Many streams of the northern Gulf of Mexico coastal plain have similar geomorphic and stratigraphic character and comparable influences on their drainage basin evolution. Potential geomorphic influences on floodplain morphology vary temporally and spatially in their effect and include inherent geomorphic processes, eustatic sea level rise, evolution of a stream's receiving basin, adjustment to active tectonics, and local climate fluctuation. A 14.3-km segment of meander belt in the middle Amite River valley in southeastern Louisiana was selected to test the relative effect of geomorphic factors on Holocene floodplain evolution. Floodplain evolution in this valley responded to sea level rise and sedimentation in the Mississippi River delta plain; however, channel response to peak floods and variability in bank stratigraphy imprint over the more general floodplain influences.;Three alloformations, identified as Magnolia Bridge (MAG), Denham Springs (DS), and Watson (WAT), can be differentiated by unconformable boundaries, landscape morphology, and relative pedogenic development. Sedimentary deposits consist of a lower sandy and upper silty facies. Lithofacies and sedimentary environments are dependent on fluvial process and independent of alloformation boundaries. Preserved lithofacies consist of channel deposits, point bar and scroll bar deposits, channel fill, and overbank deposits. Separation of flow during large floods into primary and secondary components controls lithofacies geometry.;Surface horizons of all alluvial soils are similar, but the overlie stratified parent material (Entisols) on the MAG, cambic horizons (Inceptisols) on the DS, and minimally developed argillic horizons (Alfisols) on the WAT. Important pedogenic processes include worm bioturbations and water table fluctuations that control the distribution of color mottles, stains, and sesquioxide concretions. Particle-size distributions indicate that soils formed in the silty facies from stratified alluvium.;Alluvial stratigraphy and chronology indicate an active meander belt (WAT) by at least 9 ka, when sea level was lower and the Amite River was tributary to a larger drainage basin that extended across an exposed continental shelf. The DS became an active meander belt by 3 ka, after the Mississippi River delta formed the Pontchartrain basin. The current meander belt (MAG) developed, in part, during the European settlement of the drainage basin."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Whitney Joseph Autin.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-09, Section: B, page: 3883."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 79-91).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Geomorphology</topic>
      <geographic>Amite River Valley (Miss. and La.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Geology</topic>
      <geographic>Amite River Valley (Miss. and La.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <geographic>Amite River (Miss. and La.)</geographic>
      <topic>Alluvial plain</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9002121</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24556305</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">911014</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1067600</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 AUTI 378.76 L930D 1989 AUTI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9002121</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 AUTI 378.76 L930D 1989 AUTI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
