<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Illness behavior and the preoperative prediction of postoperative pain in cholecystectomy patients</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Tynes, Lannis Lee</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1958-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1989</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 138 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>146 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Eighty (80) elective cholecystectomy patients volunteered to participate in the present study which assessed the relation between past illness behavior and the report of pain following surgery. A review of the literature indicated that demographic variables (e.g., sex, age) and general psychological variables (e.g. state anxiety) have been the subject of many studies attempting to predict postoperative pain, yet learning and behavioral factors such as past illness behavior and familial modelling of illness behavior have not. Preoperative assessments included the Illness Behavior Inventory (IBI; Turkat, 1983), the Familial Illness Behavior Inventory (IBI-F; derived from the IBI), the State Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI) and the Eysenck Personality Inventory (EPI). Postoperative pain scores consisted of a Visual Analogue Scale of pain, the McGill Pain Questionnaire, and the amount of postoperative narcotic analgesics required. Results of multiple regression analyses revealed that the Social Illness Behavior factor of the IBI and the mother rating of the IBI-F were significant predictors of postoperative pain scores. The psychological variables of state anxiety, trait anxiety, and neuroticism (EPI) had been obtained in order to compare their efficacy with the illness behavior variables in the prediction of postoperative pain. These particular psychological variables had been demonstrated by other researchers to be relatively reliable predictors of pain report following surgery. When the illness behavior measures and the psychological measures were both entered as independent variables, postoperative pain was predicted most generally from both state anxiety (STAI) and the Social Illness Behavior factor of the IBI. Apparently, illness behavior and anxiety are valuable predictors of pain both singly and in combination. Implications of these data for future research in the prediction and management of postoperative pain are discussed."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Lannis Lee Tynes.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-08, Section: B, page: 3719."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 84-106).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Postoperative pain</topic>
      <topic>Psychological aspects</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Gallbladder</topic>
      <topic>Surgery</topic>
      <topic>Psychological aspects</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Sick</topic>
      <topic>Psychology</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9002176</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24600217</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">911022</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1069846</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 TYNE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9002176</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 TYNE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
