<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Photochemical vapor deposition of gallium arsenide utilizing ultraviolet radiation</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Norton, David Paul</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1962-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1989</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xvii, 171 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>189 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Photochemical means have been utilized to deposit arsenic, gallium and gallium arsenide thin films in an attempt to achieve deposition of gallium arsenide at substrate temperatures lower than those utilized in conventional organometallic chemical vapor deposition. Photolysis, Hg-photosensitization and light-driven pyrolysis have been utilized to obtain thin films on quartz, fused silica, gallium arsenide and silicon substrates. Triethylgallium and arsine served as the reactants with a low pressure Hg lamp, a high pressure Hg-Xe arc lamp and an ArF excimer laser serving as the ultraviolet radiation sources.;Deposition of arsenic and gallium arsenide thin films on quartz was investigated utilizing Hg-photosensitization. Arsenic thin films were deposited on quartz by means of Hg-sensitized decomposition of arsine at substrate temperatures ranging from 50 to 240$\sp\circ$C. Films deposited below 200$\sp\circ$C were found to be amorphous while those deposited above 200$\sp\circ$C consisted of rhombohedral arsenic. Gallium arsenide deposition at temperatures less than 250$\sp\circ$C utilizing Hg-photosensitization occurred only in the presence of an additional broadband ultraviolet light source. Polycrystalline gallium arsenide thin films were obtained on quartz substrates using both a low pressure Hg lamp and a Hg-Xe arc lamp.;Direct photochemical vapor deposition of gallium arsenide was also achieved on fused silica, gallium arsenide and silicon substrates. The film stoichiometry was highly dependent on the substrate temperature with arsenic-rich films obtained for substrate temperatures below approximately 250$\sp\circ$C. Single crystal gallium arsenide thin films were obtained on gallium arsenide substrates at a substrate temperature of approximately 315$\sp\circ$C with room temperature Hall mobility values as high as 4000 cm$\sp2$/V-sec. It was found that, for perpendicular beam geometry, both photolytic and pyrolytic mechanisms contributed to the thin film growth.;A mass spectroscopic study of the photolytic decomposition of the two reactants was also performed. In addition, a simple first-order model is presented for light-driven chemical vapor deposition of gallium arsenide at low substrate temperatures for which both gas-phase and surface-adsorbed species photodissociate. Results of this work indicate that the photodissociation of surface-adsorbed species is the more useful process for achieving stoichiometric GaAs deposition at low temperatures using photochemical means."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by David Paul Norton.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-08, Section: B, page: 3630."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 159-166).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Semiconductor films</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Gallium arsenide semiconductors</topic>
      <topic>Design and construction</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Vapor-plating</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Photochemistry</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9002164</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24600228</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">911022</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1069848</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 NORT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9002164</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 NORT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
