<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Studies on Trypanosoma cruzi isolates from Louisiana mammals with particular reference to infectivity to dogs</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Barr, Stephen C. (Stephen Charles)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1954-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1989</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>v, 280 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>286 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation describes studies on three Trypanosoma cruzi isolates from Louisiana mammals with particular reference to infectivity to dogs.;Isolates from an opossum (Tc-O) and armadillo (Tc-A) were obtained during a blood culture survey of these animal populations in Louisiana. Prevalence of T. cruzi were 37.5% and 1% in opossums and armadillos respectively. Further, 48% opossums had myocarditis suggestive of T. cruzi infection.;Rural dogs with known contact with T. cruzi hosts, housed rural dogs, urban animal shelter dogs and household pets showed 4.7, 0, 2.3 and 0% serological prevalence to T. cruzi respectively.;Tc-O and Tc-A (wild isolates) displayed similar in vitro characteristics, growth rate in liquid media, protein profiles on SDS-PAGE and zymodeme types. An isolate from a dog (Tc-D) displayed markedly different parameters.;Slight differences in infectivity to 6 inbred mouse strains were noted between wild isolates, but marked differences occurred between wild isolates and Tc-D. Wild isolates, but not Tc-D, produced high parasitemias, weight changes, and muscle pathology in CF1 mice.;Wild isolate infected dogs developed high parasitemias and acute myocarditis 2 to 3 weeks post infection. Survivors of acute disease developed chronic dilated cardiomyopathy within 9 months of infection. Tc-D infected dogs showed no clinical signs and low parasitemias.;Wild isolate but not Tc-D, infected dogs developed electrocardiographic abnormalities associated with conduction disturbances during acute disease, and ventricular based arrhythmias and cardiac function loss as measured by echocardiography.;Tc-D and Tc-O infected dogs had similar antibody and lymphocyte blastogenic responses to T. cruzi epimastigote antigens. Western blot analysis showed similarities and differences between infected dog serum and T. cruzi epimastigote antigens from both isolates.;Wild isolate infected dogs had severe granulomatous myocarditis, mild encephalitis and myositis during acute disease, and biventricular dilation, fibrosis and mild myocarditis during chronic disease. Minimal pathology was seen in Tc-D infected dogs.;Results indicate the wild T. cruzi isolates are similar, are virulent to dogs, and may constitute a model for human Chagas' disease. Tc-D is different from the wild isolates, and infective but non-virulent to dogs."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Stephen C. Barr.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-08, Section: B, page: 3347."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 257-267.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Trypanosoma</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Chagas' disease</topic>
      <topic>Animal models</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Dogs</topic>
      <topic>Diseases</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9002124</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">20062442</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">890724</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1067834</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 BARR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9002124</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 BARR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
