<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Mastitis in unbred and primigravid dairy heifers</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Trinidad, Pedro</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1958-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Dairy Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1989</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 154 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>168 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Prevalence of mastitis and efficacy of intramammary treatment were determined in unbred and primigravid heifers (n = 116) from 4 dairy herds. Of 97 heifers from which secretion samples were obtained, intramammary infections were detected in 96.9% of animals and 74.6% of quarters. Clinical symptoms were observed in 29% of heifers. Staphylococcus aureus infections were detected in 37.1% of animals. Teat canal colonizations were confirmed in 93.1% of heifers and 70.7% of quarters. The most common isolates from mammary glands were Staphylococcus chromogenes, Staphylococcus hyicus, and Staphylococcus aureus. Average somatic cell counts in secretion from infected and uninfected quarters were 13,574 $\times$ 10$\sp3$/ml and 5,707 $\times$ 10$\sp3$/ml, respectively. Differential cell counts demonstrated that macrophages were the most prevalent cell type in infected and uninfected quarters, followed by lymphocytes and polymorphonuclear leukocytes. A total of 311 isolates from teat canal keratin and mammary secretion samples was tested for susceptibility to 12 antibiotics. Overall, more than 92% of isolates were susceptible to all 12 antibiotics tested. Thirty-five heifers were injected intramammarily with a nonlactating cow antibiotic in all quarters and 38 served as untreated controls. Prevalence of mastitis in treated heifers was reduced from 97.1% at treatment time to 40% at parturition, whereas prevalence in control heifers decreased from 100% to 97.4%. Prevalence of Staphylococcus aureus mastitis in treated heifers was reduced from 17.1% to 2.9%, while in untreated heifers, prevalence decreased from 26.3% to 15.8%. Somatic cell counts at parturition were also lower in treated heifers. Mammary tissues from quarters of unbred heifers infected with Staphylococcus aureus exhibited less alveolar epithelium and lumen, and more interalveolar stroma compared with uninfected quarters and quarters infected with non-aureus staphylococci. Staphylococcus aureus-infected quarters also exhibited greatest leukocyte infiltration into parenchymal tissues and cisternal linings. Results of this study demonstrated a high prevalence of mastitis in heifers, and a high susceptibility of isolates to several antibiotics. In addition, intramammary treatment before parturition was highly efficacious in controlling mastitis and reducing somatic cell count in early lactation."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Pedro Trinidad.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-08, Section: B, page: 3349."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <note type="acquisition">Gift ; LSU Dept. of Dairy Science ; 2003 ; midl c.1.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Mastitis</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9002175</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24600207</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">911022</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1069845</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 TRIN 378.76 L930D 1989 TRIN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9002175</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 TRIN 378.76 L930D 1989 TRIN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
