<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>etiology and control of pepper anthracnose</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Hadden, James Forbes</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1961-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Plant Pathology and Crop Physiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued> 1989</dateIssued>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc">1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 77 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>86 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Colletotrichum gloeosporioides, C. capsici, C. acutatum, and C. coccodes incite pepper anthracnose. Species were differentiated based on their conidial and colony morphology as well as colony growth rates. In a survey of southern Louisiana pepper fields in September, 1987, anthracnose incidence ranged from 5 to 75 percent. Colletotrichum capsici, C. gloeosporioides, and C. acutatum were the incitants of anthracnose in the fields surveyed. Reactions of bell pepper and tomato fruit to isolates of C. gloeosporioides, C. capsici, C. acutatum, and C. coccodes from pepper and tomato were determined by injecting mature fruit with conidial suspensions. All isolates caused characteristic anthracnose symptoms on both hosts.;Pathogenicity of 10 Colletotrichum spp. to pepper, tomato, apple, strawberry, snap bean, and blueberry fruit was determined by inoculations with conidial suspensions. Isolates of C. gloeosporioides, C. fragariae, and C. acutatum, regardless of host origin, were pathogenic on all fruit inoculated except snap bean and could not be separated based on the reactions of fruit inoculated. Isolates of C. coccodes, C. capsici, and C. truncatum were pathogenic to pepper, tomato, and apple but not to strawberry, blueberry, or snap bean. Isolates of C. orbiculare, C. higginsianum, C. lindemuthianum and C. falcatum were not pathogenic to most fruit tested.;Crop debris and seed were investigated as sources of inoculum for pepper anthracnose. Incidence of anthracnose incited by C. capsici and C. gloeosporioides ranged from 36 to 93% throughout the season on pepper pods grown in fields with infested debris and on pods from plants grown from infected seed. Low levels, 3 to 6%, of pod infection by C. gloeosporioides occurred during early and midseason in fields with no known source of inoculum, suggesting the presence of a native plant host(s).;Fungicide timing studies were conducted to determine the efficacy of maneb and chlorothalonil sprayed at 1 to 4 wk intervals for the control of anthracnose on cayenne and bell peppers. Applications at 1 and 2 wk intervals significantly reduced disease losses. Mean disease loss int he unsprayed plots was 76%, while losses in the weekly sprayed chlorothalonil and maneb plots were 25 and 37%, respectively."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by James Forbes Hadden.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 50-08, Section: B, page: 3241."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Peppers</topic>
      <topic>Diseases and pests</topic>
      <topic>Identification</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Anthracnose</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Colletotrichum</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Peppers</topic>
      <topic>Diseases and pests</topic>
      <topic>Control</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9002146</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24559639</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">911014</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1067682</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 HADD</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9002146</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 HADD</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
