<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Effect of knowledge on teachers' interactive thinking and childrens' [sic] overhand throwing performance</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Walkwitz, Ed.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Health, Physical Education, Recreation, and Dance.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 144 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>155 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study examined the effects of knowledge of subject matter (overhand throwing) and of throwing-specific instructional strategies on teacher's interactive thinking. The impact of these two categories of teacher knowledge on lesson objectives, the quality of skill practice, and kindergartners' overhand throwing development over a unit of instruction were also explored. Eight kindergarten classroom teachers who possessed high generic teaching skill competence taught a six-week overhand throwing unit to the children (N = 150) in their intact classes. Prior to the unit, four of the teachers were exposed to a training program that increased their knowledge of overhand throwing. Four teachers (comparison group) did not experience this knowledge training. During the throwing unit, stimulated recall interviews were conducted. The interviews were audiotaped, transcribed, and coded to evaluate teacher thoughts, decisions, concerns, information sources, awarenesses, and lesson objectives. In order to determine the quality of throwing practice, the student practice trials were videotaped and analyzed for frequency of opposite foot stepping. The students were pretested and posttested on an overhand throwing test that included a throw for distance, and a developmental stage assessment (foot, pelvic-spine, and arm actions).;The results indicated that teachers' knowledge of subject matter and of content-specific instructional strategies play very important roles during throwing instruction. The knowledge that was acquired during the training sessions influenced the teachers' lesson objectives and interactive thinking. This resulted in higher quality decisions. Sound professional decision-making combined with instructional procedures and strategies which focused on specific developmental body actions enabled the knowledgeable teachers to conduct lessons where the students were engaged in a high number of correct practice trials, which in turn facilitated overhand throwing development/performance. Conversely, the knowledge deficient teachers demonstrated lesson objectives and interactive thoughts/decisions that lacked an awareness of overhand throwing developmental concepts. This resulted in poorer quality practice trials and decreased the likelihood of overhand throwing development/performance gains. The overall results support the view that formal physical education instruction in public school settings under the direction of knowledgeable teachers does make a difference."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Edward Walkwitz.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: A, page: 4490."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Physical education for children</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Physical education teachers</topic>
      <topic>Training of</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017301</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25600960</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920407</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094675</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 WALK</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017301</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 WALK</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
