<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Molecular biological studies on the degradation of diphenyl ethers by bacteria</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Liaw, Hung-Ming James</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1950-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Microbiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 134 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>144 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Microbial degradation of diphenyl ethers was studied utilizing several different approaches. The first approach was to isolate mutants from a ligninolytic Erwinia sp. by conventional mutagenesis and selection. A copper-resistant mutant, designated as Erwinia sp. CU3614, was isolated and characterized to be capable of degrading diphenyl ethers as well as one dibenzo-p-dioxin in the presence of copper ions. Isolation of Tn5 transposon-induced mutants of Erwinia sp. CU3614, which lost degradation ability, demonstrated that in all probability a copper-associated activity in the biotransformation of aromatic ethers was involved. In order to study the degradation at the molecular biological level, a 2.1 kb Hind III fragment containing Erwinia sp. dpe gene was cloned into pUC19 and introduced into Escherichia coli. The dpe gene encoded the diphenyl ether cleavage activity. The expression of dpe was detected in E. coli directly on a specially designed medium, LTFN, containing 4-nitrodiphenyl ether. Mutations generated by transposon mini-Mu dI (lacZ Km$\sp{\rm r})$ were used to define the dpe coding region, as well as the determination that the lacZ promoter of pUC19 was initiating transcription into the dpe. A peptide of molecular weight of 21 kDa was detected as the product of dpe gene in the plasmid encoded proteins. To study the activities encoded by the dpe gene, resting cell assays were used to determine the degradation of diphenyl ethers, utilizing dpe plasmid transformants of E. coli and of a salicylic acid-utilizing bacterium, designated as PE7. Bacterium PE7 was isolated from a petroleum waste pit in Louisiana, and identified to be most likely an Acinetobacter sp. A broad-host range expression plasmid, pDPE2388, constructed from subcloning dpe gene into plasmid pKT230 was used to introduce Erwinia sp. dpe gene into this bacterial isolate PE7. Expression of dpe gene in E. coli and PE7 displayed the specificity: 4-chlorodiphenyl ether $&gt;$ 4-nitrodiphenyl ether $&gt;$ 4-hydroxydiphenyl ether."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Hung-Ming James Liaw.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: B, page: 5760."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 111-133).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Aromatic compounds</topic>
      <topic>Biodegradation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Molecular microbiology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Molecular cloning</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017276</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25584906</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920403</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094255</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 LIAW</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017276</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 LIAW</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
