<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Factors associated with the production of export quality fruit by small banana farmers of the Rio Grande Valley, Portland, Jamaica</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Thomas, Terrence W.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Vocational Education.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 132 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>144 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The study was aimed at determining the relationship between two production variables--technology use, and production of export quality fruit--of small banana farmers in the Rio Grande Valley, Jamaica and selected socioeconomic, personal characteristic and opinion variables, assessing the amount of variance in production explained by the latter, and identifying variables that moderate or mediate the relationship between production variables.;The target population was 120 farmers selling bananas to a public boxing plant. A random sample of non-banana farmers was used as a cross-validation check to make inferences to all farmers.;Farmers were personally interviewed using a pretested schedule. Stepwise multiple regression models were generated to explain the variance in production variables, and mediating/moderating effects of selected personal characteristic, socioeconomic and opinion variables.;Banana and non-banana farmers were essentially similar. Therefore, inferences could be made to both groups. Ten variables explained 46% of the variation in technology use. Four socioeconomic variables (farm size, rate of use of hired labor, rejection rates, and number of visits by extension officers), explained 60% of this variance. Farmers' use of technology also tended to increase with an increase in these variables.;Four socioeconomic variables (technology use, farm size, complexity of recommended practices, and farmers' opinion of the role of extension in the farming system), explained 34% of the variation in production of export quality fruit. Farmers' use of technology tended to increase with farm size and their use of technology.;Five variables (farmers' opinions about advantages of providing credit, technology, and extension, reducing the number of extension officers, and complexity of recommended practices), moderated the effect of technology use on production. Two variables (farm size and rate of use of hired labor), mediated the effect of technology use on production.;Recommendations are to increase extension activity among farmers, improve the infrastructure of the valley, provide adequate credit to farmers, and redesign the job of extension agents so that more time is spent on educational activities rather than administrative duties. Interventions to modify the system should also follow a unified approach to capitalize on the synergy among interacting variables."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Terrence W. Thomas.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-03, Section: A, page: 7170."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 111-118).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">nwjm---</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Bananas</topic>
      <geographic>Jamaica</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Farmers</topic>
      <geographic>Jamaica</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Farms, Small</topic>
      <geographic>Jamaica</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017298</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25595269</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920406</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094340</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 THOM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017298</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 THOM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
