<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>macroeconomics of presidential popularity</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Washburn, Susan Katherine</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1962-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Economics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 228 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>239 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This thesis examines several issues dealing with the public's social preference function between inflation and unemployment. First, the preference function is estimated as a nonlinear function. Second, the thesis analyzes the ability of a presidential administration to improve its popularity level by exploiting a short-run Phillips curve. Finally, preference functions disaggregated by sex, race, political party, and geographical region are estimated. Presidential approval levels are proxied by monthly Gallup Poll approval data.;Chapter One serves as an overview of the current body of literature. While theoretical analyses of macroeconomic policy have traditionally assumed that the public's social preference function is concave to the origin, in practice most empirical studies estimate a linear relationship between presidential popularity, inflation, and unemployment.;The majority of the empirical work assumes that the impact of macroeconomic variables on political popularity remains constant across presidential regimes. Chapter Two applies appropriate tests for structural change to the data. The results indicate that structural change in economic perceptions does take place between presidential regimes and thus that each regime should be estimated separately.;The econometric study in Chapter Three examines the popularity of each president from Eisenhower to Reagan. For a majority of the presidential administrations, it demonstrates that the public's trade-off between inflation and unemployment is nonlinear. This nonlinearity indicates that the marginal rate of substitution between inflation and unemployment varies with the relative rates of the macroeconomic variables.;A major question of policy importance is whether or not an administration can increase its popularity in the short-run by exploiting a short-run Phillips curve. Chapter Four estimates the Phillips curves and provides evidence that while it is theoretically possible for a president to create a political business cycle, the gains in popularity are so small as to make the activity not worthwhile.;Chapter Five examines presidential approval on a disaggregated level. There exists extensive Gallup Poll data disaggregated by sex, race, political party, and geographical region. Nonlinear social preference functions are estimated for each of these groups.;Chapter Six provides a summary of the results discussed in the thesis."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Susan Katherine Washburn.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: A, page: 5790."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 211-215).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us---</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Macroeconomics</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Presidents</topic>
      <geographic>United States</geographic>
      <topic>Public opinion</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Business cycles</topic>
      <topic>Political aspects</topic>
      <geographic>United States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <geographic>United States</geographic>
      <topic>Economic conditions</topic>
      <temporal>1945-</temporal>
      <topic>Public opinion</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017303</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25600939</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920407</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094672</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 WASH</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017303</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 WASH</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
