<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Land subsidence and saltwater intrusion in coastal areas</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Yan, Song-kai</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1942-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Civil Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xv, 308 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>323 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Land subsidence and saltwater intrusion problems are encountered concurrently or individually in many coastal areas, especially where heavy pumping is exerted. In order to evaluate the extent and progress of these two phenomena in quantity and quality, a two-dimensional model, the STRALAN (Solute $\underline{\rm Tra}$nsport and $\underline{\rm Lan}$d Subsidence) model, is developed to simulate fluid movement, solute transport and land subsidence in a non-homogeneous, anisotropic, compressible and sloping aquifer system.;The governing equations of the model, i.e., the fluid mass balance equation, solute mass balance equation and land subsidence equation for confined or unconfined as well as for sloping aquifers are derived in detail. Hybridization of finite element and finite difference methods is employed for the numerical solution of the governing equations which describe the interdependent processes of fluid density-dependent saturated ground water flow, solute transport and land subsidence caused by changes of pressure due to pumping.;STRALAN model provides, as primary calculated results, piezometric drawdown (or pressure), solute concentration and subsidence spatially and temporally in the simulated subsurface system. It has a wide variety of options from which one can select to simulate either a confined aquifer or unconfined aquifer; either a horizontal or sloping aquifer; land subsidence only; saltwater intrusion only; or both of the above; steady or transient state condition for ground water flow, solute transport or land subsidence and many other options. Similar to a U.S. Geological Survey model, the SUTRA model, STRALAN also can cope with single chemical species transport including processes of solute sorption, production and decay.;STRALAN model, is applied to the Gonzales-New Orleans aquifer, New Orleans area, Louisiana, where saltwater intrusion and land subsidence are critical issues. This case study includes: the calibration of the hydrogeologic parameters in this 352 square-mile area; the verification of the model; and prediction of the drawdown, chloride concentration and land subsidence in time and space in 1995 and 2010 with several management scenarios, including surface water supply cut-off supplementary pumping and recharging well management.;The model is also verified by comparing the simulation result with an analytical solution in terms of subsidence."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Song-kai Yan.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: B, page: 8910."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 181-192).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Groundwater flow</topic>
      <topic>Mathematical models</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Subsidences (Earth movements)</topic>
      <topic>Mathematical models</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Aquifers</topic>
      <topic>Mathematical models</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Subsidences (Earth movements)</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
      <geographic>New Orleans Region</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Aquifers</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
      <geographic>New Orleans Region</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017310</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25600944</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920407</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094673</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 YAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017310</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 YAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
