<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>comprehensive methodology for algorithm characterization, regularization and mapping into optimal VLSI arrays</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Barada, Hassan Reda</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1962-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 219 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>231 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation provides a fairly comprehensive treatment of a broad class of algorithms as it pertains to systolic implementation. We describe some formal algorithmic transformations that can be utilized to map regular and some irregular compute-bound algorithms into the best fit time-optimal systolic architectures. The resulted architectures can be one-dimensional, two-dimensional, three-dimensional or nonplanar.;The methodology detailed in the dissertation employs, like other methods, the concept of dependence vector to order, in space and time, the index points representing the algorithm. However, by differentiating between two types of dependence vectors, the ordering procedure is allowed to be flexible and time optimal. Furthermore, unlike other methodologies, the approach reported here does not put constraints on the topology or dimensionality of the target architecture.;The ordered index points are represented by nodes in a diagram called Systolic Precedence Diagram (SPD). The SPD is a form of precedence graph that takes into account the systolic operation requirements of strictly local communications and regular data flow. Therefore, any algorithm with variable dependence vectors has to be transformed into a regular indexed set of computations with local dependencies. This can be done by replacing variable dependence vectors with sets of fixed dependence vectors.;The SPD is transformed into an acyclic, labeled, directed graph called the Systolic Directed Graph (SDG). The SDG models the data flow as well as the timing for the execution of the given algorithm on a time-optimal array.;The target architectures are obtained by projecting the SDG along defined directions. If more than one valid projection direction exists, different designs are obtained. The resulting architectures are then evaluated to determine if an improvement in the performance can be achieved by increasing PE fan-out. If so, the methodology provides the corresponding systolic implementation.;By employing a new graph transformation, the SDG is manipulated so that it can be mapped into fixed-size and fixed-depth multi-linear arrays. The latter is a new concept of systolic arrays that is adaptable to changes in the state of technology. It promises a bonded clock skew, higher throughput and better performance than the linear implementation."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Hassan Reda Barada.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: B, page: 8920."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 208-218).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Algorithms</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Systolic array circuits</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017245</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25582068</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920402</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094224</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 BARA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017245</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 BARA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
