<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Influence of an expanded framework of shopping motivations and inclusion of non-store retailers on the choice set formation process</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Attaway, Jill Suzanne.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Business Administration.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xviii, 379 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>398 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Much of the research in marketing involves the study of consumer choice behavior. This study in concerned with the development and testing of a theory of retail choice or patronage. The last several years have witnessed dramatic changes in the retailing industry. In addition to the traditional department, discount, and specialty stores, consumers may increasingly choose from a wide variety of non-store retailers. Thus, any comprehensive study of retail outlet choice behavior should incorporate all of the alternatives available to the consumer.;This research developed a model of patronage which extended previous research with the addition of alternative retail outlets and the explication of important determinant variables. The inclusion of all available retail outlets presents a more comprehensive view of consumers' retail choice decisions and aids researchers in understanding the varied choice behavior of individuals. Consumer shopping motivations, involvement, experience, knowledge, and contextual influences were proposed as primary determinants of retail outlet choice.;A large focus of the dissertation research involved the construction and validation of a consumer shopping motivation scale. Three stages of data collection were conducted to develop a comprehensive, a reliable and valid measure. Motivations were proposed to represent underlying forces that stimulate and compel individuals to interact with the retailing community. The research proposed motivations to greatly influence the number and types of retailers consumers patronize.;In operationalizing retail choice, this dissertation employed a choice set process paradigm. Herein, the research considered store or outlet choice to be a complex decision process. The choice set formation process recognizes consumers have many alternatives to choose from in selecting a retail outlet and is concerned with the cognitive process of alternative evaluation and the derivation of choice sets. The dissertation proposes consumers categorize retail alternatives into four groups.;The results of the dissertation demonstrate the proposed shopping motivation scale to be a reliable and valid indicator of consumers' underlying needs. In addition, the results demonstrate how the various determinants of patronage are related to each other as well as their influence on the size of consumers' choice sets."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Jill Suzanne Attaway.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: A, page: 5640."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 322-336).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Consumer behavior</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Retail trade</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Mail-order business</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017242</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25582047</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920402</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094221</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 ATTA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017242</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 ATTA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
