<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>development of a fetal uterine cell in vitro co-culture system for mammalian embryos</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Wiemer, Klaus Enrique</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Animal Science Dept.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 169 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>182 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"In Experiment I, 125 two-pronuclear murine ova were cultured in either Ham's F-10 plus l5% human serum (HF-10h), on a monolayer of human uterine fibroblasts (HUC) or fetal bovine uterine fibroblasts (FBUC). After 96 hours in culture, 2.4% embryos in HF-10h were viable compared with 45.2% and 61% for embryos on HUC and FBUC, respectively. Results suggest that monolayers were advantageous to medium alone for culturing murine embryos.;Experiment II was conducted to assess the development of 117 bovine embryos in HF-10 (Treatment A), on a monolayer of FBUC (Treatment B) or hormone-pretreated FBUC (Treatment C). Embryo viability assessed at 12, 24, 36, 48, 60 and 72 hours in culture. The viability at 72 hours was 38.5%, 87.2% and 76.9% for Treatments A, B and C, respectively. These results indicate FBUC were superior to that of HF-10 medium alone for culturing bovine embryos.;In Experiment III, 45 equine embryos were cultured in either Ham's F-12 plus 10% FCS (HF-12), on a monolayer of fetal equine uterine fibroblasts (FEUC) or FBUC. Results suggest that early-stage embryos benefited from the FBUC while later-stage embryos benefited when cultured in HF-12 alone.;In Experiment IV, 35 equine embryos were either transferred to recipients or cultured on FBUC for 24 hours prior to transfer to recipients. Pregnancy rate (PR) for fresh embryos was 53.3% and not different from the 42.1% PR for cultured embryos. Results suggest that FBUC could be used as a method for transporting equine embryos.;In Experiment V, 272 human IVF zygotes were cultured for at least 24 hours in either Earle's Balanced Salt solution (EBSS) or on FBUC prior to embryo replacement. Incidence of implantation for embryos cultured in EBSS alone was 17% which was lower than the 35% for co-cultured embryos. Results suggest that culture of human zygotes on FBUC could be considered for improving pregnancy rates from human IVF procedures.;Overall, fetal cells were advantageous over control media in each experiment in this study. Therefore, one should not overlook this system in future embryo research and commercial opportunities."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Klaus Enrique Wiemer.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: B, page: 4960."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 153-168).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Cell culture</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Embryology</topic>
      <topic>Mammals</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Mammals</topic>
      <topic>Embryos</topic>
      <topic>Transplantation</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017307</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25600984</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920407</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094678</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 WIEM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017307</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 WIEM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
