<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>relation of compliance to quality of life in dialysis patients</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Dietz, Linda S.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 117 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>114 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The goal of the current study was to gain knowledge of the impact that dietary compliance has on quality of life for end-stage renal disease patients receiving chronic in-center hemodialysis. As a result of this type of research, health care professionals may better understand the individual and collective influence that various aspects of dietary compliance have on quality of life. This knowledge may be helpful in making future recommendations about the necessity of the dietary regimen.;This study investigated the relation between three commonly employed physiological parameters of dietary compliance (blood urea nitrogen, potassium, and intersession weight gain) and four measures of quality of life (Quality of Life Index, Personal Resource Questionnaire, Karnofsky Activity Scale, and Psychological General Well-Being Schedule). Also, the influence of relevant medical/demographic characteristics (age, age beginning dialysis, years on dialysis, and number of diagnoses) was examined. Subjects in the study included 67 hemodialysis patients from a university hospital dialysis center in a large southern city.;Correlational procedures, multiple regression analyses, and a canonical correlation were employed to investigate the association between dietary compliance, medical/demographic variables and quality of life. In general, the results suggested that the dietary compliance variables have little impact on quality of life. This finding provided further support for the loosening of dietary restrictions. Medical/demographic variables, however, were modestly correlated with one quality of life variable, activity. Knowledge about relevant medical demographic characteristics suggest that high risk patient profiles may be developed for early identification of patients who may benefit from rehabilitation. One problem noted in this study is the difficulty in defining and measuring the construct of quality of life."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Linda S. Dietz.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: B, page: 9800."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 67-83).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Hemodialysis</topic>
      <topic>Patients</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Patient compliance</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017259</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25584777</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920403</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094238</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 DIET</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017259</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 DIET</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
