<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Dangerousness</title>
      <subTitle>risk assessment for violent behavior</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Shaffer, Charles Edward</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1942-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vi, 64 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>71 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Federal court decisions and state and federal legislation have made the legal concept of dangerousness the predominant criterion in involuntary mental health hospital commitments and in determining the least restrictive custody level in prison inmate custody assignments. However, no adequate consensual definition with empirical methods of measurement exists. Megargee's (1976) definition of dangerousness as the probability of violent behavior was used as the basis for an empirical approach to measuring dangerousness in this study. Recent studies in the literature (Monohan, 1984; Klassen &amp; O'Conner, 1988) suggested that discriminant analysis might be an appropriate methodology for model development. Review of the literature suggested a variety of potential predictors to use in a discriminant model. Criterion groups of 50 violent psychiatric hospital patients and 50 violent prison inmates were identified, with violence defined as assault or overt threats of assault on another person within six months of admission. Comparison groups of 50 nonviolent patients and 50 nonviolent inmates were drawn from subjects hospitalized or imprisoned during the same years as the criterion subjects. Four validation samples of 25 subjects each were also drawn.;Stepwise discriminant analysis of the combined hospital and prison derivation samples yielded a discriminant function containing eight variables which was 75% accurate in classifying the original sample and 73% accurate in classifying the holdout validation sample. The analysis of the hospital sample resulted in a discriminant function containing five variables which was 85% accurate in classifying the original sample and 74% accurate on the validation sample. The analysis of the prison sample resulted in a discriminant model with six variables which was 72% accurate in classifying the original sample and 78% accurate on the validation sample.;It was concluded that the derived population-specific (i.e. hospital or prison) models did constitute legally defensible, empirically valid measures of dangerousness for the populations studied. It was also concluded that stepwise discriminant analysis is an appropriate methodology for deriving risk assessment models of dangerousness. Current plans for replication were discussed."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Charles Edward Shaffer.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: B, page: 1003."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 45-54).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Violence</topic>
      <topic>Forecasting</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Prediction (Psychology)</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017292</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25595245</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920406</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094336</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 SHAF</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017292</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 SHAF</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
