<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Characterization and potential applications of cascade arborols and preparation of metallocyclic palladium(II) and rhodium(III) complexes</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Baker, Gregory Rufus</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1958-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xvii, 180 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>198 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A new class of specifically shaped, highly branched molecules was prepared where the branches emanate from tetrahedral carbons. This class of molecules has been named arborols because of their topological similarity to the ""Leeuwenberg"" model for tropical trees. The arborols were synthesized a layer (or tier) at a time to generate cascade spheres, where the number of terminal groups per sphere increases exponentially. Initially, molecules possessing a single cascade sphere attached to simple hydrocarbon chains were prepared to develop synthetic methods and provide proof-of-concept.;Several series of dumbbell shaped, two-directional arborols were prepared, where two cascade spheres are connected via a hydrocarbon backbone of varying length (3 to 13 carbons). The molecules were named (m) -n- (m) arborols, where m denotes the number of terminal hydroxyl moieties, and n denotes the length of the hydrocarbon backbone. Some of these arborols (m = 6: 8 $\leq$ n $\leq$ 13; m = 9: 10 $\leq$ n $\leq$ 13) formed aqueous gels at concentrations of ca. 0.3-10%. Gel formation was determined to be a function of cascade sphere size and chain length.;The generalized cascade sphere synthesis was applied to benzyl halides. A three-directional arborol possessing a central benzene core was prepared. The three symmetrically placed spheres formed a triad, which was readily visualized via transmission electron microscopy; their aggregation properties of aqueous solutions were studied by dynamic light scattering. The synthetic procedure was then used to modify commercially available poly(vinylbenzyl chloride) to demonstrate the potential for polymer modification.;Triethyl methanetricarboxylate was utilized as a malonate equivalent to permit the preparation of a series of bis(thioether) tetradentate ligands, which would be difficult to prepare by other means. Preliminary attempts to prepare the cyclometalated Pd(II) complexes of these new ligands failed.;The synthesis and X-ray crystal structure analysis of a cyclometalated Rh(III) complex of methyl 3-(2-pyridyl)-2-carbomethoxypropanoate revealed the presence of a metal-carbonyl oxygen bond. Variable temperature $\sp{\rm 1}$H NMR spectra indicated the presence of an equilibrium process where an ester carbonyl from one ligand displaces the coordinated ester carbonyl of the other ligand."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Gregory Rufus Baker.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-02, Section: B, page: 7460."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 164-178).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Molecules</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Ligands</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Palladium</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rhodium</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9017244</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">25602899</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920407</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1094749</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 BAKE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9017244</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 BAKE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
