<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Methods of parameter estimation of linear regression models for yield prediction</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Shin, Man Yong</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1953-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Forestry, Wildlife, and Fisheries.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 110 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>120 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Different parameter estimation methods of yield prediction models were investigated using data from the Southwide Loblolly Pine Seed Source Study. This project consisted of three distinct studies. Each study dealt with a possible situation in which other parameter estimation methods rather than the ordinary least squares (OLS) estimator might be used. Three different evaluation statistics were computed to select the ""best"" estimation method for each situation.;The objective of the first study was to select the best estimator for a yield model which had multicollinearity among independent variables. Three types of biased estimators were compared with the ordinary least squares estimator in terms of the predictive ability of the yield model. Ridge estimators were better than the OLS estimator in dealing with multicollinearity problems. Among methods used for selecting the ridge parameter k, Mallows's (1973) C$\sb{\rm k}$ statistic provided the best ridge estimator. On the other hand, principal components and Stein-rule estimators performed poorly compared to the OLS estimator in prediction problems. However, the improvement of yield prediction by ridge estimator was not enough in terms of volume per acre. Thus, the OLS estimator might be preferable due to the simplicity.;The second study dealt with the calibration of yield prediction models to a specific locality and seed source by using Stein-rule estimators. The Stein-rule estimators provided better yield prediction for a specific locality than OLS estimators. For seed sources, however, the Stein-rule estimators offered little gain in prediction compared with the OLS estimators.;In the third study, Kalman filter estimators were used to update yield prediction models by combining OLS estimators from the sample data with some prior information. Two different sources of prior information were applied in this study. Kalman filter estimators performed better in both cases than OLS estimators. Kalman filter estimators also predicted yield better when prior information was obtained from inside the study area than from outside of the study area."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Man Yong Shin.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1576."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 103-109).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Forests and forestry</topic>
      <topic>Statistical methods</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Forests and forestry</topic>
      <topic>Mathematical models</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Parameter estimation</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025340</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186666</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111993</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 SHIN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025340</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 SHIN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
