<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Theoretical and numerical models for heat and mass transport and groundwater flow near salt domes</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Evans, David Griffin</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1956-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geology and Geophysics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 324 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>339 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Groundwater near salt domes is an inherently complex hydrogeologic system because groundwater is subject to large lateral gradients in salinity and temperature. Moreover, groundwater flow is indirectly coupled to salt tectonics because diapirism alters the salinity and thermal conditions as a sedimentary basin evolves. In order to study this complex environment, mathematical and numerical models are developed which explicitly couple heat and dissolved salt transport to groundwater flow, and account for basin subsidence and salt diapirism. The groundwater flow field is described using a mass stream function which does not require the Boussinseq assumption. The numerical model uses a control volume finite difference scheme and resolves nonlinearities iteratively using under-relaxation.;In order to assess the role of thermohaline convection near salt domes, dimensional analysis is used to simplify the transport equations and reduce the number of model parameters to three: the Rayleigh number, the Lewis number, and the buoyancy ratio. The buoyancy ratio is the ratio of salinity to temperature effects on pore water density, and it is the only dimensionless parameter that appears in the groundwater flow equation. The sense of convective circulation near a salt column depends primarily on the value of the buoyancy ratio and the thermal gradient contrast between the salt and overlying sediments. When the thermal gradient contrast is large or the buoyancy ratio is small, convective circulation drives groundwater up along the salt edge. These conditions arise over a limited range of geologic circumstances.;A more comprehensive numerical model is used to investigate groundwater flow when salt dissolves preferentially at the crest of a salt dome during diapirism. Simulation results indicate that groundwater will flow down along the salt flank except when regional background salinities are high. Downward groundwater flow leads to low surface heat flow above the dome, in contrast to calculations based on heat conduction alone. Simulation results further indicate that groundwater flow is only weakly dependent on the hydrologic boundary conditions because groundwater density gradients are large. In the absence of high regional salinities, upward flow of groundwater near salt domes is probably driven by the release of geopressured fluids."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by David Griffin Evans.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1710."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 218-227).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Groundwater flow</topic>
      <topic>Mathematical models</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Salt domes</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Terrestrial heat flow</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Mass transfer</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025302</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186457</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111961</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 EVAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025302</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 EVAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
