<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Use of infrared piezobirefringence for observation of dislocations in semiconductors with cubic symmetry</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Dutta, Aloke Kumar</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xvi, 139 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>156 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The use of infrared piezobirefringence for characterization of defects in cubic semiconductor materials is investigated in this work. Under stress, these normally isotropic materials become birefringent. The stress can result from an applied external load or from defects present in the material. Defects can be generated in the material during its growth and/or processing. As a first step towards defect characterization, the case of diametrically loaded discs of semiconductor materials was simulated. This was done to obtain a better understanding of the simulation algorithm prior to its subsequent use in dislocation characterization. A dark-field plane polariscope was constructed using a He-Ne laser tuned to 1.15 $\mu$m wavelength as the light source. The computer simulated images matched well with the experimentally observed ones on diametrically loaded discs of silicon and gallium arsenide.;The behavior of the stress-optic coefficient C was also investigated, which has been treated as a constant by other investigators in earlier works. In this work, it was found that for (100) oriented Si and GaAs discs under diametrical compression, the stress-optic coefficient C is a strong function of position for a given load, and also changes with the direction of the applied load with respect to the principal crystal axes. However, no such dependence was found for (111) oriented Si and GaAs discs under diametrical compression, as expected from the crystal symmetry. The values of C for (100) oriented Si disc under diametrical compression ranged from 2.0 $\times$ 10$\sp{-12}$ cm$\sp2$/dyne to 3.0 $\times$ 10$\sp{-12}$ cm$\sp2$/dyne and for (100) oriented GaAs disc under diametrical compression ranged from 0.8 $\times$ 10$\sp{-12}$ cm$\sp2$/dyne to 2.6 $\times$ 10$\sp{-12}$ cm$\sp2$/dyne for the cases investigated. The corresponding figures for (111) oriented Si and GaAs discs under diametrical compression are 2.33 $\times$ 10$\sp{-12}$ cm$\sp2$/dyne and 1.94 $\times$ 10$\sp{-12}$ cm$\sp2$/dyne respectively.;Next, an accurate algorithm was developed for the simulation of the images of dislocations as a function of the sample orientation, the orientation of the dislocation line with respect to the principal crystal axes, the orientation of the Burger vector with respect to the dislocation line, and the polarization angle of the incident light. An image data bank has been created for different dislocations. This data bank can be utilized to obtain an accurate characterization of the image of a dislocation by comparing the experimentally obtained images with the simulated ones. In this work, images of the dislocations were observed experimentally and were matched with the simulated images. This approach provides a fast, non-destructive alternative technique for defect characterization in semiconductor materials."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Aloke Kumar Dutta.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1980."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 112-119).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Semiconductors</topic>
      <topic>Defects</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Semiconductors</topic>
      <topic>Testing</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Refraction, Double</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025301</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186452</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111960</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 DUTT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025301</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 DUTT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
