<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Isolation and characterization of a Rhodobacter capsulatus bioB mutant using a novel method to screen for strains unable to synthesize heme</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Cardin, Rhonda Diane</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1961-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Microbiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 150 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>161 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The common tetrapyrrole pathway of the photosynthetic bacterium, Rhodobacter capsulatus, ultimately leads to the synthesis of bacteriochlorophyll, heme, vitamin B-12, and siroheme. Molecular analysis of tetrapyrrole biosynthesis has been limited due to a lack of mutants. This study describes the isolation and characterization of a biotin-requiring mutant of R. capsulatus unable to synthesize heme. Growth conditions were established to allow selection and characterization of heme-deficient strains of R. capsulatus. A screening method was developed to isolate strains of R. capsulatus unable to synthesize heme. Tn5 derivatives of a bchB strain that exhibited an altered ability to synthesize the fluorescent porphyrin Mg-2,4-divinyl pheoporphyrin $a\sb5$ monomethyl ester were scored for hemin-dependence. One nonfluorescent, hemin-requiring mutant, strain AJB544, was isolated. This mutant could not grow on aminolevulinate or porphobilinogen whereas protoporphyrin and hemin supported growth. AJB544 was found to be a bio mutant, and it was shown that hemin could partially replace the requirement for biotin. Thin-layer chromatography and fluorimetric analysis revealed that AJB544 accumulated coproporphyrin and protoporphyrin when grown in minimal medium containing hemin or 2.5 nM biotin. Coproporphyrin was the major porphyrin that accumulated when AJB544 was grown in minimal medium containing hemin. Porphyrin formation by cell-free extracts of AJB544 and AJB478 demonstrated that AJB544 could form normal levels of protoporphyrin from protoporphyrinogen but not from aminolevulinate or porphobilinogen. Addition of biotin to extracts of AJB544 resulted in a 2.0 to 3.8-fold increase in protoporphyrin formation from aminolevulinate or prophobilinogen. Extracts of AJB544 grown in minimal medium containing biotin demonstrated an increase in protoporphyrin formation from aminolevulinate or porphobilinogen. These data suggest that biotin is required for the conversion of coproporphyrinogen to protoporphyrinogen.;Southern blot analysis demonstrated that strain AJB544 contained a single Tn5 insertion. AJB544 was characterized as a bioB mutant by crossfeeding studies and thin-layer chromatography. The bioB gene was cloned from R. capsulatus by screening a pLAFRI library of R. capsulatus DNA and localized to a 2.85 kb EcoRI-PstI fragment. Introduction of the bioB gene into AJB544 restored the fluorescent phenotype."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Rhonda Diane Cardin.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1633."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 124-149).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Photosynthetic bacteria</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Heme</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025294</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186410</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111954</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930 1989 CARD</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025294</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930 1989 CARD</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
