<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Behavior of the American alligator in a Louisiana freshwater marsh</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Rootes, William Lee</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1949-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Forestry, Wildlife, and Fisheries.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 107 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>121 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Stomachs from 706 alligators (Alligator mississippiensis) harvested from a southern Louisiana fresh marsh in 1987 and 1988 were examined for web tags from smaller marked alligators. Alligators $$2.73 m TL) were significantly more cannibalistic than smaller alligators (P $&lt;$ 0.0001). Males and females were cannibalized in the same proportion they occurred in the population. Cannibalism mortality appeared to be distributed proportionately among all cohorts in the 0.35-2.12 m TL size classes resulting in a relatively uniform reduction across the group. Cannibalism was found to be an important population regulating mechanism, accounting for an estimated 50.2% of total hatchling mortality and 70.1% of total mortality in age 11 months and older alligators.;Male growth rates in both a palustrine marsh (Lacassine National Wildlife Refuge) and estuarine marsh (Rockefeller Refuge) marsh types were greater than female rates (P $&lt;$ 0.0001). Growth rates and weight-length ratios of alligators in estuarine marsh were greater than those of alligators in palustrine marsh (P $&lt;$ 0.0001). Age specific fecundity and survivorship rates of alligators in the palustrine marsh were less than alligators in the estuarine marsh.;The home range size and activity pattern of adult female alligators of different reproductive status were compared among seasons of the year. Home range size (P = 0.54) and minimum average daily movement rates (P = 0.85) did not differ between nesting and non-nesting radio-collared females during the summer nesting season. No difference was found between females with and without broods in the two variables during the fall brooding season. Adult radio-collared female alligators ranged over larger areas and had greater daily average daily movement rates during the spring breeding season than during any other season of the year (P $&lt;$ 0.01). Annual home range size of the 15 adult female alligators monitored during the study was 36.2 $\pm$ 42.6 (SD) ha."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by William Lee Rootes.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1576."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>American alligator</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025334</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186624</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111988</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 ROOT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025334</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 ROOT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
