<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>evolution of IgG and IgM antibodies to antigens of Mycobacterium leprae in experimentally inoculated armadillos</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Vadiee, Abdul Reza</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1959-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Microbiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 102 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>113 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The nine-banded armadillo (Dasypus novencinctus linn.) is highly susceptible to infection with M. leprae and has become an important animal model in the study of leprosy. In an attempt to define the major immunogens of M. leprae and the isotypic antibody response to these molecules during infection, the IgG and IgM antibody responses of experimentally-infected armadillos to the sonicated M. leprae, supernatant fraction of sonicated M. leprae, lipoarabinomannan derived from M. tuberculosis, and phenolic glycoliopid-I was analyzed using immunoblot and ELISA. Antibodies to the specific epitope (defined by monoclonal antibody IIIE9) on the 65-kDa protein of M. leprae were analyzed using a competitive antibody binding assay. Our results showed that protein antigens of M. leprae elicited a predominant IgG antibody response, whereas, carbohydrate antigens of M. leprae, including liporarbinomannan, induced an IgM response. Phenolic glycolipid-I elicited both IgG and IgM antibody responses. Some animals produced and maintained a strong IgG antibody response to phenolic glycolipid-I which correlated with their ability to delay dissemination of the infection and with their ability to survive infection for longer periods of time. Antibodies to an M. leprae specific epitope on the 65-kDa protein in crude cell wall extracts but not to the recombinant 65-kDa protein were detected during the later stage of infection in both armadillos and leprosy patients. The lack of concordance between CABA's developed with the crude native antigen and those developed with the purified recombinant 65-kDa protein is suggestive of false-positive results, possibly induced by steric hindrance, being associated with CABA which incorporate crude cell wall extracts as antigen source. Therefore, the IIIE9 epitope of M. leprae does not appear to be immunogenic in the armadillo or the leprosy patient.;It was shown that antibody profiles to various M. leprae antigens proved useful in monitoring the course and outcome of infection in armadillos as well as establishing baseline information on the humoral immune response in armadillos during the course of an untreated infection with M. leprae."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by  Abdul Reza Vadiee.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-07, Section: B, page: 3246."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Mycobacterium leprae</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Leprosy</topic>
      <topic>Immunological aspects</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Leprosy</topic>
      <topic>Animal models</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025350</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186732</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1112002</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 VADI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025350</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 VADI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
