<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>total Lagrangian finite element analysis for metal forming with application to metal extrusion</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Foroozesh, Mehrdad</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1962-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Civil Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 282 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>292 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A detailed formulation for finite element analysis of metal forming problems is carried out in this work. It incorporates every aspect of the analysis, including the iterative solution procedures for geometric and material non-linearities, implementation of the material model, and formulation of curved contact boundaries. The finite element formulation is based on a Total Lagrangian approach which by-passes the use of the Jaumann stress rate tensor commonly used in the Updated Lagrangian formulation. The yield model used is of the von Mises type with both kinematic and isotropic hardening and is formulated in the Eulerian space. This model is then transformed to the Lagrangian reference frame. In the evaluation of stresses, yielding is first detected through the use of an elastic-predictor stress; subsequently upon detection of yielding, the consistency condition is used to evaluate the actual stress and plastic strain tensors. This method is used in conjunction with subincrementation of the strain increment tensor. The curved kinematic boundaries are modeled using the Hermite parametric formulation although other formulations such as $\beta$-splines and Besier parametric curves may also be used with slight modifications. The above mentioned formulations are incorporated into the finite element program, UNIFES (UNIfied Finite Element Solver), which is developed by the author. This program may be used for analysis of 2-D and 3-D problems. A complete listing of this program along with the details of the formulations and a users guide is provided in this work.;Applicability of the above formulations in solving metal extrusion problems is examined through several finite element analyses which are performed by using the UNIFES program. It is shown how the distance between the nodes on the die interface can lead to fluctuations in the extrusion pressure, and how the amplitude of these fluctuations may be reduced by mesh refinement, using multiple types of elements. The effect of changes in the die angle as well as changes in the reduction ratio, on the extrusion pressure is also investigated. A detailed account of the solution procedures is also provided."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Mehrdad Foroozesh.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1961."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 114-120).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Finite element method</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Lagrange equations</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Deformations (Mechanics)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Metals</topic>
      <topic>Extrusion</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025304</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186468</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111963</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 FORO</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025304</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 FORO</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
