<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Pro bono publico</title>
      <subTitle>New Orleans politics and municipal reform in the Progressive Era, 1912-1926</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Fitzmorris, Terrence Walter</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1950-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of History.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>2 v. (ii, 691 leaves) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>696 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Social prejudice and moral consideration did not form the basis of city politics and municipal reform in New Orleans during the Progressive Era. The Regular Democratic Organization, the so-called political machine and the civic reformers of New Orleans were more concerned with issues of expanding and centralized municipal authority, regulation of private and public corporations, completion and expansion of public services, ""living wages"" and decent working conditions for organized labor, equitable taxation and assessment rates for property holders, and city planning and development. Admittedly, the principal leadership of the municipal reform movement came from the ""upper crust"" of New Orleans society and its beliefs had a profound influence on the content of the municipal reform movement. It would be incorrect to assume that social prejudice, class distinctions, and moral considerations formed the basis of city politics. Though the ""Regular Democrats"" had supporters among the lower working classes of New Orleans, RDO contained men of all social classes, economic classifications, educational achievements, and political persuasion.;The Regular Democratic Organization, too, was dedicated to municipal reform. As a rule, the RDO did not fear or object centralized municipal authority and, broadly speaking, its efforts championed home rule and preserved democratic institutions. At times, however, the commitment of the RDO to democratic institutions stymied efforts to establish an efficient, centralized municipal government. The civic reformers, on the other hand, advocated centralized municipal government only if they could control it. By and large, the social and commercial elite opposed public regulation of business and commerce, accusing the Regulars of ""politicizing"" private and public affairs.;Unwilling to accept their declining political influence, the civic reformers demanded the restructuring of the municipal government and the realignment of political power in New Orleans. They demonstrated for the commission council form of government and other political reforms. They achieved only modest success, but managed to influence the structure and content of municipal affairs. And, contrary to conventional understanding, the civic reformers did nor desert politics with every electoral defeat. Rather, they organized and politicked through the numerous civic and commercial organizations they controlled, compelling the RDO to temporize its attempts to centralize authority and realign political power in New Orleans."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Terrence Walter Fitzmorris.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: A, page: 1361."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 674-690).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Political parties</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
      <geographic>New Orleans</geographic>
      <topic>History</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Progressivism (United States politics)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <geographic>New Orleans (La.)</geographic>
      <topic>Politics and government</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025303</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186460</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111962</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 FITZ</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025303</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 FITZ</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
