<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Phosphorus sorption characteristics of acid sulfate soils of Thailand</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Krairapanond, Asdaporn</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1961-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Marine Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 127 leaves, [1] : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>137 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The study of P-sorption by soils has practical interest but little is known on the P-sorption characteristics of acid sulfate soils of Thailand, particularly under reduced soil conditions. The effects of pH, redox potential, and various forms of Fe, Al, and Mn on P-sorption of the actual acid sulfate soils (Sulfic Tropaquept) and the para-acid sulfate soil (Typic Tropaquept) were studied in laboratory microcosms. Soil suspensions with a soil to 0.01 M CaCl$\sb2$ solution ratio of 1:7 were incubated under various pH and redox potential conditions. After the incubation period, the soil suspensions were equilibrated with KH$\sb2$PO$\sb4$ ranging from 0 to 500 mg P kg$\sp{-1}$ soil. Some sets of soil suspensions were extracted by 1 N NH$\sb4$OAc (pH 4.0) and sodium-citrate dithionite solution (20%), intended to remove Fe, Al, and probably Mn in the forms of exchangeable and free oxides, before P addition. Three sorption equations were used to describe the P-sorption data.;The classical Langmuir equation provided the best fit of the P-sorption data. More native insoluble P was released under reduced than oxidized conditions. Para-acid sulfate soil released more native insoluble P than did actual acid sulfate soils under both conditions. Para-acid sulfate soil also sorbed less added P than did actual acid sulfate soils. The P-sorption of both actual and para-acid sulfate soils was significantly affected by pH, redox potential, the extracted treatment before P addition, and their interactions. The P-sorption increased significantly with increasing pH and decreasing redox potential. Treating soils with NH$\sb4$OAc and sodium-citrate dithionite solutions reduced P-sorption, and decreased the differences in P-sorption due to the effects of pH and redox potential. The treatments did not remove the difference in P-sorption between the actual and para-acid sulfate soils. Closely significant correlation between P-sorption parameters and iron-oxides indicated the primary role of iron-oxides in P-sorption of the acid sulfate soils of Thailand. Aluminum-oxides seemed to play a secondary role in P-sorption of these soils. Manganese also showed a significant effect on P-sorption."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Asdaporn Krairapanond.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1773."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note>Library's c.2 (Middleton Library) is missing Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">a-th---</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Acid sulfate soils</topic>
      <geographic>Thailand</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Soil physical chemistry</topic>
      <geographic>Thailand</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025289</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26180506</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111786</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 KRAI 378.76 L930D 1989 KRAI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025289</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 KRAI 378.76 L930D 1989 KRAI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
