<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Sulfur chemistry of Louisiana tidal marsh soils</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Nawarat Krairapanond</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Marine Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 171 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>185 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The amounts and profile distribution of various sulfur forms in Louisiana coastal marshes were investigated to understand sulfur cycling as related to the origin and type of tidal wetland marshes. Sampling was conducted quarterly from a Panicum hemitomon freshwater marsh, a Spartina patens brackish marsh, and a Spartina alterniflora salt marsh in Barataria Basin, Louisiana. Soil samples were fractionated into acid-volatile sulfides (AVS), elemental sulfur, HCl-soluble sulfur, pyrite sulfur, ester-sulfate sulfur, carbon-bonded sulfur, and total sulfur.;Seasonal changes showed a greater effect on the distribution of S fractions in brackish and salt marsh than in the freshwater marsh. Season appeared to have a pronounced effect on the distribution of acid-volatile sulfides, elemental sulfur, and pyrite sulfur. The profile distribution of acid-volatile sulfides and elemental sulfur in all marshes was similar. These sulfur forms showed the greatest abundance in the oxidized zone ($&lt;$20 cm) during spring, summer, and fall. Marsh soil oxidation processes occurring during the plant growing season and a falling water level over the marsh surface resulted in a low pyrite sulfur concentration in the surface. The maximum concentration of pyrite sulfur was observed below 20 cm in all marsh types and its concentration was relatively high during winter. The presence of HCl-soluble sulfur was contributed largely from pore water sulfate, which was greater in salt marsh than in brackish and freshwater marshes, respectively. Organic sulfur, in the forms of ester-sulfate sulfur and carbon-bonded sulfur, was the major contributor to the total sulfur pool in all marsh types. Carbon-bonded sulfur was generally 2 to 3 times more abundant than ester-sulfate sulfur with less seasonal variation. Sulfur concentration (volume basis) and sulfur accumulation rates increased from freshwater marsh to salt marsh. Reduced sulfur species removed by marsh accretion or sedimentation process are likely significant in marsh energy flow. Plant activity, tidal fluctuation, and distance along a salinity gradient from the Louisiana coast seemed to have a strong influence on the distribution of sulfur."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Nawarat Krairapanond.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1718."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Sulfur cycle</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Soils</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
      <topic>Sulphur content</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Salt marshes</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025327</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26180442</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111782</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 NAWA 378.76 L930D 1989 NAWA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025327</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 NAWA 378.76 L930D 1989 NAWA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
