<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Geometric modeling and recognition of elongated regions in images</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Lipari, Charles A. (Charles Anthony)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1954-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 124 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>137 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The goal of this research is the recovery of elongated shapes from patterns of local features extracted from images. A generic geometric model-based approach is developed based on general concepts of 2-d form and structure. This is an intermediate-level analysis that is computed from groupings and decompositions of related low-level features.;Axial representations are used to describe the shapes of image objects having the property of elongatedness. Curve-fitting is shown to compute axial sequences of the points in an elongated cluster. Script-clustering is performed about a parametric smooth curve to extract elongated partitions of the data incorporating constraints of point connectivity, curve alignment, and strip boundedness. A thresholded version of the Gabriel Graph (GG) is shown to offer most of the information needed from the Minimum Spanning Tree (MST) and Delauney Triangulation (DT), while being easily computable from finite neighborhood operations. An iterative curve-fitting method, that is placed in the general framework of Random Sample Consensus (RANSAC) model-fitting, is used to extract maximal partitions. The method is developed for general parametric curve-fitting over discrete point patterns.;A complete structural analysis is presented for the recovery of elongated regions from multispectral classification. A region analysis is shown to be superior to an edge-based analysis in the early stages of recognition. First, the curve-fitting method is used to recover the linear components of complex object regions. The rough locations to start and end a region delineation are then detected by decomposing extracted linear shape clusters with a circular operator.;Experimental results are shown for a variety of images, with the main result being an analysis of a high-resolution aerial image of a suburban road network. Analyses of printed circuit board patterns and a LANDSAT river image are also given. The generality of the curve-fitting approach is shown by these results and by its possible applications to other described image analysis problems."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Charles A. Lipari.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1988."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 111-115).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Computer vision</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Image processing</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Pattern recognition systems</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025318</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26180479</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111784</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 LIPA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025318</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 LIPA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
