<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>study of model Hamiltonians on finite clusters</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Chen, Duan Pin</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1963-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Physics and Astronomy.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1989</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 218 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>227 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"We present two methods to study model Hamiltonians defined on clusters. One is the symmetrization of the Hilbert space basis according to irreducible representations of the symmetry group of the Hamiltonian. The other one adapts the Lanczos diagonalization method directly to the second quantized form of the Hamiltonian studied. By the symmetrization of the basis, one takes advantage of the symmetries of the Hamiltonian, and uses the group theory to find the invariant subspaces of the Hamiltonian in the complete Hilbert space. Then one needs only to work within the invariant subspaces. This method cuts down substantially the size of the matrix representation of the Hamiltonian to be diagonalized. Therefore, one could study relatively larger systems. As a result, all the eigenvectors and eigenvalues are obtained. Consequently, one could calculate thermodynamical quantities and various correlation functions, such as, the spin correlation, the charge correlation, the superconductivity pairing correlation, and the photoemission spectra. One the other hand, the Lanczos method, mentioned here in particular, is a specially developed computer program for the study of the model Hamiltonians. This program uses the key feature of the Lanczos method in diagonalization, allows one to use the second quantized form of the Hamiltonian directly without pregeneration or storing the matrix elements of the Hamiltonian. Two methods could be combined to take the full advantage of the symmetries of the Hamiltonian by input of the symmetrized wavefunction as the starting trial wavefunction in the Lanczos method. Here we illustrate the above two methods by applying to the Hubbard, and extended Hubbard models on a simple cubic cluster, and the lattice Anderson model on the two dimensional square lattice. Other interesting results for different systems are also briefly discussed here."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Duan Pin Chen.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-04, Section: B, page: 1896."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1989.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 94-98).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Solid state physics</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Hamiltonian systems</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Hubbard model</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Anderson model</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9025296</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1989</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">26186426</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">920715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1111956</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1989 CHEN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9025296</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1989 CHEN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
