<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>history of rudimental drumming in America from the Revolutionary War to the present</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Chandler, Eric Alan</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Music.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 106 leaves : music ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>116 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Rudimental drumming gained significance in America during the period of the Revolution. Ever since the late eighteenth-century and through the nineteenth-century, it was used exclusively in the military.;This study traces the migration of drum rudiments and their use in military settings from Great Britain to America. The contributions of the Swiss drummers and the incorporation of their drum music into American rudimental drumming are also examined. The introductory chapter covers related pertinent and prefatory topics such as a definition of rudimental drumming, the duties of the military drummer, non-rudimental types of drumming and a summary of the origin and development of rudimental drumming in Europe.;The second chapter, which constitutes the body of the work, begins with an investigation of military drumming in America beginning in the Revolutionary War era and continuing through the nineteenth-century. This chapter also includes calls, signals, and various rudiments used by the American military drummer as well as an analysis and interpretation of the changes that took place in performance practices and notation.;The third chapter deals with rudimental drumming in the twentieth-century beginning with the bands of John Philip Sousa, comparing techniques and principles of the past to modern marching percussion sections. Changes in rudiments during this century through the efforts of the National Association of Rudimental Drummers and the Percussive Arts Society are also examined.;The study concludes that many of the same rudiments and patterns used in Europe from the fifteenth-century, and in America from the late eighteenth-century, are still used today and have remained unchanged. It has also been concluded that, in comparison to other countries, a large number of drum manuals have been published in America prior to the twentieth-century. A further conclusion acknowledges multiple applications of drum rudiments to other percussion instruments.;Often, the work of any such project is measured in part by its usefulness and contribution. This study will serve as a reference for the rudimental drummer as well as for the historian and could be used by scholars and instructors at all levels."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Eric Alan Chandler.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-09, Section: A, page: 2914."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (D.M.A.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 93-97).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Drum</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Military music</topic>
      <topic>History and criticism</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Drum language</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Signals and signaling</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9104118</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">27211482</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930108</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1160030</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 CHAN 378.76 L930D 1990 CHAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9104118</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 CHAN 378.76 L930D 1990 CHAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
