<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Louisiana barrier island change analysis derived from a geographic information system (GIS) based on sequential aerial photography</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Worthy, Lionel Dorsey</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1947-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Marine Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xxiii, 245 leaves : ill., maps (some col.) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>269 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Surface feature maps were derived from color-infrared aerial photographs for Louisiana's Timbalier Island and Eastern Isles Dernieres. These provided a basis for the implementation of a barrier island Geographic Information System (GIS), a quantitative spatial framework through which specific proximal and temporal interactions could be examined. This system was utilized to observe relationships between changes in island shorelines and surface areas relative to location and extent of island cover categories. It was further employed to test the applicability of the rollover and deltaic barrier cycle models of island dynamics within the context of the Louisiana coastal environment.;Both islands exhibited significant changes, including net losses in island width and surface area. However, results indicated that areas containing marsh or swale experienced significantly lower rates of shoreline erosion than other areas. Combining shoreline change data from this study with that from previous studies indicated a consistent long-term trend of shoreline retreat. Based on these combined observations, Timbalier Island can be expected to persist through the year 2140, and the Eastern Isles Dernieres through 2040.;The rollover model (Godfrey and Godfrey, 1974) describes a shoreward migration of barrier islands in response to increasing sea levels. The deltaic barrier cycle (Penland and Boyd, 1981) describes a sequence of stages associated with the formation, abandonment, and eventual subsidence of major river deltas. Neither Timbalier Island nor the Eastern Isles Dernieres showed significant accretion on their bay sides, precluding any net landward migration, responses fundamentally inconsistent with the rollover model. Timbalier Island underwent a steady westward lateral migration, consistent with the flanking barrier stage of the deltaic barrier cycle. However, the Eastern Isles Dernieres, which represents the transgressive barrier arc stage, exhibited a westward, rather than eastward lateral migration and no net landward migration, responses inconsistent with the deltaic barrier cycle model."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Lionel Dorsey Worthy.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-09, Section: B, page: 4161."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 233-244).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Barrier islands</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Beach erosion</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Coastal ecology</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <geographic>Isles Dernieres (La.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9104181</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">27257549</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930115</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1160519</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 WORT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9104181</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 WORT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
