<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Role duality as represented in the anti-abolitionist speeches of James Shannon</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Poyner, Barry Cole</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1962-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Speech Communication, Theatre, and Comunication Disorders.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vi, 191 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>198 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The dissertation alleges that a speaker may juggle roles in a given rhetorical situation, what may be termed role duality. Role duality refers to a speaker's attempt to effect multiple intentions while fulfilling or partially fulfilling multiple role expectations. A purpose of this dissertation was to speculate further on the nature and function of role duality by analyzing the speeches of James Shannon. Correspondingly, another purpose was to evaluate through rhetorical criticism the pro-slavery, anti-abolitionist speeches of Shannon.;Shannon (1799-1859), an evangelist in the Churches of Christ and an influential educator, delivered two principal speeches in defense of slavery: (1) ""The Philosophy of Slavery as identified with the Philosophy of Human Happiness"" given to the Franklin Society of Bacon College, Harrodsburg, Kentucky, on 27 June 1844 and (2) ""An Address Delivered before the Pro-slavery Convention of the State of Missouri, Held in Lexington, July 13, 1855."".;The dissertation sought to determine (1) whether sufficient evidence existed to ascertain Shannon's intentions in delivering the addresses, (2) whether Shannon's rhetorical choices could be said to constitute role duality, and (3) whether the means Shannon employed furthered his goals. A preponderance of evidence pointed to the conclusion that Shannon harbored multiple intentions, and that while addressing an immediate audience, he also had in mind reaching wealthy southerners who might help Bacon College in Harrodsburg, Kentucky, or Christian University in Canton, Missouri. Less clear was whether a discernible strategy accompanied that effort. Organization seemed to play an insignificant part in reaching contributors, undecided border state auditors, and potential employers. Based on the two speeches, roughly half of Shannon's arguments were reasonably sound, seemingly indicating that Shannon was more concerned with identifying with southerners emotionally than logically convincing all listeners. As represented in the anti-abolitionist speaking of James Shannon, role duality may be seen as a strategy best reserved for desperate moments, for persons with high credibility, and for ceremonial occasions."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Barry Cole Poyner.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-09, Section: A, page: 2926."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 110-118).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <name type="personal">
         <namePart>Shannon, James</namePart>
         <namePart type="date">1799-1859</namePart>
         <role>
            <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
            <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
         </role>
      </name>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rhetorical criticism</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Slavery</topic>
      <geographic>United States</geographic>
      <geographic>Justification</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9104164</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">27255503</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930114</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1160431</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 POYN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9104164</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 POYN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
