<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>incidence of Vibrio species in Louisiana and Maryland oysters (Crassotrea virginica)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Ford, Mary Lynelle</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1943-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Microbiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 115 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>127 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Vibrio species, normal inhabitants of the sea and of shellfish harvested from marine or brackish waters, have been established as the causative agents of serious human infections. An investigation to isolate and identity Vibrio species in oysters collected from eight Louisiana commercial oyster beds was conducted. A selection of 127 vibrio isolates and 46 reference strains, including all known Vibrio species, were subjected to a bacteriological identification scheme of 46 parameters. When the data from the wild strains and the reference strains were analyzed by the numerical taxonomy program, TAXAN Version 3.0, six major phena were evident. Four of the phena contained Vibrio parahaemolyticus, Vibrio vulnificus, Vibrio cholerae, Vibrio mimicus, Vibrio furnissii, and Vibrio Group 521. Genetic relatedness studies showed one of the other phena to be composed of isolates of Vibrio damsela. The remaining major phenon appears to be a previously undescribed Vibrio group.;Because of the severity and rapidity of the disease process in Vibrio vulnificus infections and because of the high mortality rates associated with these infections, a rapid serological method for V. vulnificus identification was developed. Species-specific anti-V. vulnificus flagellar (H) monoclonal antibody coagglutination reagents were sent to laboratories throughout the United States and Canada to be assessed for specificity. One of the user laboratories reported that fifteen Vibrio strains, isolated from Eastern seaboard oysters, agglutinated in these reagents but did not conform to established V. vulnificus bacteriological profiles. These findings suggested that the reagents may not be species-specific. DNA from representative oyster isolates which produced agglutination reactions were examined for thermal denaturation midpoint temperature, mol% G + C content, and DNA-DNA reassociation with DNA from V. vulnificus biogroups 1 and 2. High percentages of relative reassociation with V. vulnificus reference strains indicate that the H coagglutination reagents exhibit a high degree of specificity for V. vulnificus isolates, even those showing aberrant phenotypic characteristics."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Mary Lynelle Ford.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-09, Section: B, page: 4175."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 103-113).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Vibrio infections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Shellfish</topic>
      <topic>Microbiology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Oysters</topic>
      <topic>Contamination</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Diseases</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9104132</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">27211311</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930108</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1159997</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 FORD</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9104132</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 FORD</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
