<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Temporal compression in chirped pulse regenerative amplification ; Picosecond time-resolved Raman study of excited state charge transfers</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <titleInfo type="alternative">
      <title>Picosecond time-resolved Raman study of excited state charge transfers</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Chang, Yong Joon</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1964-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 185 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>199 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The chirped pulse regenerative amplification in Nd:YAG lasers is demonstrated to be able to provide picosecond optical pulses with $\sim$gigawatt peak powers at a repetition rate of 2kHz. By taking advantage of the effects of gain narrowing and gain saturation in the regenerative amplifier, it is shown that the chirped amplified pulse width can be varied systematically from $\sim$12ps to 150ps.;These high peak power pulses were utilized to perform several picosecond time-resolved resonance Raman spectroscopic experiments. One study involves the investigation of excited state electron transfer in symmetric and asymmetric polypyridineruthenium(II) complexes. The competing influences of solvent relaxation, vibrational relaxation and interligand electronic coupling in the metal-to-ligand charge transfer (MLCT) excited state were investigated. The results indicate that vibrational relaxation is the dominant mechanism for electron ligand-localization phenomenon. In addition, the results from dynamic solvent effects study indicate that the solvent motions do not contribute significantly to this localization. The interligand electron transfer during the lifetime of the MLCT excited state was also investigated using a variety of mixed-ligand Ru(II) complexes. The rate of this electron transfer is found to depend greatly on the free energy gap between the two dissimilar ligands.;The excited state proton transfer in a pentaamineruthenium(II) complex was also investigated. The role of ultrafast solvent relaxation in facilitating an accelerated non-equilibrium proton transfer in the MLCT excited state of this complex was studied. No proton transfer was observed to occur with a rate significantly faster than that predicted by diffusion-controlled kinetics. This result indicates that the charge on the heteroatom in the reduced ligand expected to receive the proton is not strong enough to structure the solvent molecules in such a way which facilitates non-equilibrium proton transfer."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Yong Joon Chang.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-09, Section: B, page: 4358."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Raman spectroscopy</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Excited state chemistry</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Laser pulses, Ultrashort</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9104119</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">27211454</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930108</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1160026</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 CHAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9104119</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 CHAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
