<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Sampling and analysis of dynamic headspace volatile compounds from selected protein-rich food matrices</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Matiella, José Ernesto</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1959-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Food Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 92 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>104 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Volatile compounds from two protein-rich foods, crabmeat and eggs, were studied with emphasis on qualitative and quantitative determination of a wide variety of chemical substances including degradation compounds from amino acids, lipids and carboyhdrates as well as compounds derived from the packaging material and the environment. Boiled and pasteurized blue crab (Callinectes sapidus) meat samples were analyzed for volatile flavor components by dynamic headspace sampling, capillary column gas chromatography and mass spectrometry. Fifty-three volatile compounds were identified in crabmeat samples. Levels of volatile compounds in both samples were compared and it was found that the boiled crabmeat contained higher levels of most compounds.;Thirty-eight volatile compounds were identified in scrambled eggs. Selected compounds were quantified. Aldehydes were the most abundant volatile compounds in the egg samples. Volatile styrene monomer increased in scrambled egg samples during a two-week storage of shell eggs in a polystyrene container. Scrambled eggs prepared from a batch of supermarket shell eggs contained 7 times more ethylbenzene and styrene than those prepared from a batch of fresh farm eggs stored in a polystyrene container for two weeks.;A USDA method of dynamic headspace sampling/gas chromatography was evaluated and used to quantify dimethyl sulfides as potential quality markers in liquid whole egg samples. Percent acceptance (0, 20, 40, 60, 80, or 100%) by a panel of five USDA egg inspectors on an experimental batch of samples generally decreased with increasing dimethyl sulfide (DMS) concentration (0 to 540 ng/g) in the samples. In addition, dynamics of DMS and dimethyl disulfide (DMDS) formation during egg spoilage were investigated. It was found that egg decomposition may follow different paths and that DMS concentration may not be indicative of the extent of spoilage in a sample.;This study used a relatively low-artifact analytical approach to generate objective information on flavor quality of selected protein-rich foods. Further investigation into the interaction of the critical volatile compounds with the food matrices as well as packaging and/or the environment may provide critical information to facilitate improvement of the flavor quality of the foods."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by José Ernesto Matiella.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-09, Section: B, page: 4126."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 76-82).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Food</topic>
      <topic>Sensory evaluation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Food preferences</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Eggs</topic>
      <topic>Preservation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Crab meat</topic>
      <topic>Preservation</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9104153</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">27257521</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930115</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1160512</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 MATI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9104153</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 MATI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
