<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Parallelization of goal driven, production systems on hypercube machines in a C environment</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Shrivastava, Rajendra K.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Computer Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 200 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>214 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Production systems are widely used in artificial intelligence to capture the notion of expertise in modeling expert systems. Production systems are computationally intensive programs spending most of the execution time in their MATCH or recognise phase. Efforts have been made by the research in this dissertation to minimize the production system's execution time by optimizing the MATCH phase. Goal oriented deterministic production systems are commonly used for robotics applications and formed the main class of production systems that were studied in this dissertation.;The main motivation for the research was to provide a better MATCH algorithm and use the multiprocessing capabilities of existing parallel computer hardware. The dissertation realizes these goals by transforming a traditional production system's scalar equivalence operations into C arithmetic hashing function to generate an indexing variable for the switch-case construct of the C language. Partitioning of the working memory into homogeneous blocks and distributing production memory over the multiprocessors enhanced the MIMD operation of the production system.;A scheme is formulated and implemented to identify a few key condition elements that may be used as an indexing variable and reduce the number of condition elements used in the MATCH phase. The complete translation from OPS5 code to C and the implementation scheme is presented in this dissertation. Various issues regarding the distribution of the inference engine over the multiprocessor environment and other related synchronization topics for distributed systems are covered in the dissertation. A detailed description of the parallel computer's simulator is also provided in the dissertation.;The dissertation identifies other research topics and problems related to parallelization of production systems, the most significant being the ability to incorporate LEARNING in production systems by using one or all of the idle processors that are waiting for the active processor to complete it's activities."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Rajendra K. Shrivastava.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-09, Section: B, page: 4455."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 145-151).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Expert systems (Computer science)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>C (Computer program language)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Hypercube networks (Computer networks)</topic>
      <topic>Programming</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9104172</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">27255461</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930114</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1160423</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9104172</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
