<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Effects of rock/cutter friction on PDC bit drilling performance</title>
      <subTitle>an experimental and theoretical study</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Kuru, Ergun</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Petroleum Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xxxii, 356 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>373 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A new mechanistic drilling model for PDC bits was derived from the balance of forces acting at the PDC cutter. The model combined the torque and the drilling rate equations, cutter's geometry and rock properties.;A new understanding of frictionally generated heat between rock and PDC cutter is introduced. The numerical analysis revealed that neglecting the heat generated at the cutting surface area results in underestimation of the actual wearflat temperature by 10% to 530%, depending upon bit dull and downhole hydraulics.;The example bit performance comparison made by calculating the MBP curves showed 18% reduction of drilling rate when the new and more rigorous temperature limitation is used.;A new PDC bit wear model was derived and used for bit performance prediction. The model relates bit life with temperature, weight on bit, rotary speed, and cutter geometry. The predictions showed that the effect of the friction dominates bit life, and this effect is greater than the effect of convective cooling.;A new laboratory instrument was constructed and succesfully used to measure friction forces between sliding surface of a PDC cutter and the rock surface. Results showed that friction coefficient did not change considerably within the range of tested rock and fluid types.;The concept of maximum bit performance (MBP) curve was introduced. The curves represented the maximum values of average drilling rates for various pre-assumed footage values.;A new method for preparing a multi-bit drilling program, the dynamic drilling strategy, was developed. The dynamic drilling strategy provided the best combination of PDC bit runs to achieve the minimum drilling cost for a long borehole interval. The method was numerically compared to the conventional drilling optimization and to the field practices. Considerable savings of 25% and 60% were estimated, respectively.;Based on the drilling model, a new method was developed for the insitu measurements of the PDC bit condition and lithology change detection. The technique was verified by comparing the predicted and measured PDC bit wear and by showing the correlation between rapid formation changes and discontinuities in the diagnostic plots."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Ergun Kuru.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-10, Section: B, page: 5008."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Bits (Drilling and boring)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Drag bits (Drilling and boring)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Oil well drilling</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9104146</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">27255526</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930114</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1160434</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9104146</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
