<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Fast parallel algorithms on a class of graph structures with application in relational databases and computer networks</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Radhakrishnan, Sridhar</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1963-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Computer Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 154 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>164 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The quest for efficient parallel algorithms for graph related problems necessitates not only fast computational schemes but also requires insights into their inherent structures that lend themselves to elegant problem solving methods. Towards this objective efficient parallel algorithms on a class of hypergraphs called acyclic hypergraphs and directed hypergraphs are developed in this thesis. Acyclic hypergraphs are precisely chordal graphs and their subclasses, and they have applications in relational databases and computer networks. In this thesis, first, we present efficient parallel algorithms for the following problems on graphs. (1) determining whether a graph is strongly chordal, ptolemaic, or a block graph. If the graph is strongly chordal, determine the strongly perfect vertex elimination ordering. (2) determining the minimal set of edges needed to make an arbitrary graph strongly chordal, ptolemaic, or a block graph. (3) determining the minimum cardinality dominating set, connected dominating set, total dominating set, and the domatic number of a strongly chordal graph.;Secondly, we show that the query implication problem ($Q\sb1\ \to\ Q\sb2$) on two queries, which is to determine whether the data retrieved by query $Q\sb1$ is always a subset of the data retrieved by query $Q\sb2$, is not even in NP and in fact complete in $\Pi\sb2\sp{p}$. We present several 'fine-grain' analyses of the query implication problem and show that the query implication can be solved in polynomial time given chordal queries.;Thirdly, we develop efficient parallel algorithms for manipulating directed hypergraphs H such as finding a directed path in H, closure of H, and minimum equivalent hypergraph of H. We show that finding a directed path in a directed hypergraph is inherently sequential. For directed hypergraphs with fixed degree and diameter we present NC algorithms for manipulations. Directed hypergraphs are representation schemes for functional dependencies in relational databases.;Finally, we also present an efficient parallel algorithm for multi-dimensional range search. We show that a set of points in a rectangular parallelepiped can be obtained in O(logn) time with only 2.log$\sp2 n$ $-$ 10.logn + 14 processors on a EREW-PRAM. A nontrivial implementation technique on the hypercube parallel architecture is also presented. Our method can be easily generalized to the case of d-dimensional range search."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Sridhar Radhakrishnan.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: B, page: 5979."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 142-153).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Algorithms</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Programming (Mathematics)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Computer programming</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Graph theory</topic>
      <topic>Data processing</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112265</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28447205</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198702</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 RADH</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112265</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 RADH</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
