<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Using the domestic chicken egg for culturing preimplantation mammalian embryos</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Blakewood, Eldred Griffin</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Animal Science Dept.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 145 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>156 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A novel embryo culture system has been developed using 96-hour chick embryos. One to four mammalian embryos can be injected into the chick embryo amnion (CEA) and allowed to develop for 72 to 96 hours. Pronuclear-stage mouse embryos from two different strains were cultured in the CEA or in Whitten's medium. There were more expanded blastocysts from one strain of embryos when cultured in the CEA. More hatched blastocysts resulted from embryos of both strains when cultured in the CEA.;Two to eight-cell goat embryos cultured in the CEA for 72 hours or on cell monolayers reached to blastocyst stage at higher rates than when cultured with trophoblastic vesicles or in medium alone. When culture in the CEA was extended to 96 hours, more blastocyst were obtained than when embryos were co-cultured on monolayers for 96 hours or in medium alone. More expanded blastocysts were observed following the culture of precompaction stage bovine morulae in the CEA than when embryos were cultured on monolayers or cultured in medium alone. Culture of bovine morulae on monolayers or in the CEA prior to freezing improved post-thaw viability when compared with culture in medium alone.;When in vitro fertilization (IVF)-derived bovine embryos were cultured sequentially in two or three CEA, development was not improved over culture with cumulus cells and unacceptable loss of embryos occurred. The culture of IVF-derived embryos in the chick embryos during the first 48 hours of development resulted in less four to six-cell embryos than culture with cumulus cells, however, culture of later-stage IVF-derived embryos in the CEA appears to be as effective as cumulus cell co-culture.;Extracted chick amniotic fluids (CAF) were used to supplement the culture medium for mouse and cow embryos. Two-cell mouse embryos developed at similar rates when cultured in CAF or fetal bovine serum (FBS) supplemented medium, however, embryos placed in the CEA cleaved at higher rates. The use of CAF as a supplement in in vitro maturation and culture medium for bovine IVF procedures appears to be as effective as supplementation with FBS."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Eldred Griffin Blakewood.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: B, page: 5652."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 131-143).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Fertilization in vitro</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Reproductive technology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Embryology, Experimental</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112219</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28444132</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930713</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198671</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 BLAK</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112219</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 BLAK</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
