<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Wood specific gravity gradients in tropical trees</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Wiemann, Michael Carl</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1946</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Botany.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 65 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>73 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Pith to bark wood specific gravity (SG) trends were measured in tropical trees and compared with trends found in temperate trees. Extraordinary increases were found across the stems of some tropical wet forest colonizing species, with most tropical species showing at least moderate increases. In contrast, temperate species showed little change, and decreases were almost as common as increases.;In Chapter One (published in Wood Fiber Sci. 20(3):344-349), three colonizing species in tropical wet forest were found to produce low SG wood when small and to linearly increase SG with diameter growth. Trends in small trees were similar to those in the inner portions of large trees. Increases were $&gt;$200% in the largest trees, with no apparent maximum SG.;Chapter Two (Forest Sci. 35(1):197-210) reports on an additional 20 tropical wet forest species and 17 temperate species. The greatest increase in any temperate species was 40% from pith to bark. In contrast, the greatest increase in tropical species was 270%; the average was 60%. The largest gains were found in colonizers.;Intermediate results were found in tropical dry and montane rain forests, and are reported in the third chapter (Amer. Jour. Botany 76(6): 924-928). For dry forest, the largest increases (60%) were in species also found in wet forest.;Chapter Four (unpublished) reports on mechanical properties of wood from four colonizers. Static bending showed strong correlations between SG and moduli of rupture and elasticity. Microscopic examination indicates that greater proportion of fibers and thicker cell walls account for increased SG.;The overall conclusions to be drawn from this study are that some light-demanding tree species of highly competitive tropical environments allocate resources toward production of low SG, weak wood and rapid height growth when young. With age, these species gradually shift resources toward production of stronger, stiffer wood with more fibers and thicker cell walls. Shade tolerant species and species from less competitive environments show little change. Thus biomass allocation toward the competing goals of height growth and stem strength may be related to species light requirements and degree of competition."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Michael Carl Wiemann.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-01, Section: B, page: 2400."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rain forest ecology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Trees</topic>
      <geographic>Tropics</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Trees</topic>
      <topic>Growth</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Wood Density</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112272</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28451577</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198806</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 WIEM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112272</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 WIEM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
