<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Crustal extension in the southern Snake Range and vicinity, Nevada-Utah</title>
      <subTitle>an integrated geological and geophysical study</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Alam, A. H. M. Shah.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geology and Geophysics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 126 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>138 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study of late Cenozoic crustal extension in the southern Snake Range metamorphic core complex, the southern Snack and the Hamlin Valleys utilizes industry-acquired seismic data, two petroleum exploration boreholes, gravity data and surface geology of the adjacent ranges. Isotopic age determinations from outcropping igneous rocks were used to date the structural and tectonic events.;The dominant structural elements of the southern Snake and the Hamlin Valleys are relatively young ($&lt;$17 Ma), and are north-south striking, planar normal faults and associated half-grabens. The valleys are separated by an east-west striking accommodation zone and evolved independently by temporal and spatial interference and superposition of half-grabens. Progressive thickening of basin-fill sequences towards the bounding normal faults within each half-graben suggest semi-continuous slip along the bounding faults; interruptions are represented by angular unconformities which define three seismic sequences above the volcanic unit. K-Ar age determinations of 34 and 26 Ma from volcanic rocks in the Needles Range are correlated with the bottom and top of the volcanic unit; this volcanism was followed by inception of basin formation recorded by the oldest valley-fill sequence. The geometry of the oldest valley-fill sequence indicates that it continued to the west but is now eroded as the Snake Range core complex was uplifted. The intermediate valley-fill sequence records a major stage of tectonism synchronous with displacement along the Snake Range Decollement in the southern Snake Range between 17-18 Ma. Deposition of the youngest valley-fill sequence began at 10 Ma synchronously with a 45$\sp\circ$ change in the regional extension direction.;A late-stage (Late Cenozoic) uplift was recognized in the south-east corner of the Snake Range core complex as a top lap in the seismic data and as a previously recognized unconformity in the outcrop separating angular, older Tertiary conglomerates from flat-lying younger conglomerates on top. Late-stage, local uplifts, as results of disruption of a previously bent elastic plate by normal faults and of differential deformation of various components of a heterogeneous crust in response to bending stress, superpose broad, regional uplifts and explain the total uplift in the Snake Range metamorphic core complex."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by A. H. M. Shah Alam.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: B, page: 5778."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 107-120).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Formations (Geology)</topic>
      <geographic>Nevada</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Formations (Geology)</topic>
      <geographic>Utah</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <geographic>Earth</geographic>
      <topic>Crust</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112214</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28443526</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930713</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198649</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 ALAM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112214</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 ALAM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
