<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Popular participation and farming systems research and extension</title>
      <subTitle>examining the Central Visayas Regional Project 1 in Bohol, Philippines</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Hubchen, Jonathan Manning</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1961-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Vocational Education.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 124 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>134 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The Central Visayas Regional Project 1 (CVRP) in the Philippines uses a Farming Systems Research and Extension (FSR&amp;E) approach which addresses the interrelated components facing the rural household system. A major principle of FSR&amp;E is local participation. This study was conducted to measure the level of popular participation in a CVRP ""working area"".;The study measured local performance and importance of activities relating to the planning, execution, and evaluation of CVRP projects as perceived by beneficiaries. It determined which of the participation activities had a higher score for perceived importance than for perceived performance. Then it determined the relationship between various program variables and the participants' perceived performance of those activities.;The CVRP showed progress in achieving physical targets and responding to its clientele's concerns. However, the clients' continued dependence on the CVRP remained a problem. FSR&amp;E should be applicable to on-site conditions. Popular participation is stressed because the clientele understand the environment for which innovations are designed. Their participation also empowers them toward self determination.;The author designed a spoken interview survey to measure local participation in CVRP activities. Respondents first gave information regarding their participation in the CVRP. They then rated local performance and importance of twenty-three participation activities using a 0-4 scale.;The author compiled statistics for the 331 interviews. All of the activities had importance scores that were statistically higher than those for perceived performance. Five had importance scores which were defined as substantively higher because they exceeded the performance scores by at least one half point. These were led by the activities entitled ""Organizing Trips"" and ""Looking for Outside Resources"".;Length of participation had a small relationship (r value) with Looking for Outside Resources. Performance scores for upland farming activities and organizations were generally higher relative to their counterparts in nearshore fishery areas. Leaders showed significant differences in perceived performance in ""Experimentation"", ""Enforcing Laws"" and ""Organizing Trips"".;The author advocated measures to increase local contributions in obtaining resources and adapting to local conditions. He suggested giving particular attention to nearshore activities and increasing local contribution to training sessions."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Jonathan Manning Hubchen.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: A, page: 3997."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 93-96).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rural development</topic>
      <geographic>Philippines</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Watershed management</topic>
      <geographic>Philippines</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Farm management</topic>
      <geographic>Philippines</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112238</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28447689</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198727</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 HUBC</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112238</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 HUBC</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
