<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Variability of practice and the contextual interference effect in motor skill acquisition</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Hall, Kellie Green</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1955-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Kinesiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 155 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>170 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The relationship between variability of practice and contextual interference was investigated in this study. The hypothesis proposed here was that these two effects are compatible, in that each addresses different learning situations. That is, the contextual interference effect relates only to situations where skill variations are controlled by different generalized motor programs, while practice variability relates only to situations where skill variations are parameter modifications of the same generalized motor program (Magill &amp; Hall, in press).;To test this compatibility hypothesis, two experiments were reported that were based on Wulf and Schmidt (1988). Blocked and random practice schedules were added to their design, resulting in a 2 by 2 (same vs different relative timing) experimental design. A variety of retention and transfer tests were used to investigate the specific conditions that favor the demonstration of practice schedule effects. A control group which received no acquisition training, was added in Experiment 2.;Results from both experiments showed the typical contextual interference effect with depressed scores by the random groups during acquisition and superior scores on both transfer and retention tests. Certain characteristics of the transfer and retention tests were found to influence the demonstration of the practice schedule effects. Results supported the hypothesis that the variability of practice prediction and the contextual interference effect are compatible. In a multiple skill practice setting, practice schedule may or may not influence learning, depending on the characteristics of the skills being learned. If skill variations are from different classes of movements, then learning benefits due to high interference practice schedules will occur. However, if the skill variations are from the same class of movements, practice schedule benefits will not occur."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Kellie Green Hall.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: A, page: 4059."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 90-98).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Motor learning</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Movement education</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Kinesiology</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112236</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28446780</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198693</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 HALL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112236</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 HALL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
