<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Neutral impurity scattering in semiconductors</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Kwong, Kwok Chuen</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1952-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Physics and Astronomy.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 119 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>131 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Neutral impurity scattering is a relatively untouched subject because it is only significant at very low temperatures. With the development of a new class of impurity band conduction devices that operate at cryogenic temperatures, it becomes necessary to describe the scattering in a more realistic fashion.;We have calculated both elastic and inelastic scattering of electrons by substitional As in n-type Si, taking into account the anisotropy of the host band structure. Specifically, in regard to inelastic scattering, we calculated the differential and integrated cross sections for transitions from the ground state to the valley-orbit split states $\Gamma\sb $ and $\Gamma\sb $. Intervalley scattering was also considered but was not found to be substantial within the first Born approximation. The cross sections for excitation of the $\Gamma\sb $ state were found to be negligible. This result is probably due to the cancellation of potentially large terms by symmetry. However, the $\Gamma\sb $ excitation is rather substantial. In contrast to scattering in free space, the incident and outgoing wavevectors are confined to a small cone, while the actual particle velocity can have a broad angular span.;The formal theory of elastic scattering was extended to as required by the anistropy of the conduction band. Potentials for the calculation were obtained by scaling the potentials of the hydrogen atom. We obtained a set of coupled differential equations similar to those in electron-molecule scattering with axial symmetry. Due to the complication of the interplay between the anisotropy and the multivalley nature of the host, we have to neglect inter-valley scattering. It is found that for a specific outgoing direction, incidence along the longitudinal directions of the ellipsoidal valleys gives the maximum rate; whereas the transverse directions have the maximum scattering rates for any fixed incident directions. At low incident energies, the scattering is dominated by the singlet state with our choice of the exchange potentials."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Kwok Chuen Kwong.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: B, page: 5947."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 64-67).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Electrons</topic>
      <topic>Scattering</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Semiconductors</topic>
      <topic>Impurity distribution</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112243</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28448796</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198770</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 KWON</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112243</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 KWON</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
