<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>study of internal auditor perceptions of selected audit activities performed during the design phase of systems development</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Cerullo Margaret Virginia</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1945-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>E.J. Ourso College of Business</namePart>
      <namePart>Department of Accounting</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 297 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>311 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Little evidence exists concerning the criteria which internal auditors consider when selecting activities to perform during systems design. Likewise, knowledge concerning the perceived role(s) of the internal auditor in systems design is limited.;This dissertation examined the perceptions of internal auditors who have assisted in the development of a system and have, therefore, participated in the choosing of activities to perform during systems development. Nine systems design audit activities were selected from the literature to represent the different levels of involvement recommended in the literature. Internal auditors' judgments of the similarity of the nine audit activities were collected in two questionnaires, representing two areas of internal auditor involvement: (1) The Controllability Questionnaire assumed that activities are chosen to provide assurance that adequate EDP application controls are designed into a system. (2) The Auditability Questionnaire assumed that activities are chosen to provide assurance that audit needs are designed into a system. Respondents were approximately equal between the above groups. Internal auditors judged the similarity of each pair of the audit activities and then rated the activities on attributes chosen by the researcher, a priori, as factors influencing these similarity judgements.;The survey results were analyzed using multidimensional scaling (MDS) and canonical correlation techniques. Internal auditors' perceptions of systems design audit activities were modeled in two-dimensional MDS solutions for both groups of respondents. The attributes found to significantly affect the perceptions of systems design audit activities in the auditability MDS solution differed from those in the controllability MDS solution. Both models identified the activities which each respondent group perceived as the most and least appropriate."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Margaret Virginia Cerullo.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: A, page: 4181."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 185-195).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Auditing, Internal</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>System design</topic>
      <topic>Auditing</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112221</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28444035</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930713</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198662</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 CERU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112221</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 CERU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
