<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>comparative study of the effects of Sesbania drummondii on the hepatic cytochrome P-450 monooxygenase systems of chickens and rats</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Banton, Marcy Iva</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1956-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 292 leaves : ill.; 28 cm.</extent>
      <extent>305 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The effect of an extract of Sesbania drummondii on the hepatic cytochrome P-450 monooxygenase system was evaluated in two experimental models, the White Leghorn chicken and the Sprague-Dawley rat. The cytochrome P-450 monooxygenase systems were compared using studies of catalytic activities and two major enzyme components, cytochrome P-450 and NADPH-cytochrome P-450 reductase. Two ""classical"" cytochrome P-450 inducers, phenobarbital and $\beta$-naphthoflavone, were used to probe induction mechanisms.;S. drummondii induced opposite effects on the hepatic cytochrome P-450 component of chickens versus rats. Cytochrome P-450 specific content was increased 2-fold in chickens but decreased 2-fold in rats. Qualitative differences in microsomal proteins were found using SDS-gel electrophoresis. The protein profile of S. drummondii-treated chickens was induced differently from phenobarbital or $\beta$-naphthoflavone. In the rat, the microsomal protein profile was similar to controls but of lower protein band staining intensity. Western blots revealed two S. drummondii-induced microsomal proteins of chickens that cross-reacted with antibody against rat P-450IA1. One of these proteins corresponded to the $\beta$-naphthoflavone-induced chicken protein. The other appeared unique to S. drummondii treatment. Neither of protein was detected by this antibody in the S. drummondii-treated rat.;Sesbania drummondii induced different responses in chicken versus rat cytochrome P-450 catalytic activities. Chickens showed increases of 2-fold in aminopyrine N-demethylase and 4-fold in aldrin epoxidase; no change in ethoxyphenoxazone and benzyloxyphenoxzone O-dealkylases; and a 2-fold decrease in pentoxyphenoxazone O-dealkylase. Similar activities were induced by phenobarbital. In contrast, S. drummondii-treated rats had 2 to 3-fold decreases in all activities, except ethoxyphenoxazone O-dealkylase, which was unchanged.;Species differences were also observed in the effect of S. drummondii on the NADPH-cytochrome P-450 reductase component. S. drummondii-treatment induced a 2-fold increase in NADPH-cytochrome c reductase activity in chickens but no change in treated rats. Use of cumene hydroperoxide indicated that the induced effects on the reductase contribute to aminopyrine but not aldrin metabolism in the chicken, and neither substrate metabolism in the rat.;These findings suggest that Sesbania drummondii can induce changes in hepatic cytochrome P-450 monooxygenase systems and these changes are species-dependent."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Marcy I. Banton.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: B, page: 5757.;Directors: Wayne Flory; Charles Short."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis(Ph.D.) -- Louisiana State University, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography: leaves 225-252.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Cytochrome P-450</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Veterinary toxicology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Poisonous plants</topic>
      <topic>Toxicology</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112217</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">22301873</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LBD</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">900831</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1199070</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 BANT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112217</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 BANT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
