<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Analysis for creep, shrinkage and temperature effects on expansion joint movements in composite prestressed concrete bridges</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Rebello, Keith J. (Keith Joseph)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1959-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Civil Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xv, 299 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>315 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A rigorous and efficient analytical model to predict the long-term deformation behavior of bridges with multiple, precast, pretensioned, prestressed concrete girders supporting cast-in-place-concrete deck slabs, was developed. The analytical procedure uses the finite element method with three-dimensional 20-node isoparametric elements to realistically model bridge geometry. Time dependent effects due to load and temperature history, creep, shrinkage and aging of concrete are included in the analysis. Creep and shrinkage strains are evaluated at different times using the more commonly used procedures, namely, the ACI-209, Bazant-Panula II and CEB-FIP procedures. Temperature strains are calculated from an assumed typical bridge temperature distribution based on the average temperature occurring during any time period. The effect of temperature on creep is also accounted for. Prestressing tendons are modelled as being embedded in concrete and as contributing to girder stiffness. Position continuity in tendon profiles is maintained. Losses in prestress due to steel relaxation and geometry changes are calculated in the analysis. The analytical model is capable of simulating typical construction schedules to predict deformations at any stage during the service life of a bridge.;A parametric study was conducted to quantify the influence of key geometric and material properties of the bridge on the long-term expansion joint movements. Bridge systems representing a wide range of key parameters were analyzed to develop formulas to estimate creep and shrinkage movements with a certain degree of confidence. These formulas formed the basis of a rational procedure for calculating the long-term bridge deck movements. The recommended procedure accounts for the effects of bridge geometry and material properties on joint movements. These effects are ignored in current highway bridge deck joint design methodology. The use of the recommended procedure permits the designer to determine span lengths and the maximum number of continuous spans between expansion joints in bridge decks, if the limit of movement that can be accomodated by the chosen joint sealing system is known.;The analytical model has been coded into a FORTRAN program which can be used to evaluate the long-term behavior of bridges with or without expansion joints, and with different support conditions."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Keith J. Rebello.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: B, page: 6017."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 158-162).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Bridges</topic>
      <topic>Design and construction</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Concrete bridges</topic>
      <topic>Floors</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Concrete bridges</topic>
      <topic>Joints</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Concrete construction</topic>
      <topic>Joints</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Concrete</topic>
      <topic>Creep</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112266</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28447150</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198700</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 REBE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112266</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 REBE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
