<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Spinach carbonic anhydrase</title>
      <subTitle>primary sequence, transport into chloroplasts and expression in escherichia coli</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Fawcett, Timothy W.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1955-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Biochemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 101 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>110 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Carbonic anhydrase (CA) catalyzes the reversible hydration of CO$\sb2$. Plant carbonic anhydrases are structurally distinct from those found in animals. In C$\sb3$ plants, the enzyme is located in chloroplasts.;To date, little structural information on the enzyme from plants has been available. In this study the full-length cDNA for the spinach chloroplast CA was sequenced. The cDNA contained 1,156 base pairs. The open reading frame encoded a protein of 34,569 daltons. Comparison of the N-terminal sequence of this protein with that of other chloroplast precursors indicated that CA is synthesized as a precursor. The transit peptide likely contains about 60 amino acids.;Indirect immunoprecipitation of translation products synthesized using pea poly A RNA indicated that the pea precursor is approximately 36,000 daltons. Incubation of either the pea or spinach precursor with isolated intact chloroplasts resulted in import of the precursor and cleavage to a polypeptide of about 30,000 daltons. Various spinach CAs containing deletions ranging from 34 to 78 amino acids were expressed in E. coli, under the control of the trc promotor. Each of the CAs assembled to yield the enzymatically active hexameric enzyme.;Immunological techniques performed in E. coli expressed spinach CA as well as total plant extracts demonstrated the susceptibility of CA towards proteolysis at the N-terminal end. Furthermore, a cross-reacting protein, which is distinct from the well characterized periplasmic CA, was demonstrated to be present in extracts of Chlamydomonas reinhardti.;Western blotting of CA extracts from leaves, chloroplasts or E. coli expressing CA indicated that CA is susceptible to proteolysis. N-terminal sequencing data obtained by others suggests that the degradation is from the N-terminus. Also, extracts from pea stems and leaves contained a polypeptide which cross-reacted with antibodies raised against spinach CA. Root extracts contained no cross-reacting polypeptides. These results suggest that, like other chloroplast proteins, expression of CA is regulated in a tissue specific manner."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Timothy W. Fawcett.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: B, page: 5844."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 75-87).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Carbonic dioxide</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Spinach</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Botanical chemistry</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112230</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28446561</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198685</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 FAWC</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112230</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 FAWC</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
