<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>effect of olivocochlear bundle transection on cochlear mechanics</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Littman, Thomas A.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1952-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Speech Communication, Theatre and Communication Disorders.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 92 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>102 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A growing body of research suggests that the efferent innervation to the cochlea, the olivocochlear bundle, plays a role in modulating the mechanical function of the cochlea. Some of the more provocative findings supporting an hypothesis of OCB modulation have come from studies which assessed efferent influences on tuning curves and acoustic distortion products, two measures thought to be sensitive indicators of cochlear mechanical function. While the OCB appears to be capable of modifying cochlear mechanics, the functional role attributed to the efferents has been difficult to define. For example, some studies which have transected all or part of the OCB have found changes in cochlear tuning, while others have not. Similarly, investigations which have electrically or acoustically stimulated the OCB have yielded contradictory findings. Particularly little is known about the role of tonic OCB input in cochlear function.;The purpose of this project was to determine the influence of tonic efferent input on cochlear mechanics, by transecting the entire olivocochlear bundle (OCB) in guinea pigs, and observing changes in tuning curves and acoustic distortion products. The olivocochlear bundle was transected by avulsing the inferior vestibular nerve, as it enters the internal auditory canal of the right bulla. Auditory brainstem response (ABR) thresholds, ABR tuning curves, and acoustic distortion products were measured before and after surgery. Successful transection of the OCB was verified histochemically.;Results revealed no consistent changes in tuning curves or in the growth functions of the acoustic distortion products. It was therefore concluded that tonic olivocochlear input is not necessary for normal cochlear mechanical function. It appears that the OCB normally exerts an influence on cochlear mechanics only when activated by sound. Possible roles for the OCB in the forward masking phenomenon were discussed, as well as a putative OCB role in reducing the auditory input to cochlear nucleus and higher centers, to improve central auditory processing."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Thomas A. Littman.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 51-12, Section: B, page: 5795."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 64-74).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Cochlea</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Labyrinth (Ear)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Auditory pathways</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9112247</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28438543</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930712</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198566</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 LITT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9112247</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 LITT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
