<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Rice improvement through tissue culture</title>
      <subTitle>inheritance of somaclonal variation and improvement of somaculture techniques</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Xie, Qingjun</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1953-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Plant Pathology and Crop Physiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xxii, 225 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>248 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The objectives of this research were to study the inheritance of homozygous variation from rice somaculture, to select rice somaclones for increased sheath blight resistance, and to determine the mode of inheritance of the resistance. To accomplish these objectives it was necessary to improve somaculture techniques for rice suspension and protoplast culture especially for the American long-grain cultivars. A method for incorporation of the chemical mutagen, ethyl methane-sulfonate (EMS), into the somaculture system was also developed to increase the frequency of somaclonal variation in tissue culture stable cultivars.;The inheritance of six homozygous variant characteristics from five somaclones was investigated. The white apiculus character was controlled by a single recessive gene. Inheritance of the purple apiculus character was controlled by a single dominant gene. Inheritance of the tall variant character from the mutated semi-dwarf cultivar Lemont was controlled by two complementary dominant genes. Inheritance of the short variant characteristic from the cultivar Labelle was controlled by quantitative genes. The genes responsible for the variant characteristics purple-red hulls and dwarfing in Lemont were not stable in the heterozygous F$\sb2$ populations generated by crossing back to Lemont. The ""disappearance"" of these two characteristics in the segregating generations may be caused by ""gene conversion"" during meiosis. The possibility that mitotic recombination might be a cause of homozygous somaclonal variation was studied. No mitotic recombination was observed from 1,100 T$\sb1$ plants regenerated from F$\sb1$ progeny from crosses among three genetic marker lines.;Two long-grain somaclonal lines resistant to sheath blight were selected from the Labelle cultivar. The resistance of SC86-20001-5 was controlled by a recessive gene. The resistance of SC86-2000l-33 was controlled by two independently inherited recessive genes.;A successful suspension culture system was established for both indica and japonic cultivars. By utilizing these suspension systems, an efficient system was developed for plant regeneration from rice protoplasts of the U.S. long-grain cultivar Labelle and the japonica cultivar Taipei 309.;By incorporating EMS into callus induction medium at the appropriate concentrations, the inhibitory effect of EMS on plant regeneration was minimized and somaclonal variation frequencies were significantly increased."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Qingjun Xie.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1167."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 153-155).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rice</topic>
      <topic>Genetics</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Plant genetic engineering</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rice</topic>
      <topic>Genetic engineering</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123247</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28454409</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198930</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 XIE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123247</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 XIE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
