<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Brugia pahangi</title>
      <subTitle>effects of maternal filariasis on the responses of their progeny to homologous infection</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Bosshardt, Stephen C.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1957-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vi, 217 leaves : ill. ; 28 cm.</extent>
      <extent>224 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The effects of in utero and neonatal exposure to maternal Brugia pahangi infections on the development of homologous infections, immune responses, and pathologic lesions was studied in age-matched progeny of infected and uninfected female jirds. High IgG antibody titers to B. pahangi antigens were present in the sera of progeny from infected mothers. These neonatal titers to homologous antigens were shown to be of maternal origin, and did not alter the cellular responses of uninfected progeny as measured by in vitro antigen-stimulated blastogenesis and in vivo pulmonary granulomatous inflammatory responses to antigen-coated beads. Studies were conducted to measure age-related differences in susceptibility, lymphatic lesion formation, and antibody responses to B. pahangi infection in 2$-$, 6$-$, 10$-$, and 15-week old jirds from uninfected mothers. Significant reductions in quantities of testicular and intralymphatic worms recovered and antibody responses to solbule antigens in jirds infected at 2 weeks of age had no measurable effect on susceptibility or lymphatic lesion severity expressed as the ratio of intralymphatic thrombi formed per intralymphatic worm. Challenge infections in 2- or 4-week old progeny from B. pahangi-infected and uninfected female jirds yielded equivalent adult worm recoveries and microfilaremias. Lymphatic lesion severity expressed as the ratio of intralymphatic thrombi formed per intralymphatic worm recovered was similar in all groups. Offspring infected at either 2 or 4 weeks of age from infected mothers exhibited significantly lower serum IgG antibody titers to B. pahangi antigens compared to infected progeny of uninfected mothers at 5-8 weeks postinfection. Infected offspring from infected mothers displayed significantly fewer antigen-specific splenic plague-forming cells at 5 weeks postinfection than infected control progeny. Qualitative and quantitative reductions in serum antibody reactivity to B. pahangi antigens were also demonstrated by Western immunoblot at 8 weeks postinfection in infected progeny of infected females. These results suggest that a partial immune tolerance to B. pahangi antigens develops in infected offspring of infected female jirds. These modulated antibody responses had no measurable effect on the establishment of adult worms, microfilaremias, lymphatic lesion development, or antigen-specific pulmonary granulomatous inflammatory responses."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Stephen C. Bosshardt.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1216."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis(Ph.D.) -- Louisiana State University, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 177-207).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Elephantiasis</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Filariasis</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123177</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)); 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">23685040</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LBD</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910503</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1199071</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 BOSS</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123177</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 BOSS</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
