<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Soil- and water-based management strategies for revegetation and productivity improvemet of brackish marsh soil</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Sigua, Gilbert C.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Agronomy Dept.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xvi, 265 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>282 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Laboratory, greenhouse, and field experiments were conducted on brackish marsh soil of Hackberry, Louisiana (LA). This study was aimed to obtain detailed information on some soil- and water-based management factors that were applicable to the revegetation and productivity improvement of the area. This area was inundated by brackish-saline water, and is now open water, almost totally void of vegetation.;The deteriorating productivity and continuous loss of vegetation in the study area can be related to the seasonal and temporal biochemical transformations. These transformations were significantly correlated to precipitation and minimum and maximum temperature in the area. Stochastic regression models were established to describe seasonal and temporal behavior of water and soil pH, electrical conductivity, total dissolved solids, and ionic strength in brackish marsh.;The variability of individual soil properties in the study area as indicated by the coefficient of variations differed significantly (p = 0.01). A uniform application of any soil amendments like fertilizer or gypsum in the area that possessed spatially variable soil would result in over application in some parts of the area and under application in others.;Soil drying significantly reduced urease activity in the area and was detrimental to the overall growth and yield of marsh vegetation. There was zero survival in the non-flooded plots except that marsh hay cordgrass had survival rate of 32.8%.;The four species of marsh vegetation: Spartina patens Muhl. (marsh hay cordgrass), Distichlis spicata L. (salt grass), Paspalum vaginatum SW. (joint grass), and Scirpus americanus Pers. (freshwater three-square) responded significantly to N and gypsum (G) applications. Their overall yield response was described as DMY = 2.68 + 1.62N $-$ 0.98N$\sp2$ + 0.37N$\sp3$ $-$ 0.73G + 0.62G$\sp2$. Plots receiving 7 Mg gypsum ha$\sp{-1}$ produced significantly more dry matter yield (DMY) than did the control. This treatment increased the DMY of joint grass (5.04 to 8.08 Mg ha$\sp{-1}$), marsh hay cordgrass (1.90 to 6.91 Mg ha$\sp{-1}$, salt grass (0.97 to 2.79 mg ha$\sp{-1}$), and three-square (1.55 to 2.84 Mg ha$\sp{-1}$) in flooded plots. Significantly higher survival rates of plants were observed in flooded plots treated with gypsum than in the plots without gypsum or flooding."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Gilbert C. Sigua.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1140."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Brackish water plants</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Marsh ecology</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Marsh plants</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Wetland plants</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123240</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28451656</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198811</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 SIGU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123240</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 SIGU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
