<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Historic changes in channel morphology of Mississippi river tributaries</title>
      <subTitle>Southwestern Mississippi</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Yodis, Elaine G.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1959-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geography and Anthropology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 146 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>159 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study assesses the geomorphological changes to the fluvial systems of two rivers in southwestern Mississippi that have been foreshortened. Channel foreshortening in the lower reaches of these rivers is similar to a lowering of base level and causes a steepening of the channel gradient which leads to channel incision, bank erosion and increased sediment load. Analysis of historical and modern data and a comparison with three unmodified rivers in the same physiographic region, provide an estimate of the magnitude and rate that such disturbances are transmitted through the fluvial system.;Degradation and channel instability of the Homochitto River and St. Catherine Creek occurred immediately after foreshortening and proceeded upstream by knickpoint migration. A relationship was found to exist between the rate of knickpoint migration and drainage basin area of the mainstem channels and tributaries. Variations in the rates of channel incision and widening were related to changes in the regional geology. The increased bankfull capacity of the foreshortened channels has reduced the frequency of overbank flooding. The size of point bars along the Homochitto River have nearly doubled due to the introduction of enormous volumes of sediment from channel widening. Short-term channel changes also occurred in response to scour and fill associated with individual flood events.;From these data a five phase model was formulated to illustrate the evolutionary change to the channel system. The meandering phase represents the channel prior to foreshortening. The degradation and aggradation phases indicate the sequential adjustments of the channel after knickpoint formation. The longitudinal profile in the final phase has reached a quasi-equilibrium position, although is located at a lower elevation indicating some degree of nonrecovery. Additionally, the recovery time varied both spatially and temporally within the fluvial systems with the tributary channels lagging behind that of the mainstem."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Elaine G. Yodis.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: A, page: 1036."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 127-138).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-ms</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rivers</topic>
      <geographic>Mississippi</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>River channels</topic>
      <geographic>Mississippi</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>River engineering</topic>
      <geographic>Mississippi</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123248</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28460822</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930716</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1199073</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 YODI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123248</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 YODI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
