<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Diffusivity estimation for counterdiffusing reactants in catalytic solids</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Chang, Chauchyun.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemical Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 311 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>326 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The diffusivities of molecules whose sizes approach the intracrystalline pore sizes of zeolites have been studied at and near conditions prevailing during catalysis, by both desorption and kinetics techniques.;For the desorption approach, a series of unary isothermal desorption experiments (following an almost instantaneous initial temperature rise) were conducted for toluene or benzene with five different zeolites. Diffusion and readsorption are shown to control the process. The intracrystalline diffusivities (D$\sb{\rm e}$) were derived by fitting the desorption curves with four models of varying complexity; only models which take into account readsorption (either at equilibrium or not) can both fit the data adequately and give reasonable estimations of D$\sb{\rm e}$. A nonequilibrium readsorption model is probably superior to an equilibrium readsorption model, because: (1) it can fit both the rising and falling portions of isothermal desorption curves and (2) the D$\sb{\rm e}$'s predicted by such a model are comparable to those reported in the literature by other techniques (chromatographic, adsorptive uptake) under similar conditions. But these D$\sb{\rm e}$'s are still at least three orders of magnitude smaller than those predicted by the Pulse Field Gradient (NMR) technique.;For the kinetics approach, the disproportionation of toluene, a well understood reaction, was studied using the same zeolites at intraparticle-diffusion-limited conditions in order to estimate the product of effectiveness factors and rate constants. The D$\sb{\rm e}$ for toluene in counterdiffusion was estimated by fitting the rate data to generalized effectiveness factor expressions, using literature results for the rate expression. The rate constants obtained in this study are comparable to the second-order intrinsic rate constants for zeolite catalysts obtained from the literature; however, the effective binary D$\sb{\rm e}$'s for toluene computed from this approach are at least two to three orders of magnitude smaller than the D$\sb{\rm e}$'s derived from the desorption curves. This result suggests a reduction of molecular mobility resulting from restricted passage of counterdiffusing reactants in zeolite windows during catalysis."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Chauchyun Chang.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1583."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 211-224).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Diffusion</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Catalysis</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123183</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28444049</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930713</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198664</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 CHAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123183</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 CHAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
