<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>combustion of linear droplet arrays in a co-axial, convective flow</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Tsai, Jeng-Syan</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemical Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 160 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>169 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"As approximations for spray-combustion processes, a series of increasingly sophisticated numerical models has been developed to simulate the combustion of linear droplet arrays in a co-axial, convective flow. Common to all of the models is an embedded grid, developed to increase computational accuracy.;The first and simplest model is potential flow model (for Re $\to$ $\infty$). The flow is assumed to be ideal and infinitely-fast kinetics (flame sheet assumption) represent the combustion. The results show that the instantaneous droplet burning rates are increased as the droplet spacing is increased, and the burning rates of droplets tend asymptotically to smaller values as the number of droplets in the array is increased.;A second model, a Stokes flow model (for Re $&lt;$ 1), is developed by using the Stokes approximation for the flow field. The results show that, owing to the lack of strong convective flow, the temperature and species contours can penetrate deeper into the flow.;The third model extends the analysis to heat transfer for linear arrays of spheres at any Reynolds number, i.e. the model is based on the steady-state Navier-Stokes equations, but no combustion is considered. A more accurate flow pattern around the arrays is obtained and the predicted heat transfer and drag agree well with the experimental data in the literature.;The fourth model introduces combustion into the third model through a finite-rate, one-step chemical reaction approximation. The model predicts a thick flame layer, rather than a flame sheet. For large Reynolds numbers, the results show that the downstream droplets have a higher burning rate than the leading droplets. For small Reynolds numbers, the model predicts behavior similar to that predicted with the potential and Stokes flow models.;Finally, an unsteady-state model, based on the full Navier-Stokes equations, is used to study the variation in burning behavior with time. The reduction in droplet size, velocity, and spacing is included. The results show that even when the droplet spacing is significantly reduced (from 14 to 6 radii) the burning behavior of droplets is not affected."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Jeng-Syan Tsai.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1595."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Combustion engineering</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Incineration</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Thermodynamics</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123245</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28455264</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1199043</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 TSAI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123245</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 TSAI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
