<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Functionality and binding of washed mechanically separated beef in restructured meats</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Koh, Kyung Chul</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1955-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Animal Science Dept.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 212 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>226 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Binding and texture are important attributes of restructured meats which are dependent upon protein properties. Meat was pre-salted with 0, 2.25, 4.5, 6.75, or 9.0% sodium chloride (NaCl) and extracted with buffers (pH 6.0) containing 0, 0.6, 1.2, 1.8, or 2.4 M NaCl to determine total extractable protein (TEP). Increased NaCl level in extraction buffers increased TEP, but NaCl levels of 2.25 and 4.5% in meat interfered with release of solubilized proteins into extraction solutions. Restructured beef roasts of 0, 0.45 or 0.9% NaCl and 0, 0.225 or 0.45% sodium tripolyphosphate (STPP) were manufactured with 10% mechanically separated beef (MSB), washed MSB or minced beef (control) preblended with 0, 4.5 or 9.0% NaCl and 0, 2.25, or 4.5% STPP. Beef roasts containing preblended MSB had similar cooking loss (CL) and tensile strength (TS) compared to the controls, but washing of MSB decreased functionality (CL and TS) in restructured roasts. Addition of NaCl and STPP improved CL, TS and tenderness, but chloride ions were more effective than phosphate ions at equivalent ionic strengths for decreased CL and increased tenderness. Ionic strength of preblended treatments explained 65.4, 44.8 and 45.1% of the variations in CL, TS and tenderness, respectively. The relationships of physicochemical properties of extracted proteins to the functionality of precooked roasts showed trends for relationship between loss of sulfhydryl content and CL, hydrophobicity and TS, and initial sulfhydryl content in meat and tenderness. Precooked roasts containing 10% MSB were lighter and more yellow and had a higher chroma value compared to the controls. Roasts with MSB initially had a similar redness to the controls and remained unchanged during refrigerated storage of 14 days although redness for the controls continuously decreased. Both 9% NaCl and 4.5% STPP additions to preblends independently enhanced initial redness of roasts and provided for increased redness throughout 14 days of storage at 2$\sp\circ$C. A formulation of 10% MSB, 0.45% NaCl and 0.45% STPP is suggested for precooked, low-sodium, low-cost restructured beef roasts which would be marketed through refrigerated display."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Kyung Chul Koh.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1154."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 168-190).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Meat</topic>
      <topic>Quality</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Beef</topic>
      <topic>Quality</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123211</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28448662</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198761</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 KOH</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123211</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 KOH</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
