<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Ecology of Erwinia chrysanthemi, causal agent of bacterial stem and root rot on sweetpotato and etiology of souring</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Duarte, Valmir</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1953-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Plant Pathology and Crop Physiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 144 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>156 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"During three seasons, mother storage roots of Beauregard sweetpotato were inoculated with Erwinia chrysanthemi in March, and the pathogen was recovered from them the day they were bedded, 7 days later, and at the first and second pullings of slips as well as from underground stems at harvest in September and October of the first and second transplantings, respectively. Little stem rot occurred in the fields during the three seasons.;Thirteen strains of E. chrysanthemi, 8 isolated originally from sweetpotato and 5 from other hosts, and one strain of E. carotovora subsp. carotovora were inoculated on sweetpotato and 12 different hosts. Strains from hosts other than sweetpotato caused little or no disease on sweetpotato. Of 95 carbon sources tested, sweetpotato strains used the same 25, were unable to grow on 57, and varied on 13 substrates.;Jewel and Beauregard sweetpotato stem cuttings were inoculated with E. chrysanthemi and/or Fusarium solani before planting in the greenhouse and in the field. In the greenhouse, stem rot lesion length was greater when the two pathogens were inoculated together than the sum of stem lesion length produced by both pathogens inoculated separately. The same effect was observed on Beauregard in the field in 1989 and 1990.;When storage roots were punctured with a flamed needle and incubated for 5 days submerged in distilled water in plastic bags, 85 to 100 % rotted in 2 tests. In the same tests, 15% and none of storage roots rotted when surface disinfested with NaOCl. Two distinguishable pectolytic spore-forming, anaerobic bacteria resembling Clostridium in morphology were found in the lesions, regardless of treatment. Inoculation of storage roots with pure cultures of these bacteria and incubation under anaerobic conditions induced rapid maceration and production of gas, typical of ""souring"", a disorder previously regarded as solely physiological in origin."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Valmir Duarte.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1164."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 141-143).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Sweet potatoes</topic>
      <topic>Diseases and pests</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Root rots</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Erwinia</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123186</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28446451</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198682</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 DUAR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123186</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 DUAR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
