<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Very highly-excited states of "two-electron" systems</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Sadeghpour, Hossein R.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1958-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Physics and Astronomy.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 152 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>163 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The delicate balance that exists between the forces mediating the interaction within multiply-excited electrons and the binding forces of these electrons to the nucleus is totally ignored in the independent particle model of electronic interactions. This dynamical ""see-saw"" is best described in the hyperspherical representation.;We use this method to obtain hyperspherical potential curves, analogous to the Born-Oppenheimer curves of molecular species, for very highly-excited two-electron states of the hydrogen negative ion, helium, and calcium. The present numerical effort exploits the analytic nature of the solutions to the Schroedinger equation at small and large distances to diagonalize the hyperspherical Hamiltonian in the combined representative basis functions. Numerical deficiencies resulting from linear dependency of the total basis set are overcome in an automatic fashion. In the case of He and H$\sp-$, a high degree of diabaticity is observed which limits the channel interaction to within a select set of hyperspherical channels. These dominant channels relevant to photoionization experiments of H$\sp-$ and He are identified.;Inelastic excitation probabilities to these channels are calculated with (a) coupled-hyperspherical channel method and (b) Landau-Zener method in which only nearest-neighbor coupling is considered. Transition probabilities obtained in the Landau-Zener approximation show monotonic behavior with energy.;Correlation effects in H$\sp-$ and He due to the interaction of an asymptotic electron with a permanent electric dipole moment caused by the orbital momentum degeneracy of hydrogenic levels, are studied in the independent-electron coordinate picture. The correlation between the bound electron and the escaping electron is built in through the long-range dipole operator. The polarization of the fluorescence from photofragments is calculated and is shown to violate propensity rules in certain instances.;A preliminary investigation of the correlation effects in Ca is pursued by obtaining highly-excited hyperspherical potential curves for both $\sp1$P$\sp\circ$ and $\sp1$S$\sp e$ final-state symmetries."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Hossein R. Sadeghpour.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1501."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 145-151).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Electron-electron interactions</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Electrons</topic>
      <topic>Scattering</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Photoabsorption</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123235</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28451595</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930715</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198807</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 SADE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123235</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 SADE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
