<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Chromatographic peak shape analysis and modeling</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Jeansonne, Mark Stephen</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1962-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xix, 243 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>263 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Various aspects of chromatographic peak quantitation and shape characterization are investigated in detail for single and overlapping chromatographic peaks. From the viewpoint of providing better quantitation of real chromatographic data while minimizing computational complexity, the results presented should be easily incorporated into existing routine chromatographic data analysis regimes. Three topics applicable to modern chromatographic data analysis are considered.;First, progress in the application of the exponentially modified Gaussian (EMG) function to chromatography is reviewed. The review covers the following areas: (1) equations derived from the model, (2) studies of inherent errors in the quantitation of chromatographic peaks via use of the EMG model, (3) chromatographic applications since 1983, and (4) applications to flow injection analysis. The information discussed and the references included in this review should provide a valuable resource for those researchers considering or already using the EMG model in their studies.;Second, improved empirical equations based on the EMG model are presented. The equations utilize measurements of the graphical parameters peak height (hp), width (W), and asymmetry for the calculation of the following chromatographic figures of merit (CFOMs): $\tau$, $\sigma$, area, variance, third and fourth statistical moments, excess, and skew. The equations are shown to be more accurate than traditional numerical methods when applied to single and overlapped chromatographic peaks that fit the EMG model. Application to simulated and real chromatographic peaks is discussed.;Finally, a computationally simple, normalized data transformation that can be used for peak shape analysis and comparison is introduced. Compared to slope analysis, moment analysis, and the distribution function, the ""Q transformation"" performs much better over a wide range of experimental conditions, including signal to noise (S/N) ratios of less than 100 in which the other methods often fail. This method is shown to be computationally simple, easy to automate, and very intuitive in nature. Application of the Q transformation for impure chromatographic peak detection using single-channel channel data is discussed. Its advantages over the skew, excess, slope analysis and distribution function methods are reported using both simulated and real data."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Mark Stephen Jeansonne.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1393."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Chromatographic analysis</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Chemistry, Analytic</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123204</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28449164</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198795</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 JEAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123204</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 JEAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
