<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Structural and biosynthetic studies of natural products of the asteraceae and lamiaceae</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Menelaou, Marios Andrea</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1962-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xxii, 266 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>289 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"As part of the investigation of the allelopathic interactions of members of the Florida scrub community, the chemical constituents of Solidago pauciflosculosa (Asteraceae) and Calamintha ashei (Lamiaceae) were studied.;Aqueous and organic extracts of fresh leaves of S. pauciflosculosa provided large amounts of diterpene acids. The two major diterpenes isolated, 17-oxygrindelic acid and 17-oxogrindelic acid, showed significant inhibitory effects on germination and radicle growth of two Florida sandhill grasses, Schizachyrium scoparium and Leptochloa dubia. The organic extracts of S. pauciflosculosa were very rich in sesquiterpenes, the three major sesquiterpenes being (+)-epicurlone, (+)-episesquiphellandrene ($-$)-a-trans-bergamotene. These three compounds did not show any significant effects on the germination and radicle growth of test species.;Fresh leaves of C. ashei were very rich in menthofuran monoterpenes and flavonoids. The two major monoterpenes, epievodone and desacetylcalaminthone exhibited strong inhibitory effects on the germination and root growth of test species at concentrations of 106 and 92 ppm, respectively, whereas the flavonoids showed no effects.;Investigation of the chemical constituents of the root of S. pauciflosculosa, S. canadensis and S. sempervirens provided acetylenic compounds and diterpene acids. cis,cis- and cis,trans-Matricaria esters from S. pauciflosculosa as well as cis-dehydromatricaria ester from S. canadensis showed strong inhibitory effects on the germination of test species. cis,cis-Matricaria ester completely inhibited germination of Florida sandhill grasses at 106 and 53 ppm.;Biosynthetic studies of chemical constitutents of hairy root cultures of Tagetes patula (Asteraceae), using $\sp $C-labeled acetates, established the biosynthetic pathway of two bithiophenes and the sesquiterpene b-farnesene. The bithiophenes are formed by linear combination of acetate followed by loss of the two terminal carbon units to give the 12 carbon skeleton of the bithiophenes. b-Farnesene also followed the predicted pathway via the mevalonic acid route.;Further investigation of the chemical constituents of hairy root cultures of Tagetes patula provided, besides the above three compounds, two known bithiophenes and four benzofurans."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Marios Andrea Menelaou.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1441."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Allelopathic agents</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Compositae</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Lamiaceae</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123221</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28436983</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930712</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198457</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 MENE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123221</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 MENE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
