<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Studies in the electrochemistry of insulators and ion transport</title>
      <subTitle>anodization, oscillometry, electroosmosis, and capillary electrophoresis</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Ghowsi, Kiumars</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 162 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>175 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"In part one, an analytical model for the growth kinetics of the anodic oxidation of Si at constant voltage is developed. The theoretical model derived for the film growth rate is consistent with the existing empirical relation reported earlier. Electronic current density, the major total current component, is shown to be nonohmic and space charge limited. Equations are derived, each as a function of time, for the total current density, the electronic current density, and the ionic efficiency during anodic oxidation. These theoretical predictions are in good agreement with the available experimental data.;In part two, the high frequency conductances of three binary electrolytes: NaCl, K$\sb2$S0$\sb4$, and K$\sb3$Fe(CN)$\sb6$ have been measured in aqueous solution by a spectrum analyzer. A maximum conductance at a specific high frequency has been observed at certain concentrations for each electrolyte. The cell used for the experiments is a capacitive cell, or so-called condenser-type cell. A theoretical circuit model, which incorporates the Debye-Falkenhagen effect, has been developed for this type of cell and low field conditions. The calculations based on the classical electrostatic interactions of ions are in satisfactory agreement with experimental results. Some aspects of the high frequency conductance in capacitive cells, such as the role of the Debye-Falkenhagen effect, which has been ignored or misrepresented previously, are clarified.;In part three, the characteristics of the metal-insulator-electrolyte interface (MIE), under quasi-equilibrium conditions, have been studied theoretically. Mathematical models of the MIE have been developed for two cases: ideal, and non-ideal. By combining MIE characteristics and the electroosmotic effect in a capillary, a novel effect called field effect electroosmosis can be postulated. Based on this effect, a new device called a metal-insulator-electrolyte-electrokinetic field effect device (MIEEKFED) can be designed.;Finally, two new fundamental equations for Micellar-Electrokinetic Capillary Chromatography (MECC) have been derived, which are the corresponding Capillary Zone Electrophoresis (CZE) equations for the resolution and the migration time. A Van Deemter-like equation to describe the theoretical plate height for MECC has also been derived. MECC optimal resolution has been found for neutral solutes in three cases: where the migration mobility of the micelle is negative, zero, and positive."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Kiumars Ghowsi.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1391."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 161).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Electric insulators and insulation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Metals</topic>
      <topic>Anodic oxidation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Electrokinetics</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123191</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28446610</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198687</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 GHOW</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123191</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 GHOW</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
