<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>role of sonority in jargonaphasia</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Christman, Sarah Slack.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Speech Communication, Theatre, and Communication Disorders.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vi, 126 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>133 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The Sonority Sequencing Principle suggests that the relative sonority rank among sounds can explain intrasyllabic and transsyllabic phoneme ordering patterns in normal speakers. The values of segments can be ranked from most to least sonority as follows: Vowels, Glides, Liquids, Nasals and Obstruents. The unmarked order of segments within an initial demisyllable is O-N-L-G from the periphery toward the peak, and G-L-N-O in a final demisyllable from the peak toward the periphery. The sonority ""slope"" of an initial demisyllable will be steep to maximize the perceptual saliency of syllable onset. In a final demisyllable, especially if embedded, the slope will be flatter to maintain sonority contrast between abutting syllables.;This study answered the following questions: (1) What syllable shape and sonority profile patterns (in four types of demisyllables) are present in the neologistic and legitimate English utterances of three fluent aphasics, (2) Are these patterns similar to those observed in the well-formed utterances of normal speakers, (3) Does the sonority principle facilitate neologism analysis, (4) Can sonority be incorporated further into models of sentence production and, (5) What implications for sonority theory and for theories of neology are suggested by results.;Data from three neologistic jargonaphasics were audio-recorded during expressive language tasks. Neologisms were phonemically transcribed by three independent listeners. A demisyllable data base for target-related neologisms, abstruse neologisms, and English words was compiled for each subject. Summary frequency distributions for demisyllable shapes and sonority profiles were obtained and tested for each word type.;Results from extensive demisyllable analyses suggested the following: (1) demisyllable shapes for neologisms and English words were most often of the form CV or CVC, (2) intrasyllabic and transsyllabic sonority profiles in neologisms and English words were most frequently of the preferred patterns, although some exceptions were noted, (3) demisyllable shapes and sequence preferences were similar to patterns found in legitimate English words and, (4) sonority may constrain the operation of mechanisms that create neologisms, whether viewed from a serial or parallel model of language production. Results suggest that sonority may partially govern construction of normal and impaired phonological forms."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Sarah Slack Christman.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1383."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 76-81).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Sonorants (Phonetics)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>English language</topic>
      <topic>Sonorants</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Aphasia</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123184</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28444080</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930713</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198667</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 CHRI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123184</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 CHRI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
