<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Attributions of teachers and students in middle school science classrooms</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Rhys, Lennie Holomon.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. Curriculum &amp; Instruction.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 177 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>191 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purpose of the present study was to examine: (a) teachers' notions about their students, (b) students' notions about themselves and learning, and (c) important factors that characterize, and possibly influence, these notions. The investigation was based on attribution theory, which proposes a framework for ascribing causes of a person's behavior, given that person's belief system. In this study, five notions, or attributions, were specified: attachment, concern, satisfied, indifferent, and rejection, and were expressed in three forms: oral, written, and behavioral.;Subjects included three sixth-grade science teachers, three eighth-grade science teachers, and one science class from each teacher's schedule. For each class, data was collected over eight days. First, the researcher recorded the number of hints given to students during the daily lessons. Following, the teacher was asked: (a) to assign each student to one of the five attribute groups, and (b) to complete a demographic information form. In addition, the students were asked: (a) to assign themselves to attribute groups, and (b) to indicate their beliefs about science learning; further, demographic information was collected both from the students and their school records.;The data were analyzed using parametric and non-parametric statistics. First, results showed no statistically significant differences on number of hints given by grade or attribute group, indicating a lack of differential instruction according to these two factors. Second, statistically significant results were found for match between teacher assignments and student assignments by attribute group; the attachment group had significantly fewer matches than did the concern and satisfied groups, indicating differences in teacher attitude toward these groups. Third, statistically significant differences among teacher-assigned groups were found for the demographic variables of gender, race, and socioeconomic status, although no statistically significant results were found among student-assigned groups. Finally, statistically significant differences were found among both teacher-assigned and student-assigned groups according to student beliefs about learning. The findings for demographic variables and beliefs about learning indicate that there are important, but different, factors that characterize and influence teachers' attributions toward their students and students' attributions toward themselves. Such findings have important implications for teacher instruction and student learning in the classroom."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Lennie Holomon Rhys.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: A, page: 8720."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 121-126).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Attribution (Social psychology)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Attribution (Social psychology) in children</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Teacher-student relationships</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Teachers</topic>
      <topic>Attitudes</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Students</topic>
      <topic>Attitudes</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123232</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28447121</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930714</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1198699</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 RHYS</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123232</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 RHYS</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
