<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>relationship of serum killing, phagocytosis and oxidant production by bovine monocyte-derived macrophages to intracellular survival of Brucella abortus</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Bounous, Denise Ida</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1952-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 98 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>108 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Functional activities of monocyte-derived macrophages and serum killing ability in a population of Brucella abortus-naive cows were evaluated. The ability of these macrophages to phagocytize and control intracellular survival of B.abortus and to produce oxidant was measured.;Fresh normal bovine sera killed significantly more B.abortus than reactor serum or fetal bovine serum. When heated to destroy complement, none of the sera were capable of significant killing. The ability of sera from B.abortus-naive cows to kill the bacteria was normally distributed, with all animals within $\pm$ 2 sd of the mean.;Phagocytosis of bacteria opsonized with autologous or reactor sera was significantly greater than phagocytosis of bacteria opsonized with fetal bovine serum. After phagocytosis, bacteria opsonized with autologous, reactor, or fetal bovine serum displayed no differences in their ability to survive within macrophages. The abilities of the macrophages to phagocytize and to kill B.abortus were not significantly correlated. Phagocytosis and killing activities of macrophages from individual cows were normally distributed.;Oxidant production by monocyte-derived macrophages was compared to that by neutrophils after stimulation with phorbol myristate acetate, opsonized zymosan, or B.abortus opsonized with autologous, reactor, or fetal bovine serum. Neutrophils responded faster to all stimuli, and produced up to 100 fold more oxidant than macrophages. PMA stimulated significantly more oxidant from macrophages than opsonized zymosan or opsonized B.abortus. Macrophages and neutrophils stimulated with opsonized zymosan, and reactor serum-opsonized B.abortus had higher mean oxidant production than cells exposed to the other stimuli, suggesting receptor specific initiation of the respiratory burst. Four cows were identified as potential outliers based on oxidant production greater than 2 sd from the mean. There was no correlation between oxidant production and intracellular survival of the bacteria."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Denise Ida Bounous.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1285.;Directors: Frederick M. Enright; Kent A. Gossett."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.) -- Louisiana State University, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Bibliography : leaves 85-97.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Brucella abortus</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Macrophages</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Phagocytosis</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123178</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)); 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">22974699</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LBD</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910117</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1199094</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 BOUN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123178</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 BOUN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
