<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Computational neural learning formalisms for perceptual manipulation</title>
      <subTitle>singularity interaction dynamics model</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Gulati, Sandeep.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Computer Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1990</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 243 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>257 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation addresses a fundamental problem in computational AI--developing a class of massively parallel, neural algorithms for learning robustly, and in real-time, complex nonlinear transformations from representative exemplars. Provision of such a capability is at the core of many real-life problems in robotics, signal processing and control. The concepts of terminal attractors in dynamical systems theory and adjoint operators in nonlinear sensitivity theory are exploited to provide a firm mathematical foundation for learning such mappings with dynamical neural networks, while achieving a dramatic reduction in the overall computational costs. Further, we derive an efficient methodology for handling a multiplicity of application-specific constraints during run-time, that precludes additional retraining or disturbing the synaptic structure of the ""learned"" network.;The scalability of proposed theoretical models to large-scale embodiments in neural hardware is analyzed. Neurodynamical parameters, e.g., decay constants, response gains, etc., are systematically analyzed to understand their implications on network scalability, convergence, throughput and fault tolerance, during both concurrent simulations and implementation in concurrently asynchronous VLSI, optical and opto-electronic hardware. Dynamical diagnostics, e.g., Lyapunov exponents, are used to formally characterize the widely observed dynamical instability in neural networks as ""emergent computational chaos"". Using contracting operators and nonconstructive theorems from fixed point theory, we rigorously derive necessary and sufficient conditions for eliminating all oscillatory and chaotic behavior in additive-type networks. Extensive benchmarking experiments are conducted with arbitrarily large neural networks (over 100 million interconnects) to verify the methodological robustness of our network ""conditioning"" formalisms.;Finally, we provide insight for exploiting our proposed repertoire of neural learning formalisms in addressing a fundamental problem in robotics--manipulation controller design for robots operating in unpredictable environments. Using some recent results in task analysis and dynamic modeling we develop the ""Perceptual Manipulation Architecture"". The architecture, conceptualized within a perceptual framework, is shown to be well beyond the state-of-the-art model-directed robotics. For a stronger physical interpretation of its implications, our discussions are embedded in context of a novel systems' concept for automated space operations."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Sandeep Gulati.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-03, Section: B, page: 1544."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1990.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 216-241).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Artificial intelligence</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Neural networks (Computer science)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Robotics</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9123194</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1990</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28463012</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930716</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1199182</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1990 GULA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9123194</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1990 GULA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
