<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>J. S. Bach's Chaconne in D minor</title>
      <subTitle>an examination of three arrangements for piano solo</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <titleInfo type="alternative">
      <title>Chaconne in D minor</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <titleInfo type="alternative">
      <title>Bach's Chaconne in D minor</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Pruett, Jeffery Mark</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1959-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Music.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>v, 83 leaves : music ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>89 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The chaconne from the Second Partita for Solo Violin by Johann Sebastian Bach is one of the most often arranged compositions in the history of music. In the century following the first publication in 1802 of Bach's six sonatas and partitas for solo violin, the chaconne was performed in arrangements and transcriptions almost as diverse as the composers whom it inspired. From the years 1879 and 1893, respectively, came the most famous arrangements--those by Johannes Brahms and Ferruccio Busoni (both for solo piano). Larry Sitsky, writing of works based on the chaconne apart from those for solo instruments, has referred to ""countless"" arrangements for organ, orchestra, and various instrumental ensembles.$\sp1$ (Busoni himself has mentioned orchestral transcriptions of the chaconne which were performed in America during the early part of the twentieth century.)$\sp2$.;This monograph consists of an examination of three versions of Bach's Chaconne in D Minor--those by Ernst von Pauer (1867), Arthur Briskier (1954), and Karl Hermann Pillney (1968). In addition, a brief comparison of piano accompaniments written for the chaconne by Felix Mendelssohn and Robert Schumann (1847 and 1853 respectively) comprises the remainder of the study. While Pauer's arrangement dates from the second half of the nineteenth century--the period of the Brahms and Busoni versions--only the latter two have remained in the repertoire for solo piano. I have chosen to examine Pauer's Chaconne because of its display of virtuoso keyboard technique, a quality that removes it dramatically from the original source. Briskier's and Pillney's arrangements are examined in light of their similar compositional geneses--both are works dating from the twentieth century and subsequently reflect a more conservative view of the interpretation of Bach's original work.;The study of these arrangements reveals diverse attitudes toward the performance of Bach, as well as an insight into the art of piano transcription during the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. ftn$\sp1$Larry Sitsky, Busoni and the Piano: the Works, the Writings, and the Recordings (New York: St. Martin's Press, 1972), 307. $\sp2$Ferruccio Busoni, Letters to His Wife, trans. by Rosamond Ley (New York: Da Capo Press, 1975), 251."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Jeffery Mark Pruett.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-07, Section: A, page: 2317."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 67-69).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <name type="personal">
         <namePart>Bach, Johann Sebastian</namePart>
         <namePart type="date">1685-1750</namePart>
         <role>
            <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
            <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
         </role>
      </name>
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sonaten und Partiten</title>
         <partNumber>BWV 1001-1006. no. 2</partNumber>
         <partName>Partita, Chaconne</partName>
      </titleInfo>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9200085</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28524156</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930727</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200376</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 PRUE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9200085</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 PRUE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
