<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Stereoelectronics of carboxylate-imidazolium hydrogen bonds in models of the aspartate-histidine couple in serine proteases</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Nabulsi, Nabeel Abdel Raouf</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1956-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xv, 235 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>251 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The geometry of the carboxylate-imidazolium hydrogen bond in the crystalline state and the effect of microenvironment are investigated in models of the aspartate-histidine (Asp-His) couple. Synthetic methods leading to the preparation of intramolecular models, possessing syn and anti-oriented hydrogen bonds, also are described. A single-pot procedure has been developed for converting phenoxyacetonitriles into their respective benzimidazole derivative in higher yields than the traditional two step procedure. An efficient single-pot procedure also has been developed for converting benzofuran to its acetylene derivative, 2-acetoxyphenylacetylene. This method involves in situ acetylation of the unstable phenol intermediate.;Nine intermolecular imidazolium-benzoate couples have been prepared and their structures analyzed by single crystal X-ray crystallography. The structure of an intramolecular model also has been determined by single crystal X-ray crystallography. The orientation of all the imidazolium hydrogen bonds is syn relative to the carboxylate. Furthermore, syn hydrogen bonds are shorter than anti hydrogen bonds. The strength of the hydrogen bond increases as $\Delta$pK$\sb{\rm a}$ between the donor and acceptor decreases. The basicity of the carboxylate is governed by the number of hydrogen bonds accepted by it: successive hydrogen bonding to carboxylate decreases its basicity. Consequently, correlations of hydrogen-bond strength and basicity (pK$\sb{a}$ and PA) of carboxylates are more reliable when carboxylates accept equal number of hydrogen bonds. Stereoelectronics of syn hydrogen bonding to carboxylates are affected by the presence of strong and geometrically constrained anti hydrogen bonding. With respect to the plane of the carboxylate, syn hydrogen bonding lies (1) within 10$\sp\circ$ in the absence of anti hydrogen bonding, (2) out-of-plane (30-35$\sp\circ$) in the presence of one anti hydrogen bond, and (3) within 10$\sp\circ$ in the presence of two anti hydrogen bonds. Out-of-plane distortion in the presence of an anti-oriented hydrogen bond suggests a catalytic role for the anti-oriented Ser-214 side-chain in serine proteases."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Nabeel Abdel Raouf Nabulsi.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-07, Section: B, page: 3608."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 124-136).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Hydrogen bonding</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Carboxylic acids</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9200078</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28524302</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930727</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200381</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 NABU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9200078</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 NABU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
