<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Radial flow chromatography in compressed pancake-shaped beds</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Heft, Brian Keith</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1958-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemical Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 191 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm. + 4 computer disks (5 1/2 in.</extent>
      <extent>202 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The separation of a methane/n-butane mixture was demonstrated using radial flow through compressed, pancake-shaped beds of fine alumina powder. The compacted stationary phase improved performance relative to an uncompressed sorbent by assuring flow uniformity through the bed, reducing band-broadening and tailing (by decreasing interstitial hold-up) and decreasing effective plate height (through an increase in the capacity ratio of the chromatograph).;Dispersion was identified as the key dissipative effect in the prototype radial flow adsorber. An exact analytical solution derived for the transport equations describing such a device compared favorably with experimental data. The dispersion coefficients were found to be strong functions of the individual solute sorption constants. The dispersion coefficient for weakly adsorbed solutes such as methane was found to reduce to molecular diffusivity. This phenomenon is believed to result from a combination of classical Taylor dispersion and pore hold up effects such as that suggested by Dayan and Levenspiel (D2) for conventional, axial flow patterns.;The elementary Peclet number defining the order of the Bessel functions appearing in the analytical solution was shown to control the shape of the response curve. The system time constant that determines retention is seen to vary with--among other parameters--the equilibrium sorption constant and the radius of the adsorber. The inverse dependence of both the Peclet number and the time constant on interstitial porosity indicates that increased compression will sharpen the response while increasing retention.;A theoretical comparison of inward and outward flow configurations indicates that the order of the Bessel functions defining the response is higher for the inward flow option. This suggests that the inward flow configuration may ultimately offer performance advantages. Unfortunately, mechanical difficulties prevented experimental verification of this trend.;Methods for improving separation--including the use of greater sorbent bed compression, temperature programming and stacking of individual sorbent discs--are discussed briefly."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Brian Keith Heft.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-07, Section: B, page: 3754."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 136-139).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Chromatographic analysis</topic>
      <topic>Equipment and supplies</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Gas chromatography</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9200067</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28565199</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930804</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1203408</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 HEFT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9200067</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 HEFT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
