<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Quantitation of phenolic acids and effect of controlled atmosphere storage on peach fruit quality</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Horticulture.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 96 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>106 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Total and individual phenolic acids in firm-ripe fruit of ten different peach (Prunus persica Batsch.) genotypes were analyzed by spectrophotometry and high performance liquid schrmoatography (HPLC) and related to internal browning potential. A comparison of phenolic acid separation was made between five different column types. A Lichrosorb RP-18 column provided the best separation of the major phenolic acids in peach fruit mesocarp tissue. Quinic was the predominant phenolic acid, followed in concentration by gentisic, catechin, chlorogenic, and syringic acids. Quantities differed between genotypes. The genotypes with the highest internal browning potential contained the highest concentration of chlorogenic acid, gentisic acid, and total phenolics.;Controlled atmosphere ((1% O$\sb2$, 4% O$\sb2$, 7% O$\sb2$, or 20% O$\sb2$) + 5% CO$\sb2$) (CA) storage was tested to determine its effect on several physical and chemical attributes of firm-ripe harvested fruit. The 1% O$\sb2$ + 5% CO$\sb2$ and 4% O$\sb2$ + 5% CO$\sb2$ stored fruit had lower concentrations of reducing sugars but higher sucrose than fruit stored in air. Fruit pH increased and titratable acidity decreased over the 40 day storage period. The 1% O$\sb2$ + 5% CO$\sb2$ and 4% O$\sb2$ + 5% CO$\sb2$ stored fruits were higher in citric and malic acid content than air stored fruit. Citric acid and malic acid decreased during storage. Little or no change in individual phenolic acids occurred during storage or between 1% O$\sb2$ + 5% CO$\sb2$ and air storage. Internal color darkened and became redder with storage. CA stored fruit were significantly firmer than air stored fruit. Sensory evaluation indicated CA (1% O$\sb2$ + 5% CO$\sb2$) stored fruit were more acidic, sweeter, and had better overall flavor than air stored fruit. Peach fruits held at room temperature for 2 days following storage at 0$\sp\circ$C in air for 40 days developed external and internal browning and fruit quality deteriorated. Comparable fruit stored at 0$\sp\circ$C under 1% O$\sb2$ + 5% CO$\sb2$ had very little internal breakdown and retained good quality after 2 days at 22$\sp\circ$C. The 20% O$\sb2$ + 5% CO$\sb2$ and air treatments had the highest percentage of fruit decay during storage at 0$\sp\circ$C."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Ahmed FathAllah El-Shiekh.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-07, Section: B, page: 3363."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 73-79).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Phenols</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Peach</topic>
      <topic>Storage</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Fruit</topic>
      <topic>Quality</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9200060</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28535086</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930729</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200512</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 EL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9200060</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 EL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
