<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Isolation and characterization of macrophage inhibitory compounds from Mycobacterium paratuberculosis</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Hines, Murray Elison, II</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1956-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 220 leaves : ill., photos. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>231 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Fractions exhibiting activity detrimental to the killing function of activated bovine monocyte/macrophages towards Candida albicans were obtained from Mycobacterium paratuberculosis. Active fractions were initially derived by ultrasonication of bacterial samples followed by ammonium sulfate precipitation, ion-exchange chromatography, gel filtration chromatography, heat precipitation, acid precipitation and alkali treatment. Two different fractions that exhibited marked inhibition of macrophage killing ability were derived and partially characterized.;Novel methodology was developed to accomplish the task of lysis and fractionation of mycobacteria utilizing the Matrix Solid Phase Dispersion (MSPD) technique that appeared to be much more efficient and is certainly less time consuming and less expensive than classical methodologies. Fractionation of cellular components were confirmed by analysis of the solvent extracts by SDS-PAGE, Markwell protein determination, High Pressure Liquid Chromatography (HPLC) and Gas Chromatography/Mass Spectrometry (GC/MS). By making minor modifications in the MSPD technique both genomic and plasmid DNA were obtained in partial purity. The DNA samples were further purified using classical methodology to obtain DNA that was amenable to restriction endonuclease digestion with yields comparable to those of classical means.;By utilizing the MSPD technique for lysis and fractionation of mycobacteria, two M. paratuberculosis strain 18 MSPD fractions demonstrating marked inhibitory activity towards the killing function of macrophages were obtained (ACN and H$\sb2$O MSPD extracts). Further fractionation by centrifugal filtration and by Concanavalin A affinity chromatography demonstrated as many as three compounds that show macrophage inhibitory activity. All of the active fractions appear to be combinations of carbohydrate and lipid (glycolipids) with proteinaceous components either being minimal or absent. Preliminary plasma desorption mass spectral data suggests that one fraction may be a mixture of mycolic acids, while the other two fractions contained mannosyl and/or glucosyl functional groups."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Murray Elison Hines II.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-07, Section: B, page: 3474."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.) -- Louisiana State University, 1991.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Cattle</topic>
      <topic>Infections</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Tuberculosis in cattle</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Macrophages</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9200068</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">24169315</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LBD</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">910802</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200380</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 HINE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9200068</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 HINE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
