<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Feedback linearization of nonlinear systems</title>
      <subTitle>robustness and adaptive control</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Kim, Weon Ho</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1959-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemical Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 242 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>255 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Feedback linearization provides an effective means of designing nonlinear control systems. This method permits one to have an exactly equivalent linear system by using a coordinate transformation and state feedback. Once the nonlinear system is transformed to a linear system, one can proceed with well developed control technologies for linear systems. Feedback linearization is based on a model of the real system. If there is mismatch between the model and the real plant, feedback linearization does not yield an exactly linear system. The question of robustness then arises: will a controller based on the model be stable when applied to the real plant?;We have developed a theoretical approach to analyze robustness of feedback linearization of SISO (Single-Input Single-Output) systems. We have also considered the dimensional reduction of a high dimensional model which is not a standard singularly perturbed system. Specifically we have found sufficient conditions for boundedness and convergence of the system trajectories when feedback linearization based on a nominal mathematical model is applied to an uncertain real plant which may have parametric and structural uncertainties as well as unmodeled dynamics. The developed approach does not require the restrictive conditions which are commonly used in the previously developed methods of robustness analysis.;Furthermore, for parametric uncertainties a nonlinear adaptive control of feedback linearizable processes is proposed. The main feature of the proposed nonlinear adaptive control system is that it is relatively straightforward and simple. For this adaptive control system we have found sufficient conditions for stability of the output regulation and tracking of feedback linearizable systems using the second method of Lyapunov.;Examples of the robustness analysis and the adaptive control for unstable chemical and biochemical reactors are given."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Weon Ho Kim.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-07, Section: B, page: 3757."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 209-213).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Nonlinear control theory</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Nonlinear theories</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9200073</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28524545</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930727</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200384</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 KIM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9200073</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 KIM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
