<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>study of the metal clusters in the nitrogenase proteins of Azotobacter vinelandii</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Oliver, Melinda Ehrlich</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1959-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 210 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>225 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Electron Paramagnetic Resonance (EPR) spectroscopy was used to examine the paramagnetism of the clusters in nitrogenase from Azotobacter vinelandii. The EPR spectrum of nitrogenase (Av1 and Av2) was examined in the presence of an extrinsic paramagnet, DyEDTA, at different concentrations of NaCl, during thionine oxidation (Av1), and in the presence of MgATP (Av2). Cross combinations of Av1 and Av2 were also investigated in the presence and absence of the chemical cross-linker, EDC as well as with the nitrogenase components from Clostridium pasteurianum.;From relaxation enhancement measurements, the distance of closest approach of DyEDTA to the intrinsic metal clusters in Av1 and Av2 was calculated. For Av2, the distance was calculated to be 5 A. The calculated distance for Av1, however, put the M center practically on the surface of the protein. One reason for this (probably) spurious result may be that the distance calculation is derived for a model with total spin S = 1/2. The M center in Av1 is a faster-relaxing S = 3/2 system which will affect the different terms of the dipolar Hamiltonian in ways different from an S = 1/2 system.;The results of the thionine oxidation of Av1 provided evidence of dipolar interactions between paramagnetic P clusters and the paramagnetic M centers. These results were fitted to a model for the interaction and arrangement of the P clusters relative to the M centers.;The paramagnetism of the metal clusters of Av1$\sp\prime$ (the alternative nitrogenase from Azotobacter vinelandii) was investigated as a function of (1) enzymatic turnover; (2) thionine oxidation of Av1$\sp\prime$; (3) the effects of pH on Av1$\sp\prime$; and (4) isolation of the cofactor. The S = 1/2 signal was completely quenched upon completion of turnover, while the S = 3/2 signal decreased only slightly in intensity. Thionine oxidation of Av1$\sp\prime$ produced analogous results in which the S = 1/2 signal was oxidized with one-half equivalent of thionine. The S = 3/2 signal required almost four equivalents before decreasing significantly in amplitude. Increasing the pH of Av1$\sp\prime$ shifted the S = 3/2 signal and the S = 1/2 signal increased in amplitude. Finally, FeVco, the cofactor or M center of Av1$\sp\prime$, was successfully extracted into DMF but not into NMF."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Melinda Ehrlich Oliver.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-07, Section: B, page: 3625."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Protein nitrogen</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Plants</topic>
      <topic>Effect of nitrogen on</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Nitrogen</topic>
      <topic>Fixation</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9200080</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28528838</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930728</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200410</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 OLIV</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9200080</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 OLIV</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
