<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Fluorescence studies of phosphofructokinase from bacillus stearothermophilus</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Kim, Soon-Jong</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1957-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 136 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>150 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Phosphofructokinase catalyzes the phosphorylation of $\beta$-fructose 6-phosphate (Fru-6-P) to $\beta$-fructose 1,6-bisphosphate. The first part of this dissertation shows that phosphofructokinase from Bacillus stearothermophilus (Bs-PFK) is a tetramer in the region pH 4.5-9.5 unlike the enzymes from mammalian sources, which exhibit association-dissociation reactions. Circular dichroism, steady-state fluorescence, and static and dynamic light scattering were used to study the conformational properties of the enzyme. Inactivation of the enzyme below pH 7.0 is not due to dissociation of the tetramer to dimers or monomers.;In the second part, the fluorescence of the lone tryptophan was investigated by steady-state and time-resolved techniques. The decay of Bs-PFK can be best described as a discrete double exponential with lifetimes of $\sim$1.6 and 4.4 ns. The decay-associated emission spectra of the two components are identical. Similar results were obtained in D$\sb2$O, suggesting that the heterogeneous emission is not due to excited-state proton transfer. The activation energy for the temperature-dependent nonradiative decay rate was $\sim$0.94 Kcal/mol. The emission had a quantum yield of 0.30 $\pm$ 0.03 with a rate constant for acrylamide quenching, 0.62 $\times$ 10$\sp9$ M$\sp{-1}$ s$\sp{-1}$ which is 4-fold lower than the value expected for a diffusion controlled reaction. The fluorescence anisotropy is 0.18 suggesting that the tryptophan environment is fairly rigid. From the anisotropy decay measurements, a single exponential decay with rotational correlation time of $\sim$40 ns with r(0) value of $\sim$0.19 was obtained.;Finally, the effects of allosteric ligand binding and site-specific mutation on the conformation of Bs-PFK were studied. Addition of adenosine triphosphate (ATP) or Fru-6-P did not cause any change in fluorescence. However, there is about 7% decrease of quantum yield and 2 nm red shift of emission maximum, upon adding the inhibitor PEP. Fru-6-P restores the fluorescence parameters to those of native Bs-PFK indicating the substrate induced allosteric transition from T- to R-conformation. The Arg-252 to Ala-252 mutation caused opposite effects: increase of quantum yield and 2 nm blue shift of emission maximum."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Soon-Jong Kim.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-07, Section: B, page: 3479."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Allosteric enzymes</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Tryptophan</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Fluorescence</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9200072</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28531715</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930728</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200477</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 KIM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9200072</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 KIM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
