<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Conceptus-derived immunosuppressive factors and their role in fetal allograft protection</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Roth, Terri Lynn</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1964-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Animal Science Dept.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 151 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>165 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The role of conceptus-derived immunosuppressive factors in protecting the fetal allograft was investigated by first examining the immunosuppressive activity derived from ovine, caprine and hybrid conceptus trophoblast tissue. Medium conditioned by 20 day-old conceptus trophoblast tissue from each species suppressed sheep and goat lymphocyte proliferation (P $$.05) between the immunosuppressive effects of the three media on either sheep or goat lymphocytes. In subsequent studies, horse conceptus-conditioned medium (HCCM) derived from embryos at days 9, 15 and 26 of gestation, suppressed mitogen-stimulated horse lymphocytes (P $&lt;$.001). HCCM maintained its suppressive activity following heating and repeated freeze-thawing. Using microconcentrator centrifugation, it was determined that the suppressor factor(s) was $&gt;$100,000 MW. HCCM was tested in donkey and goat lymphocyte cultures and proved capable of suppressing proliferation of xenogeneic lymphocytes (P $&lt;$.01). However, the suppressive capacity of HCCM in caprine lymphocyte cultures was less (P $&lt;$.05) than that in equine cultures. Trophoblast tissue of 21 day-old horse conceptuses was cultured in the presence and absence of indomethacin. Both immunosuppressive activity and the concentration of prostaglandin E$\sb2$ (PGE$\sb2$) in the medium of each culture were measured. While PGE$\sb2$ production was greatly reduced in cultures containing indomethacin, trophoblast-derived immunosuppressive activity was not affected (P $&gt;$.05). The final study involved partial characterization of the HCCM suppressor factor's (HCCM-SF) mechanism of action. By testing HCCM-SF in cultures stimulated with mitogens that selectively activate B and/or T lymphocytes, and by sorting HCCM-SF-treated and non-treated cells labeled with fluorescent antibodies, it was determined that HCCM-SF acts on T lymphocytes. The temporal effect of HCCM-SF was also investigated and, compared to lymphocytes treated at time 0, proliferation was greater (P $&lt;$.01) in cultures treated with HCCM-SF 24 or 48 hours after the start of stimulation. Furthermore, the removal of HCCM-SF from lymphocyte cultures resulted in complete recovery of cell responsiveness. The addition of recombinant human IL-2 to the lymphocyte cultures did not overcome the suppressive effect of HCCM-SF (P $$.05). HCCM-SF may be one factor responsible for inhibiting cell-mediated fetal allograft rejection during pregnancy."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Terri Lynn Roth.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-09, Section: B, page: 4620."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 123-147).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Fetus</topic>
      <topic>Immunolgy</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Placenta</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Maternal-fetal exchange</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9207529</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28564515</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930804</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1203393</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 ROTH</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9207529</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 ROTH</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
