<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Poly (Arylene ether sulfones)</title>
      <subTitle>synthesis, modifications and applications</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xix, 229 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>249 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Poly(arylene ether sulfones) were synthesized by aromatic nucleophilic polymerization of the monomers; 4,4$\sp\prime$-biphenol, 4-chlorophenyl sulfone, hydroquinone, and tert-butylhydroquinone. Different conditions of temperature and solvent systems were used to determine the best synthetic approaches for the preparation of poly-(4,4$\sp\prime$-biphenol/4-chlorophenyl sulfone) (1:1), poly-(4-4$\sp\prime$-biphenol/4-chlorophenyl sulfone/hydroquinone) (1:2:1), and poly (4-4$\sp\prime$-biphenol/4-chlorophenyl sulfone/tert-butylhydroquinone) (1:2:1). The use of aprotic high boiling solvent mixtures of N-methyl-2-pyrrolidone (NMP), and N-cyclohexyl-2-pyrrolidone (CHP), facilitated the formation of polymers with structures which can easily be controlled by varying the ratio of monomers, and by varying the concentration of reactants.;The polymers were functionalized and modified by silylation, amination and aminomethylation. Directed silylation by electrophilic substitution ortho to the ether group was effected by bromination, followed by lithiation with butyllithium before quenching with chlorotrimethyl-silane. Silylation ortho to the sulfonyl group was effected by metal hydrogen exchange with butyllithium before quenching with chlorotrimethysilane. A maximum of two trimethylsilyl substituents can be introduced for every repeat unit.;Modification by amination was accomplished by the introduction of a nitro group and subsequent reduction of the nitro group to an amine. Sodium dithionite was more effective than sulfur/sodium borohydride, or titanium tetrachloride/lithium aluminum hydride as a reducing agent. Degrees of functionalization up to 2 amino groups per repeat unit were achieved.;Aminomethylation was performed in a two step process. The first step involved introduction of an N-methylphthalimide substituent by condensation of the activated arylene repeat units with N-hydroxymethyl-phthalimide in the presence of a highly protic solvent mixture, trifluoroacetic acid and trifluoromethanesulfonic acid. The second step involved hydrazinolysis to cleave the phthalimide group and to release aminomethyl substituents.;The polymers and their functionalized derivatives were characterized by $\sp1$H and $\sp $C NMR, infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR), differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), and viscosity measurements. $\sp $C NMR chemical shifts calculated from additivity rule were compared with the assigned chemical shifts. The spectroscopic results are consistent with the assigned structures.;The glass transition temperatures (Tg) of the polymers were compared with predicted values based upon molar additivity of incremental values for the structural units. As predicted, tert-butyl substituents raised the Tg while introduction of the more flexible trimethylsilyl groups reduced the Tg's compared to unsubstituted polymers."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Marietta N. Aniano-Ilao.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-09, Section: B, page: 4855."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 219-228).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Polymers</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Macromolecules</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Polymerization</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9207484</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28545590</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930730</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200660</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 ANIA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9207484</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 ANIA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
