<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Characterization of double-stranded RNA and fungal virus from diaporthe phaseolorum var. caulivora</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Lee, Yong-Hwan</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Plant Pathology and Crop Physiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 102 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>113 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Fifty-two isolates of Diaporthe phaseolorum var. caulivora originating from eight different states of the United States were collected and grown on potato dextrose broth for 2-3 wk. Double-stranded RNA was extracted by two cycles of cellulose (CF-11) chromatography and electrophoresed on 6% polyacrylamide gel. Among all isolates tested, 28 (54%) contained at least one molecule of dsRNA. Molecular sizes of dsRNA ranged from 0.4 to 4.5 Kb, and seven different sizes of dsRNA were detected. The 4.5 Kb dsRNA did not have sequence homology with smaller dsRNAs (2.1, 1.8, and 1.4 Kb), suggesting that the smaller dsRNAs are not deletion products of the 4.5 Kb dsRNA. The dsRNAs were located in the cytoplasm of the fungi. The dsRNA of D. p. caulivora was apparently not associated with pathogenicity, toxin production, growth rate, or phenol oxidase activity.;Isometric virus particles about 30-40 nm in diameter were detected from a virulent isolate. The viral genome was composed of one double-stranded RNA molecule with a molecular size of 4.5 Kb. The molecular size of viral dsRNA was the same as that extracted from mycelia. Three polypeptides (93 Kd, 90 Kd, and 88 Kd) were associated with the virus particles. Polyclonal antibodies generated to virus particles reacted to all three viral polypeptides. These data suggest that this virus, designated as DpcV, is a possible member of the Totoviridae.;To compare southern and northern isolates of this pathogen, fourteen selected isolates representing six southern states (AR, FL, GA, LA, MS, and TN) and two northern states (IO and OH) were compared for colony morphology, mycelial growth at 22 and 30 C, type of perithecia formation, phenol oxidase activity, pathogenicity, and phenol-soluble polypeptides by two-dimensional electrophoresis. Southern isolates showed more variable colony morphology, mycelial growth at both temperatures, phenol oxidase activity, type of perithecia formation, and level of pathogenicity to soybean cultivar Bedford than northern isolates. Greater genetic diversity was observed among southern isolates than among northern isolates in polypeptide analysis. However, polypeptide analysis by two-dimensional electrophoresis indicated a strong genetic relationship between the two populations, suggesting that the fungi causing southern and northern stem canker are the same fungus."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Yong-Hwan Lee.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-09, Section: B, page: 4544."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references.</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Fungal diseases of plants</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Plant viruses</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Soybean</topic>
      <topic>Diseases and pests</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9207517</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28560496</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930803</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1201121</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 LEE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9207517</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 LEE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
