<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Directed and spontaneous transfer of college developmental reading students' textmarking strategies</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Frazier, Deidra Williams.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Curriculum &amp; Instruction.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vi, 242 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>249 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purpose of this study was to examine directed and spontaneous transfer of college developmental reading students' textmarking strategy use. Two males and two females enrolled in a developmental reading course at Louisiana State University participated. Participants were asked to use textmarking strategies in their introductory biology course. During scheduled meetings with the researcher, participants turned in their annotated material, discussed textmarking progress, and received feedback on the quality of their annotations. Students were also asked to reflect on strategy use in assigned journal entries.;Participants were not asked to use textmarking strategies in any other content course in which they were enrolled. However, at the end of the semester, they were asked to bring in any textbooks in which they had marked to the researcher for analysis of spontaneous textmarking.;Data collection occurred over the 15-week semester and included the following sources: photocopies of participants' textbooks in both the developmental reading and biology courses, journal assignments, transcriptions of audiotaped interviews with participants and developmental reading and Biology 1001 instructors, and student course evaluations of developmental reading. Data were analyzed using constant comparative analysis.;Results indicated that: (a) Although efforts varied, students generally exhibited strong resistance to annotation; (b) students either annotated too much or too little information; (c) students had difficulty distinguishing important from trivial information, organizing information, and paraphrasing, and they initially ignored graphic aids; (d) although students gave varied reasons for adjusting textmarking, their existing knowledge of content material and test expectations appeared to be the strongest factors; (e) perceptions of textmarking utility varied little across students; (f) students' statements of textmarking utility were consistent with their use of the strategy, with the exception of one student; and (g) students gave the same reasons for lack of textmarking transfer to outside courses.;These findings are generally supported by earlier textmarking and strategy transfer research and have several implications for developmental reading programs based on a strategic learning approach. To provide students with reading and study strategies and to promote transfer of these strategies, both training within developmental reading programs and the relation between the developmental reading program and subject disciplines should be considered."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Deidra Williams Frazier.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-09, Section: A, page: 3232."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 209-221).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Note-taking</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Study skills</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9207503</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28537343</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930729</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200579</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 FRAZ</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9207503</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 FRAZ</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
