<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Self and power</title>
      <subTitle>political reconstruction in the drama of Christopher Marlowe</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <titleInfo type="alternative">
      <title>Political reconstruction in the drama of Christopher Marlowe</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Brown, Patricia A.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of English.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vi, 281 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>288 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Christopher Marlowe created Renaissance drama as we think of it today. Marlowe's princely protagonists are studied here not as sovereigns responsible for the general well-being of their subjects, but as ambitious characters who use power to control their personal environment. Seen from this viewpoint, the dramatic function of the central characters is either to develop a new stance toward the idea of public authority or to refashion an old one. Instead of attending to governance, they attempt to encompass all existence within themselves: Tamburlaine the world conqueror; Edward and Dido, public rulers whose private relationships transform their public positions; the Guise and his hypocrisy of public religion and private vengeance; Barabas and the uses of power and wealth in The Jew of Malta; Faustus, whose supernatural aspirations contain both hell and (he thinks) heaven in its scope.;In creating a new politics (and new politicians), Marlowe's texts fuse private life and governing structures by personifying those structures. The ruler becomes the representative political ""man"" looking for a way to integrate the facets of his character into a holistic human existence. The failure of central authority in these plays to be entirely orthodox or successfully hegemonic suggests that an inclusive politics of power could increase the ability of the characters to succeed by making their aspirations cooperative instead of competitive. Marlowe's drama emphasizes self-actualization (one could even say self-dramatization) without explicit moral judgments.;The work of three twentieth-century political thinkers provides the theoretical coherence for this view of politics as a possible means to self-actualization or humanization: Hannah Arendt, Michel Foucault, and Roberto Mangabeira Unger. Arendt surveys the deterioration of the Greek idea of the polis into a separation of the public and private realms of existence. Foucault's investigations support a view of the moral neutrality of power. Unger argues that domination is the one form of human action which does not increase human actualization. Because Marlovian protagonists are unconventional figures, ambitious for power, they offer various challenges to the traditional structure of authority."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Patricia A. Brown.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-09, Section: A, page: 3289."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 261-279).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <name type="personal">
         <namePart>Marlowe, Christopher</namePart>
         <namePart type="date">1564-1593</namePart>
         <role>
            <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
            <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
         </role>
      </name>
      <topic>Criticism and interpretation</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Politics in literature</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>European drama</topic>
      <temporal>Renaissance, 1450-1600</temporal>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9207491</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28540115</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930730</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200589</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 BROW</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9207491</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 BROW</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
