<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>rhetoric of community ritual</title>
      <subTitle>the blessing of the shrimp fleet at Chauvin, Louisiana</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <titleInfo type="alternative">
      <title>Blessing of the shrimp fleet at Chauvin, Louisiana</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Gordon, Barbara Elizabeth.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Speech Communication.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>v, 328 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>334 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study examines the rhetorical functions of a community ritual, the blessing of the shrimp fleet at Chauvin, Louisiana. Chauvin is a Cajun community in south Louisiana. Their annual fleet blessing was instituted in the 1930's and continues today relatively unchanged.;The author observed the preparations and performance of the blessing and boat parade and also interviewed community members about the blessing. The observations and interview transcriptions are the primary data used for analysis of the community discourse.;Fantasy theme analysis is used to demonstrate the community's use of discourse to develop and maintain group hierarchy. The discourse reveals six fantasy themes prevalent in the discourse of the people of Chauvin. The six--unity, security, perpetuation, pride, care-taking, and pioneering--are traits attributed to the shrimpers whose profession is ""blessed"" by the ritual. The fantasy themes chain into a rhetorical vision that reinforces the perception that the shrimpers are heroes. Their success or failure determines the economic status of the entire community. Thus they are crusaders whose quest is to defeat the community's fears and enemies to ensure economic stability.;The discourse about the blessing reveals four communal fears: loss of land, of business, of religious roots, and of cultural identification. Fantasy theme analysis permits the researcher to investigate how these fears pressure the group, and how discourse about the blessing spawns new fantasy themes that group members can use to adapt to the pressures. Similarly, villains such as intrusive outsiders, non-participating insiders, and the forces of nature are revealed through the discourse.;This study shows how the discourse of the blessing of the shrimp fleet unites the Cajuns of Chauvin in combating their fears and their villainous foes. Through the ritual the members of this community continue to reaffirm their Acadian culture and identity in the face of internal and external pressures to conform to mainstream American social values. Eventually, the community members will have to fend off encroachments more aggressively. Fantasy theme analysis reveals that the community members currently lack verbal strategies to help them address the increasing pressures directly."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Barbara Elizabeth Gordon.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-09, Section: A, page: 3125."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 162-165).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <name type="corporate">
         <namePart>Catholic Church</namePart>
         <role>
            <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
            <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
         </role>
      </name>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
      <topic>Customs and practices</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Public speaking</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Rites and ceremonies</topic>
      <geographic>Louisiana</geographic>
      <geographic>Chauvin</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Cajuns</topic>
      <topic>Social life and customs</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9207506</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28540096</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930730</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200588</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 GORD</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9207506</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 GORD</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
