<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Statistical sophistication of research in vocational education</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Zhang, Chi.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Vocational Education.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 118 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>128 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purpose of this study was to determine the status of, and changes in, the statistical sophistication of research in vocational education in the 1980s. The study also explored relationships among statistical sophistication, problem area studied, and methodological strategy used in vocational education research.;Data collected were obtained from 118 quantitative research reports randomly selected from the Journal of Vocational Education Research, the Journal of Agricultural Education, the Journal of Industrial Teacher Education, and the Journal of Vocational Home Economics Education published in the early (1980-1983) and the late 1980s (1986-89). The researcher developed instrument used in this study consisted of four components: background information, statistical sophistication, problem area, and methodological strategy. Each article examined was classified into one of four problem areas: teacher, student, curriculum, and setting, as proposed by Steiner (1978). Each of these articles also was classified into one of four methodological strategies: laboratory experiment, field experiment, field study and ex post facto research, and survey, as used by Schwandt (1983). The three sophistication levels used to classify each statistical technique recorded were basic, intermediate, and advanced. The statistical sophistication level of a research report was determined by the highest level of sophistication among all techniques used in that report.;The results indicated that 30 different statistical techniques were used in the sample. The majority of research reports were classified as less than advanced in their levels of statistical sophistication. No significant changes were found in the use of statistical techniques nor did the statistical sophistication level of research change from the early 1980s to the late 1980s. The statistical sophistication of research was related to both problem areas studied and the methodological strategies used. The problem area most frequently studied was ""curriculum"". ""Student"" was the least studied problem area. Research on ""student"" tended to have a higher proportion classified as advanced statistical sophistication. ""Survey"" was found to be the most frequently identified strategy used. Very few research reports used the ""laboratory experiment"" strategy. Studies which used ""field studies and ex post facto research"" tended to have a larger proportion classified as advanced statistical sophistication than those which used ""experiments"" or ""survey"" strategies."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Chi Zhang.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-09, Section: A, page: 3255."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 97-106).</note>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Vocational education</topic>
      <topic>Research</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Vocational education</topic>
      <topic>Statistics</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Vocational education</topic>
      <topic>Statistical methods</topic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9207541</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28541249</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930730</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1200615</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 ZHAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9207541</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 ZHAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
