<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>impact of Latin American debt crisis on U.S., U.K., and Canadian bank stocks</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Jayanti, Subbarao V.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Business Administration.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateIssued>1991</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 250 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>261 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The 1980s have been a decade of crisis for banks engaged in international lending. This dissertation examines the impact of twelve events related to the Latin American debt crisis on the market value of the U.S., U.K., and Canadian bank stocks. The existing literature is extended in several directions. First, different types of events and several events of the same type are analyzed to enhance the generality of the conclusions. Second, a general theoretical framework involving two testable hypotheses is utilized to interpret the economic significance of the events. Third, the capital regulation hypothesis is tested extensively and it helped to clarify some of the ambiguities presented by earlier literature on the Mexican moratorium event. Fourth, the Generalized Autoregressive Conditional Heteroscedasticity (GARCH) model is used to address some of the problems associated with the Ordinary Least Squares (OLS) market model. These include nonnormalities, nonlinearities, and heteroscedasticity, and Cornell and Shapiro's criticism against use of event study methods for studying the impact of the debt crisis. Finally, the international dimension of the Latin American problem is recognized by extending the analysis to the British and the Canadian banks.;Most of the events produced significant event-day excess returns for the U.S. banks with Latin American loans. The market distinguished high-, medium-, and zero-exposure groups among banks. The four moratoria (Mexican, Argentinean, Bolivian, and Brazilian) as a class, produced strong and consistent results, although the underlying dynamics of the moratoria differed. This study provides perspective on the economic impact of capital regulation and demonstrates a link between external exogenous events and bank value.;The analysis suggests that the GARCH model does not make a significant difference to event study results. The results for the British and the Canadian banks differ somewhat from those for the U.S. banks. Differences in capital regulation in the three countries may explain the differential reaction of the three markets for the same set of events related to the Latin American debt crisis."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Subbarao V. Jayanti.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 52-09, Section: A, page: 3343."</note>
   <note>Vita.</note>
   <note>Abstract.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1991.</note>
   <note type="bibliography">Includes bibliographical references (leaves 240-247).</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">cl-----</geographicCode>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">e-uk---</geographicCode>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us---</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Debts, External</topic>
      <geographic>Latin America</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Bank stocks</topic>
      <geographic>United States</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Bank stocks</topic>
      <geographic>Great Britain</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject authority="lcsh">
      <topic>Bank stocks</topic>
      <geographic>Canada</geographic>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9207511</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1991</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">28560450</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">930803</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1201117</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1991 JAYA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9207511</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1991 JAYA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
