<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Injection of species under electrical field to enhance bioremediation</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Rabbi, Md. Fazle</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1965-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Civil and Environmental Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1997</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 220 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>221 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Electrokinetics is one of the most viable alternatives for injecting/extracting water, organic and ionic species in low permeability soils as well as heterogeneous media because the transport processes are independent of the pore sizes. A better understanding of the principles offers the opportunity to employ multi-component species transport under electrical fields to inject electron acceptors, nutrients and other process additives for enhancement of in-situ bioremediation in low permeability and heterogeneous media. This study assesses the potential to employ and exploit the principles of multi-component species transport under electrical fields as mean to supplement, enhance and engineer in-situ bioremediation. It was determined that ammonium, sulfate, nitrate and phosphate ions can be injected in different types of soils and in a layered deposit with significantly different hydraulic and electrical conductivities. Ions transport rates of 8 to 20 cm/day occurred under current densities of 15 to 150 mA/cm$\sp2$ and voltage gradients less than 1 V/cm. A uniform distribution of the process additives could be achieved across the electrodes. These results are quite encouraging and demonstrate that the electrokinetics injection scheme has significant potential for in-situ bioremediation in low permeability soil as well as heterogeneous media.;The transportability of the injected ions also depend on the charge concentration of the other competing ions on the pore fluid. The accumulation of these pore fluid ions in the system would decrease the transference number of the injected ions. The transportability of the injected ions could be increased by flushing intermittently or continuously the electrodes compartments to decrease the conductivity at the boundaries, which would increase the initial pore fluid ions to be flushed out from the system."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Md. Fazie Rabbi.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-01, Section: B, page: 3340.;Directors: Roger K. Seals; John H. Pardue."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, 1997.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9820748</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1997</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">38208971</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980114</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1918965</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1997 RABB</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9820748</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1997 RABB</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
