<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>conceptual and empirical approach for valueing biodiversity</title>
      <subTitle>an estimate of the benefits of plant and wildlife habitat preservation in the Tensas River Basin</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Isaacs, Jack Coburn</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1968-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana Agricultural Experiment Station</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Agricultural Economics and Agribusiness</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 226 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>227 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This research estimated the passive use value of local species biodiversity in the Tensas River basin, a section of the Lower Mississippi River Valley. This research employed the contingent valuation method in eliciting willingness to pay for biodiversity conservation using the habitat needs of an umbrella species as a basis for valuation.;This study designed and implemented the Lower Mississippi Valley Plant and Wildlife Survey for primary data collection. The sample included 1,351 households drawn from a hunting permit lottery conducted by the Tensas River National Wildlife Refuge and 3,044 households drawn at random from Louisiana, Arkansas, and Mississippi. The survey distinguished between area users and nonusers to examine differences in valuation.;In a probit analysis of the nonuser group's responses to a dichotomous choice willingness to pay question, the value of a biodiversity conservation program was positively related to the respondent's education, income, concern over loss of natural habitat, knowledge of the decline in species' numbers, and attitudes concerning the fragility of the nature. The value of biodiversity conservation was negatively correlated with the number of minors residing in the household. For the user sample, the value of biodiversity was positively related to the respondent's hunting skill, concern for the loss of wild habitat, and knowledge of the decline in plant and animal species. Due to evidence of structural differences between the nonuser and user sample, this study adopts the recommendation of Silberman, Gerlowski, and Williams (1992) to exclude users from passive use valuation.;This research conducted multinomial logit analysis to examine the distinction between respondents in the nonuser sample who provided positive, negative and uncertain responses. Positive responses were positively related to education, income, concern for the loss of natural habitat, knowledge of the decline in plant and animal species, and attitudes concerning the fragility of nature and negatively related to the number of minors in the household. Negative responses were negatively related to income, knowledge of the term ""biodiversity"", attitudes regarding the fragility of nature, and anti-anthropocentric attitudes. Uncertain responses were negatively related to knowledge of the decline in species' numbers."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Jack Coburn Isaacs.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-02, Section: A, page: 5680."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9824486</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">38571721</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980309</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919111</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 ISAA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9824486</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 ISAA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
