<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Numerical modeling of multi-species transport in soils under electric fields</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Zheng, Wenbing</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1963-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Civil and Environmental Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 199 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>200 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A generalized mathematical model for electrokinetic soil processing is presented for multi-species transport of reactive components under electric fields in two-dimensional geometry, based on the earlier Acar-Alshawabkeh model. In this model, sets of partial differential equations are formulated for the transport of fluid, charge, and species in a saturated soil under coupled hydraulic, electrical, and chemical potentials. Chemical reactions pertaining to sorption, precipitation/dissolution, aqueous phase equilibria, water autoionization, and electrolysis are included in the new model. The boundary conditions corresponding to the mass transport equations are described.;A program, EK-SIM (ElectroKinetic Soil Processing SIMulation), has been developed to simulate electrokinetic soil processing. The finite element method is used to solve the mass transport equations. Eight-node, quadrilateral isoparametric elements are used in space discretization. The finite difference technique is used in time discretization. The developed code is verified by comparison to one-dimensional analytical solutions of nonreactive chemical transport with Dirichlet and Neumann boundary conditions. The basic model predictions agree perfectly with the analytical solutions. The model has been further evaluated by comparison with a bench test of the electrokinetic injection of ammonium and sulfate ions into a sand bed to enhance bioremediation and a pilot-scale test of electrokinetic lead extraction from kaolinite. The model predictions are in reasonable agreement with the experimental results and the model successfully simulates the effects of chemical reactions on species transport in the unenhanced lead remediation test.;The developed model will provide a useful tool to attain a better fundamental scientific understanding of electrokinetic soil processing and for the design/analysis of full-scale, in situ applications."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Wenbing Zheng.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-02, Section: B, page: 7790.;Directors: Yalcin B. Acar; Roger K. Seals."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9824500</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">38576031</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980310</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919131</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 ZHEN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9824500</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 ZHEN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
