<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Assessing applicant "Fit" within the selection process</title>
      <subTitle>which interviewer perceptions matter?</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Haptonstahl, Dawn Ebe.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 94 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>95 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The research literature has noted that organizations are moving beyond simply hiring individuals with the necessary knowledge, skills, and abilities (KSAs) that fulfill the requirements of the job--employers are also looking for people who can fit in with a particular work group or even an entire organization. This study tested an exploratory model that predicted recruiter selection decisions from their evaluations of applicants' person-job (P-J), person-group (P-G), and person-organization (P-O) fit. The model also postulated that P-G and P-O fit would be predicted by the perceived congruence (similarity) of work values between applicants and groups/organizations, Hypotheses were field-tested with 64 recruiters from 44 companies who conducted 262 initial interviews with job applicants. As expected, the combination of P-J, P-G, and P-O fit explained a significant amount of variance in recruiter selection decisions, such as the likelihood that applicants would be invited for a second interview or would be recommended for hiring. All three types of fit contributed to the recruiter selection decisions, but ceiling effects and high multicollinearity among the fit ratings complicated interpretation of their individual contributions. Applicant qualification match with job requirements strongly predicted P-J fit. Perceived similarity in the work values of achievement, fairness, honesty, and concern for others between applicants and organizations significantly predicted P-O fit. Value congruence between applicants and groups likewise predicted P-G fit. Among the study's strengths was the use of Edwards' polynomial regression and three-dimensional response surface techniques, which allowed for both the relaxation of traditional constraints on equations and the interpretation of the complex relationships between applicant values, organization/group values, and perceptions of fit. Future research should move beyond the recruiting interview and attend to the importance of values and P-O and P-G fit in later stages of the selection process. Additional questions should focus on the impact of fit on criteria after applicants have accepted employment, such as performance, tenure, and rate of socialization."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Dawn Ebe Haptonstahl.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-02, Section: B, page: 9010."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9824483</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">38577835</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980310</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919128</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 HAPT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9824483</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 HAPT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
