<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Reproductive isolation between two species of Topminnow, Fundulus olivaceus and F. euryzonus</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Blanchard, Thomas A.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1965-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Biological Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 92 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>93 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Fundulus olivaceus and F. euryzonus are sister species that commonly occur syntopically in the Amite and Tangipahoa River drainages in Louisiana and Mississippi. Although the habitats of the two species are quite similar, and the timing of their reproductive activity overlaps extensively, no natural hybrids between them have been documented. I examined physiological, as well as behavioral, factors that could potentially serve as effective isolating mechanisms between them.;The courtship and spawning behaviors of the two species were relatively generalized and showed a number of similarities. Under forced mating conditions in which females were allowed to associate with heterospecific males only, hybrids from reciprocal crosses were produced, and hatchlings grew at rates similar to rates of hatchlings from conspecific matings. F$\sb1$ hybrids were fertile and produced F$\sb2$ hybrid hatchlings that also grew as well as conspecific hatchlings. Although both combinations of parental types produced hybrid offspring, fertilization success was significantly lower in crosses involving F. euryzonus females and F. olivaceus males. Additionally, eggs produced from that same combination hatched less successfully than eggs from either the other heterospecific combination or the two conspecific combinations. In laboratory experiments, the observed frequency of spawning sites was non-random for both F. euryzonus and F. olivaceus pairs. Fundulus euryzonus pairs tended to spawn in faster-moving water (mode = 10 cm sec$\sp{-1}$) than F. olivaceus pairs (mode = 1.4 cm sec$\sp{-1}$). Examination of mate preference revealed that although F. olivaceus females were not more likely to spawn with conspecifics, a significantly higher proportion of F. euryzonus females spawned with conspecific mates. Reproductive isolation between F. olivaceus and F. euryzonus is probably maintained in nature by a combination of behavioral (mate preference and spawning site selection) and ecological (small-scale distributional patterns) factors."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Thomas A. Blanchard.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-02, Section: B, page: 5550."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9824474</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">38577503</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980309</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919117</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 BLAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9824474</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 BLAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
