<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Atmosphere effects revisited</title>
      <subTitle>the effect of atmosphere on judgments of validity using thematic syllogisms</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Love, Roberta E. (Roberta Elizabeth)</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 116 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>116 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Syllogisms having conclusions consistent with atmosphere are shown to be accepted at significantly higher rates than those having conclusions inconsistent with atmosphere. Furthermore, there is strong evidence that the dual influences of quality and quantity, independently affect acceptance rates.;The first experiment also indicates a main effect of gender on acceptance rates to certain invalid syllogisms (those with conclusions inconsistent with quality, or quantity, or both). The second experiment replicates the atmosphere effect found in the first experiment and extends it to valid syllogisms and indeterminate invalids consistent with both quality and quantity. It also proposes an alternative to the misinterpreted necessity explanation for the logic by belief interaction. Both explanations are tested, and results indicate both are incomplete or incorrect. Evidence of a three way interaction of logic, belief, and consistency with atmosphere is reported.;The third experiment tests the effect of instructions on response patterns. Instructions stressing correct logical procedures for judging validity fail to significantly improve performance or affect mean belief bias for either valid or invalid syllogisms. This experiment also indicates a main effect of gender on belief bias.;The theoretical justification for an influence of consistency with atmosphere is proposed, as well as a model of syllogistic reasoning, which acknowledges the simultaneous influences of logic, believability, and consistency with atmosphere."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Roberta E. Love.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-06, Section: B, page: 3111."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9836887</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980522</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919333</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 LOVE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9836887</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 LOVE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
