<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Locus of reform</title>
      <subTitle>from reflection to effectiveness through the voices of novice teachers</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Caillouet, Patricia Babin.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Curriculum and Instruction.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 263 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>263 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This descriptive multiple-case qualitative study focused on the professional and personal experiences of five novice teachers--three preservice student teachers and two first-year teachers. Research conducted in two exemplary elementary schools examined the following questions: (a) How do preservice and first-year teachers use reflective practice and self-assessment to develop effective teaching practices? (b) How do the preservice and first-year teachers' approaches to effective literacy instruction compare? (c) Why does reflection not translate into effectiveness? and (d) How is effectiveness perceived in the professional, social school environment of novice teachers?;Results of the case studies determined that teacher education programs must go beyond providing their students with strong knowledge structures if new teachers are to survive in the trenches of public schools. Four assertions emerged in response to the research questions. First, reflection, a professional practice of self-assessment, requires initiation at the preservice level to insure integration into the classroom. Second, effectiveness is defined by approved practices of respected supervisors implemented through the individual personality preferences of inexperienced teachers. Third, reflection-in-practice is a difficult concept to internalize and requires the experience and confidence of purposeful, continuous practice. Finally, professionalization is dependent on school placement and influenced by the culture of that school.;Results impact the teacher education program of these preservice students and inservice programs for new teachers and mentors. If competent, professional classroom teachers drive educational reform, the voices of these novice teachers provide insight into tools for success."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Patricia Babin Caillouet.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-06, Section: A, page: 1980."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9836858</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980520</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919302</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 CAIL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9836858</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 CAIL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
