<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>effects of gender and race on physician treatment of patient emotion</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>DeCoster, Vaughn A.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Sociology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 163 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>163 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study established theoretical and empirical foundations for the investigation into how physicians deal with (treat) patient emotion. The questions posed, ""Do physicians employ specific strategies to treat patient emotion?"" and ""What are the effects of physician-patient social characteristics (gender and race) on emotion treatment?"" Coalescing two seemingly incongruent perspectives (social constructionism and Kemper's social relational theory), I clarified the conceptual basis for the emotion management of other people. From these perspectives, I developed a three stage theory to describe and explain the physician treatment of patient emotion (triaging, diagnosing, and treatment), as well as appreciate the effects of social characteristics on this process.;Regarding the first research question, survey data collected from 225 practicing physicians supported the twenty-two proposed strategies to treat patient emotion. Considering the second question, analyses produced some support for the predicted effects of gender and race. For physician gender, female physicians were, in general, more likely to treat patient emotion than their male colleagues. However, physician gender was only significant when the physicians' type of medical practice (general vs. specialized) and practice setting (private vs. institutional) were controlled in the analysis model, suggesting that physician gender differences were more complex than those based exclusively on sex. For patient gender and race, analysis indicated that physicians randomly assigned black patient vignettes had significantly higher scores on measures of emotion evading and lower scores for emotion importance than physicians with white patients. This suggests that a patient's social characteristics do influence physician treatment of patient emotion. Overall, my research demonstrates a growing ideological acceptance and consideration for the role of emotion in medicine, whether this is occurring in actual practice remains unknown."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Vaughn A. DeCoster.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-06, Section: B, page: 3119."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9836865</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980522</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919335</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 DECO</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9836865</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 DECO</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
