<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Pest status of the fall armyworm, Spodoptera frugiperda (J.E. Smith), on conventional and transgenic cotton expressing the Bacillus thuringiensis CryIA (c) ơ-Endotoxin</title>
      <subTitle>development, survival, and host-strain influence</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Adamczyk, John Joseph</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1970-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Entomology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 74 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>74 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The pest status of the fall armyworm, Spodoptera frugiperda (J. E. Smith), including development and survival on conventional and transgenic Bacillus thuringiensis (Bt) cotton and host-strain influences, was examined in laboratory and field studies. Neonates (1st instars) were fed leaves from conventional (cv. DP 5415 and cv. DP 5690) and transgenic Bt (cv. NuCOTN 33$\rm\sp{B}$ and cv. NuCOTN 35$\rm\sp{B})$ cotton. There were no significant differences $(P&gt;0.05)$ between cultivars in larval mortality and survival to the pupal and adult stages. However, times to pupation and adult eclosion were significantly longer $(P&lt;0.05)$ for larvae fed transgenic Bt cotton compared to conventional cotton. In addition, larvae weighed significantly less $(P&lt;0.05)$ when fed transgenic Bt cotton compared to conventional cotton.;A study was conducted to determine when cotton bolls become tolerant to fall armyworm injury. Fifth instars were caged individually on bolls of various ages from conventional (cv. DP 5415) and transgenic Bt (cv. NuCOTN 33$\rm\sp{B})$ cotton to define the period of boll susceptibility to larval injury. For DP 5415 bolls, there was no significant linear relationship $(P&gt;0.05)$ describing larval mortality or successful boll penetration as a function of boll age. Larvae were able to successfully penetrate ($&gt;$60%) DP 5415 bolls throughout boll development. For NuCOTN 33$\rm\sp{B}$ bolls, there was a significant linear relationship $(P&lt;0.05)$ describing larval mortality (increased as bolls developed) or successful boll penetration (decreased as bolls developed) as a function of boll age. Larvae were able to successfully penetrate ($&gt;$40%) NuCOTN 33$\rm\sp{B}$ bolls at 350 heat-units.;Studies were conducted to determine if there were differences in susceptibility between the two host-associated fall armyworm strains to conventional (cv. DP 5415 and cv. DP 5690) or transgenic Bt (cv. NuCOTN 33$\rm\sp{B}$ and cv. NuCOTN 35$\rm\sp{B})$ cotton or to selected insecticides. Fall armyworms collected from various forage grasses were consistently more susceptible to conventional cotton, transgenic Bt cotton, and selected insecticides than larvae collected from field corn.;The utility of the sodium channel para locus to distinguish fall armyworm host-associated strains also was addressed. Genetic differentiation in the para locus was not correlated with host-associated strains. However, results suggest that this molecular marker is useful for distinguishing closely related Spodoptera spp."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by John Joseph Adamczyk, Jr.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-06, Section: B, page: 2550."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9836849</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">39150923</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980520</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate encoding="iso8601">20090521094517.0</recordChangeDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919284</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 ADAM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9836849</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 ADAM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
