<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Evaluating the impacts of farmer participation in the wetland reserve program on the Louisiana economy using I-O, SAM, and CGE as alternative modeling techniques</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Olatubi, Williams Olubodunde.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana Agricultural Experiment Station</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Agricultural Economics and Agribusiness.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 268 leaves : ill., maps ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>269 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"In the U.S., wetlands are one of the resources that have been adversely affected by development in agriculture. In response, and in order to protect wetlands as vital environmental resource, the federal government initiated several agriculture-related environmental protection programs, such as swamp buster, the Conservation Reserve Program (CRP), and the Wetlands Reserve Program (WRP).;The WRP is an incentive-based program designed to encourage farmers to reconvert appropriate cropland to wetlands through subsidy payments. Because land is withdrawn from agricultural production, regions with relatively high participation rates, such as Louisiana, could experience adverse economic impacts from the program. As of August 1996, about $39 million in subsidy cash payments have been paid to farmers for easement, restoration, and maintenance activities on 65,000 acres.;Previous studies of similar programs have utilized fixed-price models, especially input-output (I-O) models, to evaluate regional impacts. In addition to being limited in scope, these studies relied on models with stringent assumptions without consideration of other alternative models with the potential for different results.;In this study, the three most common regional impact analysis models--input-output (I-O), social accounting matrix (SAM), and computable general equilibrium (CGE)--were developed for Louisiana and used to evaluate the impact of the WRP in the state. Direct impacts of the program were captured using a combination of geographic information system (GIS), Environmental Policy Integrated Climate (EPIC) model, and published and unpublished data.;Model results show that the impacts of the program on the state economy were marginal in terms of output, income, and changes in price levels. In spite of the marginal impacts predicted here, results indicate that the impact of the program may be different at higher levels of participation and when the analysis is restricted only to participating regions or parishes. In general, the SAM yielded the largest impact estimate followed by the I-O, with the CGE yielding the smallest change. Regional economic analysts should be cautious in choosing particular regional model because results may differ markedly. For example, results from the CGE model differed in the predicted direction of change from the other regional models."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Williams Olubodunde Olatubi.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-08, Section: A, page: 3117."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9902655</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980805</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919613</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 OLAT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9902655</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 OLAT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
