<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Essays on panel unit root procedures</title>
      <subTitle>applications to the convergence hypothesis, PPP and UCIP</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Lopcu, Kenan.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Economics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 89 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>90 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The first two essays in this dissertation deal with the empirical examination of growth, specifically with the reexamination of convergence. The first essay introduces the issue and provides the preliminary results. Most of the empirical studies on the determinants of economic growth use cross-country analysis, employing long-term averages of relevant variables on each country. In these studies a negative relationship between average growth rates and initial incomes is interpreted as an indication of convergence in cross-country incomes and therefore, presented as evidence in support of neoclassical growth models. Such an analysis, however, ignores dynamic information that can explain part of the variation in growth rates. Furthermore, Quah (1993a) and Evans (1996) show that inferences from cross-country regressions regarding convergence are misleading. An alternative approach, based on unit root tests in panel data, suggests that income differences are persistent even after allowing for country specific differences.;The second essay modifies the hypothesis to test the implications of endogenous growth models. Stability tests indicate that performance of developing countries has worsened in the post-1973 period. The results indicate an unambiguous convergence only within OECD. This essay also illustrates that using log income differences rather than levels shifts the distribution toward convergence.;The dissertation is completed by a third essay that examines the PPP, UCIP and constancy of real rates of return across a large number of countries using the methodology introduced in the first essay. Findings support all these parities, indicating the failure of earlier studies to confirm these hypotheses is likely the result of low power of standard unit root and cointegration tests."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Kenan Lopcu.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-08, Section: A, page: 3100."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9902647</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">39650928</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980806</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate encoding="iso8601">20090521100142.0</recordChangeDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919593</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 LOPC</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9902647</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 LOPC</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
