<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Concurrent vs. terminal augmented feedback in the learning of a discrete bimanual coordination task</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Hadden, Cynthia Marie</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Kinesiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xviii, 322 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>322 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Two experiments compared the effects of concurrent and terminal augmented feedback in learning a bimanual coordination task. In the first experiment, twenty-four participants practiced a discrete bimanual task that required a 90$\sp\circ$ phase offset of the upper limbs under one of two feedback conditions: concurrent or terminal. Participants in the concurrent feedback group received feedback as they performed the task during acquisition. Participants in the terminal feedback group received feedback after they completed each acquisition trial. Results indicated that concurrent group was able to more accurately produce the target figure during acquisition than the terminal group. Unlike earlier studies which employed single-limb tasks and which showed that terminal participants outperform concurrent participants in retention, there was no significant difference between the two groups on transfer tests with no feedback. In fact, although the difference was not significant, participants in the concurrent group performed better than participants in the terminal group during these retention tests. In the second experiment, forty-eight participants practiced the same task under one of four conditions: concurrent, terminal, transition, and control. Concurrent and terminal feedback groups received feedback as in Experiment 1. Transition and control groups received concurrent feedback during the first two blocks of acquisition. During the remainder of acquisition, the transition group received terminal feedback and the control group received no feedback. Results indicated that the control group performed less accurately than the other three groups during acquisition. On transfer tests with no feedback, the performance of the concurrent group deteriorated such that it approached the performance of the control group. The transition and terminal groups were more accurate than the control group. The results of this experiment support previous research which has found that the presentation of concurrent feedback, as opposed to terminal feedback, enhances performance during acquisition but hinders long-term retention. The results of this dissertation demonstrate that there are some conditions under which concurrent augmented feedback can be effective for learning. These findings support the hypothesis by Lee, Swinnen and Serrien (1994) that augmented feedback is most useful when it assists the learner in interpreting intrinsic sources of feedback."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Cynthia Marie Hadden.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-08, Section: A, page: 2902."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9902637</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">39650962</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980805</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919592</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 HADD</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9902637</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 HADD</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
