<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Diagnosis of poor PDC bit performance in deep shales</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Smith, John Rogers</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1949-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Petroleum Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 333 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>334 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study was performed to diagnose the cause of poor PDC bit performance in deep, overpressured shales. Deep, overpressured wells account for a disproportionate share of all drilling costs, about 27 percent. The effect of bit performance on this cost is significant, about $2.9 billion annually in overpressured formations alone. Bit performance in deep, overpressured formations when using water-based muds is especially poor, adding at least \$500 million annually to worldwide drilling costs. This problem is described as the slow drilling shale problem and is shown to exist worldwide.;Potential causes of this problem identified in the technical literature include various kinds of balling, strong rock within shaly intervals, confining pressure effects, chip hold-down effects, and shale plasticity. The strategy of this study is to identify the characteristic symptoms of the actual problem in the field and to match them to the symptoms resulting from different possible causes in controlled laboratory tests.;Field data in an area identified as exemplitting the problem was reviewed to develop reliable symptoms. Seven bit runs had adequate drilling and log data for detailed analysis that yielded examples of effective and ineffective performance and their respective symptoms. Ineffective performance was confirmed to occur principally in shales. Full scale laboratory drilling tests confirmed that similar symptoms could be reproduced in a laboratory environment using outcrop shales. The range of physical and mineralogical characteristics of deep, overpressured shales was determined, and outcrop rocks were acquired that represent a similar range.;Single cutter tests were the cornerstone of this study. The tests allowed differentiation of several of the possible causes, and observation of whether there was any evidence that a particular cause actually occurred during a test. Global bit balling, cutter balling, confining pressure effects, and a strong rock were all explicitly tested with single cutter experiments. Global bit balling was shown to be the principal cause of the slow drilling shale problem. Although all of the other effects also impede bit performance, only global balling caused all of the symptoms observed in the field. Conventional laboratory tests were also performed to better understand the problem."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by John Rogers Smith.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-08, Section: B, page: 4436."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9902666</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980805</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919612</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 SMIT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9902666</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 SMIT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
