<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Building-based councils' influence on school policy in Lafayette Parish</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Manuel, Nancy Williamson.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Educational Leadership, Research, and Counseling.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 194 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>195 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purpose of this study was to explore whether the decision making authority of School Improvement Councils (SIC), teacher dominant, and/or Parent Advisory Councils (PAC) addresses and affects personnel, program, and budget building policy. The basic research question was, ""How do shared governance councils operate?"".;This study approached the problem through mixed methodology strategy of research, using both quantitative and qualitative techniques. Phase One of the study involved quantitative methods that gathered data from a large sample of teachers and administrators. Phase Two involved qualitative interviews of a teacher, an administrator, and a parent that helped to confirm the initial findings and provide more in-depth detail.;This study was a replication of a study done by Malen &amp; Ogawa in 1988. They discovered that a pecking order in decision making influence existed in which principals controlled the decisions of the councils and are often joined by teachers in an attempt to exclude parents.;In comparing this study to Malen &amp; Ogawa's (1988), two differences were noted. First, administrators are beginning to relinquish some decision making powers, as indicated by the official enactment of decisions in the area of programming. Second, parents are beginning to be included, rather than excluded, in the decision making arenas. Evidence of this lies in the fact that all eight of the sample schools have parents on the SICs and four of the eight schools have implemented Parent Advisory Councils.;Qualitative results indicated that the most significant impact that SICs have in the shared decision making process is in the overall programming area. Budget and personnel were topics of discussion at SIC meetings; however, no official enactments occurred. Thus, the researcher found that as the influence of teachers and parents on building-based councils increased, there was an increase in the success of school policies impacted by council decisions in the area of programming."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">Nancy Williamson Manuel.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-10, Section: A, page: 3706."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9909829</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">39911526</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980922</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919775</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 MANU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9909829</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 MANU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
