<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Reverse engineering biological control systems for applications in process control</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>McLain, Richard Brian</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1965-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemical Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 178 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>179 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The main emphasis of this dissertation is the development of nonlinear control strategies based on biological control systems. Commonly utilized biological control schemes have been studied in order to ""reverse engineer"" the important concepts for applications in process control. This approach has led to the development of a nonlinear habituating control strategy and nonlinear model reference adaptive control schemes.;Habituating control is a controller design strategy for nonlinear systems with more manipulated inputs than controlled outputs. Nonlinear control laws that provide input-output linearization while simultaneously minimizing the cost of affecting control are derived. Local stability analysis shows the controller can provide a simple solution to singularity and non-minimum phase problems.;A direct adaptive control strategy for a class of single-input, single-output non-linear systems is presented. The major advantage is that a detailed dynamic non-linear model is not required for controller design. Unknown controller functions in the associated input-output linearizing control law are approximated using locally supported radial basis functions. Lyapunov stability analysis is used to derive parameter update laws which ensure the state vector remains bounded and the plant output asymptotically tracks the output of a linear reference model.;A nonlinear model reference adaptive control strategy in which a linear model (or multiple linear models) is embedded within the nonlinear controller is presented. The nonlinear control law is constructed by embedding linear controller gains derived from models obtained using standard linear system identification techniques within the associated input-output linearizing control law. Higher-order controller functions are approximated with radial basis functions. Lyapunov stability analysis is used to derive stable parameter update laws.;The major disadvantage of the previous techniques is computational expense. Two modifications have been developed. First, the effective dimension is reduced by applying nonlinear principal component analysis to the state variable data obtained from open-loop tests. This allows basis functions to be placed in a lower dimensional space than the original state space. Second, the total number of basis functions is fixed a priori and an algorithm which adds/prunes basis function centers to surround the current operating point on-line is utilized."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">Richard Brian McLain.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 59-10, Section: B, page: 5474."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9909830</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">39903184</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">980921</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919760</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 MCLA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9909830</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 MCLA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
