<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Measurement of the cross section for elastic scattering of electron neutrinos on electrons</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Wadia, Neville D.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1970-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Physics and Astronomy.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 155 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>156 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"In this dissertation, we measure the cross section for the elastic scattering of electron neutrinos on electrons. We use data from the LSND experiment which is located at the Los Alamos Neutron Scattering Center at Los Alamos National Laboratory, New Mexico. The neutrino beam is produced when an 800 MeV proton beam from a linear accelerator is incident on a target located 29.8 m from the detector. The LSND veto system allows us to reject charged cosmic-ray particles entering the detector with high efficiency. The detector consists of 180 tons of mineral oil, to which a small quantity of scintillator is added. This combination enables us to detect both Cerenkov and scintillation light produced by highly relativistic charged particles. For the neutrino-electron elastic scattering process, we detect the recoil electron and require it to be scattered along the direction of the incident neutrino. This requirement has a large acceptance for the elastic scattering events while at the same time it reduces the background due to other processes. We obtain 133 +/- 22 events for the   nee-&amp;rarr;nee - process and measure a cross section, sigma = [11.6 +/- 1.9( stat.) +/- 1.4(syst.)] x   Ene  (MeV) x 10-45cm2, for this reaction. The average energy of the nue beam at LSND is 31.7 MeV. A feature of this reaction is that it can proceed through either charged current or neutral current interactions. The standard model of electroweak interactions predicts a destructive interference between these two channels which leads to a reduction in the cross section from its value had there been no interference. We measure the strength of this destructive interference, I = -0.88 +/- 0.22(stat .) +/- 0.11(syst.), and compare it to a value of I = -1.08 predicted by the standard model of electroweak interactions."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Neville D. Wadia.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: B, page: 1142."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922123</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40652171</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990119</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919976</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 WADI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922123</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 WADI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
