<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Spatial variability of coastal organic soil characteristics</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Dharmasri,  L. Cecil (Langappulige Cecil)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1961-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Agronomy.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 249 leaves : ill., maps, (some col.) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>250 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation is a part of the Louisiana NASA/EPSCoR (Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research) global change research, which studied the fate of carbon and sediments within the Barataria Bay Basin, Louisiana. It studied water composition to assess seawater influence within the marsh. Ion exchange resin strips were used to study the effect of salinity and Chloride (Cl) on sulfate (SO4) reduction and their potential for water and soil analysis. Chloride dominated the water system and the Cl/SO 4 ratio can be used to assess the seawater influence. Resin extractable sulfur (S) predicted non-pyritic S fraction for the marsh soils. High salinity reduced the affinity of target ions onto the resin. Limited affinity of SO 4 to resin indicates SO4 accumulation within root zone, which promotes sulfate reduction and pyrite formation.;This project mainly studied landscape position and salinity effects on pyrite accumulation and the spatial variability of soil characteristics within a saline and a brackish marsh. Salinity, pyrite, and non-pyritic iron (Fe) and S varied between streamside and inland. Depressions in mineral layer, accretion variations and associated hydrology caused the field-scale variability. When the inland site is landlocked, salinity and pyrite content within the surface horizon varied. Non-pyritic S, pH, and pyrite profiles were different in different marsh types. Mineralogical evidence also found for presence of pyrite framboids. These soils should be reclassified to indicate accumulations of reduced sulfur.;Thickness of subsurface horizons was highly spatially variable. Variation in depth to mineral layer (DML) can be due to the presence of depressions in the mineral layer surface. Typic Medisaprists occurred mostly toward inland areas and away from waterways at the saline marsh. The DML was shallower for the degrading marsh within the saline marsh type. Typic Medisaprists within the brackish marsh had thick organic layers due to presence of thick subhorizons. Spatial variability is evident for pH and organic/mineral ratio (OMR) within organic subhorizons. The OMR data varied widely for the brackish marsh compared to saline marsh. Organic soil characteristics vary spatially due to variations in associated processes, therefore, spatial variability should be considered for soil sampling schemes."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by L. Cecil Dharmasri.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: B, page: 9000."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922073</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40650274</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990113</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919897</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 DHAR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922073</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 DHAR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
