<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Ultrafast studies of reaction dynamics</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Feng, Zhenguo</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1964-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemical Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 124 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>125 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The long range goal of this research is to understand the role of the solvent in condensed phase reactions. In the gas phase, great strides have been made towards understanding chemical reactivity at the level of individual quantum states. Liquid state reactions are not as well understood due to complicated many-body interactions with the solvent.;Our approach has been to study simple reactions in solvents near their critical state. Here a small change in pressure, at constant temperature, allows a continuous change in solvent bulk density and viscosity, from near-liquid to gas-like properties. In this way reactions can be studied across the interface between gas phase behavior and the poorly understood liquid state.;In addition to chemical reactivity, the research directly investigated solvent structure and dynamics in the supercritical state. The unique solvent properties of supercritical fluids (SCFs) are the basis for SCF extractions and chromatography. Microscopic details of the fluid structure and dynamics have a direct bearing on the solubility and reaction behavior of these fluids.;The high-intensity of the generated ultrafast pulses (0.01 to 60 GW/cm 2) necessitated the need to investigate the phenomenon of nonlinear absorption. Initial studies were performed on one-dimensional polydiacetylene polymer films. Mechanisms involving two-photon absorption were developed for explanation the new finding.;The available high power in the femtosecond experimental system allowed investigation of solvent molecular relaxation processes. Using the Optical Kerr Gate technique, the nonlinear index of refraction and femtosecond molecular relaxation processes for carbon dioxide in the vapor, liquid and supercritical states were determined.;The reaction dynamics DODCI (3,3'-diethyloxadicarbocynine) isomerization were investigated. The pathway of the rapid (fs-ps) excited state isomerization followed was clarified. A Kramers turnover was observed for the slow (us-ms) ground state isomerization. These two widely different time scales each provide unique information on solvent effect."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Zhenguo Feng.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: B, page: 1192."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922076</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40651329</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990113</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919909</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 FENG</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922076</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 FENG</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
