<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>study of pore fluids and barite deposits from hydrocarbon seeps</title>
      <subTitle>deepwater Gulf of Mexico</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Fu, Baoshun</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1963-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geology and Geophysics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xvi, 275 leaves : ill., (some col.) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>276 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The primary goals of this research were to (i) determine the factors controlling the chemical compositions of pore fluids in hydrocarbon seep sediments of the Gulf of Mexico, and (ii) delineate the nature, age and origin of barite deposits associated with seeps.;Three types of pore fluids from seeps have been discerned: (i) sediment-trapped seawater; (ii) brines derived by seawater dissolution of subsurface salt diapirs; and (iii) deep-seated formation waters enriched in Ba and Ra. The Ra-enriched formation waters advecting to the seafloor may explain why  226Ra levels in the Gulf of Mexico water column are higher than in the inflowing Caribbean Sea waters.;Microbial sulfate reduction exerts a major control on the origin and distribution of authigenic carbonates in seeps. Sulfate reduction using methane in sediments underlying mussel beds exhibits higher reduction rates than those using crude oil in bacterial mats. Consequently, pore fluids in mussel beds are highly supersaturated with respect to aragonite, calcite and high-Mg calcite, whereas most pore fluids from bacterial mats are undersaturated. These results are consistent with the observation that authigenic carbonates are often associated with mussel beds but rarely occur in bacterial mats.;Hydrocarbon seeps serve as a convenient natural laboratory for investigating stable isotope fractionations resulting from microbial sulfate reduction. The calculated fractionation factors in seeps range from 1.009 to 1.026 for sulfur and 1.002 to 1.014 for oxygen, and are controlled by sulfate reduction rates. In contrast to previous investigations which found a fixed 4/1 delta 34S/delta18O ratio during sulfate reduction, this study indicates that the ratio also varies with reduction rates.;The seep barites occur as chimneys and crusts. The chimneys are 0.5 to 6.5 years old and their estimated growth rates vary from 4.4 cm/yr to 9.1 cm/yr, whereas the crusts are 9.0 to 23.1 years old. Sulfur, oxygen and strontium isotope compositions suggest that the chimneys formed at or above the sediment-water interface by mixing of sulfate-rich seawater with Ba-, Sr-, and Ra-rich formation fluids seeping with hydrocarbons. The crusts precipitated below the sediment-water interface by mixing of the formation fluids with residual seawater sulfate depleted by sulfate-reducing bacteria."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Baoshun Fu.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: B, page: 9940."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922077</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40651358</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990114</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919913</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 FU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922077</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 FU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
