<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Quantifying sustainability in aquaculture production</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Caffey, Rex Hall</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1965-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Forestry, Wildlife, and Fisheries.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xvi,  218 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>219 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Despite increasing institutional focus in aquaculture, sustainability remains an amorphous and much debated concept. Little consensus has been identified on the issue beyond the general recognition that the concept should contain environmental, economic, and sociological considerations. This study addressed the specific, relevant question of whether politically diverse aquacuiture interests can collectively develop and agree on production-level goals and indicators of aquaculture sustainability.;The research partitioned sustainability into its three subcategories: environmental, economic and social. This division facilitated the use of existing conventions of measurement and expression in each subcategory. Employing a modified Delphi technique, over 100 aquaculture stakeholders in the Southeastern U. S. were surveyed for the purpose of identifying and refining indicators of aquaculture sustainability. Aquaculture producers, researchers, regulators, and members of non-governmental organizations participating in a three-round Delphi survey and collectively identified 31 indicators of aquaculture sustainability. Survey participants provided 1,622 items for consideration as potential indicators in round 1. These items were condensed by similarity into 31 indicators and returned to the panel for comment in rounds 2 and 3.;Non-parametric statistical analysis of the survey data indicated a high level of panel agreement by the final round of the survey. Significant levels of ordinal rank correlation were detected using Friedman's randomized block design (alpha = 0.05). Increasing levels of rank convergence were detected by high values for Kendall's statistic of concordance (  W&amp;sim;0.65. .;Indicators were arranged into preliminary sub-indices of environmental, economic, and sociological sustainability. Sub-indices were combined into an overall index based on a trigonometric approach that expresses aquaculture sustainability as the ratio of case study and optimal vectors, with a relevant scoring range of --100 to 100. The resulting model is referred to as a multi-criteria index of Delphi-assessed sustainability (MIDAS). A 50-hectare, owner operated simulation was used to initialize case studies with channel catfish (Ictalurus punctatus) and crawfish (Procambaraus clarkii) and (Procambarus zonagulus). Case study scores ranged from 18 to 24 for crawfish and channel catfish production, respectively. With further refinement, to index has potential for production level evaluations of aquaculture sustainability in the Southeastern United States."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Rex Hall Caffey.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: B, page: 8870."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922058</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40651255</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990114</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919926</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 CAFF</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922058</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 CAFF</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
