<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Factors determining University enrollment status</title>
      <subTitle>the case of high school students recruited to attend Louisiana State University College of Agriculture</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Nafukho, Fredrick Muyia.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Vocational  Education.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 155 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>156 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purpose of this study was to determine whether a model existed that significantly increased the researcher's ability to accurately explain whether or not a recruited student in the College of Agriculture at LSU will enroll based upon the current recruitment strategies.;The target population for this study consisted of 1,130 prospective freshmen recruited to attend the College of Agriculture in the fall 1997. A comparison of students who resided on the College of Agriculture's 1997 prospective freshmen data base, with the university undergraduate data base gave an accessible population of 226 students. The actual sample size was determined using Cochran's formula for categorical data to be 143. Since complete data on all the variables for the subjects in the accessible population was obtained, all 226 subjects were studied.;The instrument used in this study was a computerized recording form. Data were collected by copying the variables of interest from university undergraduate admissions and the College of Agriculture data bases.;Results showed that substantively and statistically significant models exist which enhanced the researcher's ability to accurately explain enrollment status. The variable which had the highest correlations with enrollment was the dollar amount of scholarships awarded to the student. Discriminant analysis was used to determine models that explained the subject's enrollment status. The lowest total percent correctly classified was on the most efficient model at 80.09%. The comprehensive model correctly classified 85.84% of the cases; the comprehensive recruitment model correctly classified 83.19% of the cases. Variables which made significant contributions to the model included: the dollar amount awarded to the student, whether or not the student received a scholarship, whether or not the student came from within Louisiana, and whether or not the student received a departmental scholarship. Financial aid, geographic location, college mail, campus visitation programs and outreach programs were found to be essential recruitment activities.;The refinement of the model and the need to apply it at the departmental level was recommended. Rigorous research of this nature should be conducted to improve the science of enrollment management."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Fredrick Muyia Nafukho.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: A, page: 6210."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922103</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40657721</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990119</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919969</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 NAFU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922103</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 NAFU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
