<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Purification of porphobilinogen deaminase and the sequencing and expression of the hemC gene of Rhodobacter capsulatus</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Canada, Keith A. (Keith Allen)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1970-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Biological Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix,118 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>119 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Rhodobacter capsulatus uses the common tetrapyrrole pathway to synthesize heme, bacteriochlorophyll, siroheme and vitamin B-12. As part of our studies on the regulation of this pathway, the product of the hemC gene, porphobilinogen deaminase was purified approximately 200-fold. The molecular weight, isoelectric point, pH optimum and Km of the enzyme were all similar to other porphobilinogen deaminases. The stoichiometry of the enzyme was found not to be the expected four porphobilinogens used per one uroporphyrin formed. Rather a 9:1 ratio was typically seen. Further study of this atypical ratio uncovered evidence of possible in vivo regulation of porphobilinogen deaminase dependant on the cellular redox state. The protein was isolated from a two-dimensional gel and the sequence of the first twenty amino acids from the N-terminus was determined. This protein sequence matched a putative amino acid sequence 110 bp upstream of the R. capsulatus hemE gene. The putative hemC locus was subcloned from the plasmid pCAP154 which contains the  R. capsulatus hemE gene with 1.2 Kb of upstream DNA. The sequence of the upstream DNA was determined by dideoxy sequencing of both strands. A single open reading frame of 951 bp was found which could code for a 317 amino acid protein of 34,082 Da. The putative protein has 49% identity with the E. coli porphobilinogen deaminase and 44% identity with the B. subtilis enzyme. When a plasmid carrying the  R. capsulatus hemC was inserted into E. coli and  R. capsulatus, a four-fold and ten-fold increase in porphobilinogen deaminase activity was seen respectively. The DNA sequence revealed that the  hemC and hemE genes are divergently transcribed. A palindrome was identified between the two start sites, 47 bp upstream of  hemE and 42 bp upstream of hemC. This palindrome, found upstream of many R. capsulatus genes, has been proposed to be a transcriptional regulatory site. The effects of oxygen on the transcription of hemC were studied using a hemC-cat fusion vector. Under the conditions tested, oxygen had no effect on the transcription of the R. capsulatus hemC gene."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Keith A. Canada.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: B, page: 9470."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph. D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922062</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40651493</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">LUU</recordContentSource>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990120</recordCreationDate>
      <recordChangeDate encoding="iso8601">20090521101132.0</recordChangeDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919950</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 CANA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922062</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 CANA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
