<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Biology and ecology of the Anopheles quadrimaculatus sibling species complex in Louisiana</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Rutledge, Cynthia Roxanne.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Entomology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 71 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>72 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A polymerase chain reaction method for identifying individuals in the  Anopheles quadrimaculatus Say sibling species complex was validated for wild mosquitoes from Louisiana and Mississippi. This method distinguished  An. quadrimaculatus species A, B, C, and D by detecting species-specific differences in the 2nd internal transcribed spacer of ribosomal DNA and was 100% specific and 95% sensitive.;A polymerase chain reaction assay that detects differences in the second internal transcribed spacer of ribosomal DNA was tested for its usefulness in identifying all immature stages of two representatives in the  An. quadrimaculatus sibling species complex. The technique was successful in amplifying DNA from eggs, 1st through 4th instars, and pupae of  An. quadrimaculatus Say and An. inundatus Reinert.;Attempts were made to colonize four of the five sibling species of the Quadrimaculatus Complex. Field-collected mosquitoes were brought into the laboratory to use as starting material for colonies. No colonies were established during this study. The approach taken for this research was too broad and a better approach would be to spend more time on one of the species and study a select, small number of natural populations.;Sixteen larval habitats of sibling species of An. quadrimaculatus  were characterized during 1997--98. Larval mosquitoes were identified using PCR. Habitat descriptions were made along with water analysis for inorganic ions. Anopheles quadrimaculatus Say was present in fifteen of the sites. Anopheles smaragdinus larvae were not collected from any site. Anopheles inundatus was the only species collected from one habitat, and was found in association with  An. quadrimaculatus at another site. Anopheles maverlius  was collected along with An. quadrimaculatus from one larval habitat. The water analysis from the different habitats could not be statistically compared due to a lack of locating a larger number of sites with species other than An. quadrimaculatus.;Sixty-two mosquitoes were tested for the presence of the intracellular parasite Wolbachia pipientis which causes cytoplasmic incompatibility in some species of insects. Using an established PCR protocol, the rickettsia was not detected in any of the specimens."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Cynthia Roxanne Rutledge.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: B, page: 9330."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <subject>
      <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us-la</geographicCode>
   </subject>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922114</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40662274</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990119</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919973</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 RUTL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922114</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 RUTL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
