<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Teacher selection practices in effective elementary schools which differ by community type and socioeconomic status context</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Westbrook, Amy Barham.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Administrative and Foundational Services.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vi, 249 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>250 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The current study investigated teacher selection in elementary schools which differ by school type, community type, and socioeconomic status (SES). The qualities sought, procedures utilized, and problems encountered by principals during teacher selection were examined. Statistical analyses were used to determine whether school types differ significantly on variables regarding teacher selection.;The present study involved collecting both qualitative and quantitative data, and was conducted in four phases. In Phase I, all elementary schools in the state were classified by community type, student body SES, and ""effective"" and ""typical"" status.;Phase II consisted of 12 site visits to ""effective"" schools which differed by community and SES contexts. Principals and teacher interviews were conducted, and the ""effectiveness"" of the schools was verified via classroom observations.;Phase III utilized interview data to develop and pilot a questionnaire that was distributed across the various ""effective"" school contexts. Finally, in Phase IV, the questionnaire was distributed to principals of ""effective"" and ""typical"" schools, and the data were analyzed to address research questions regarding teacher selection.;The quantitative data analyses revealed that there are differences between the qualities that principals of effective and typical schools seek. Also, there are differences regarding problems encountered between principals of low- and middle-SES schools.;The qualitative data revealed findings regarding qualities with respect to classroom management, creativity, flexibility, concern for children, and enthusiasm. A teachers' teaching background, ability to get along with others, and believing that children can learn as well as whether a teacher is a parent and a teacher's morals and values are discussed.;With regard to procedures utilized, the qualitative data revealed findings with respect to checking references, observing a teacher, recruiting student teachers, and using a relaxed talk and hypothetical questions. Also, contacting references, especially past principals, investigating personnel files, and using a selection committee are highlighted.;Regarding problems encountered, one mainly associated with middle-SES schools and five associated with low-SES schools were highlighted. Also, several problems associated with central office involvement are discussed."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Amy Barham Westbrook.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-03, Section: A, page: 6150."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9922126</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40652333</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990119</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919984</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 WEST</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9922126</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 WEST</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
