<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>solo vocabulary of jazz bassist Jimmie Blanton</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Nash, Robert.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Music.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 145 leaves  : music ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>145 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Jimmie Blanton (1918--1942) is recognized today as a pivotal figure in the evolution of jazz double bass performance. His performances and recordings with the Duke Ellington Orchestra (and smaller ensembles connected with this unit) between 1939 and 1941 served to elevate the double bass from a limited role as time-keeper and ""novelty"" soloist in the rhythm section of the jazz orchestra to that of an identifiable solo voice, capable of supporting, contrasting, or blending with the reed, brass and percussion sections as dictated by musical needs. Blanton's approach to the instrument confounded the conventional notions of his era about almost every aspect of jazz bass performance: the clear, powerful tonal quality, superior pitch accuracy, technical freedom, and melodic inspiration that characterize his style immediately redefined the standards by which his contemporaries judged jazz bassists. His duo recordings with Duke Ellington at the piano, which featured extended improvised bass solos using both pizzicato and arco techniques, remain significant landmarks in recorded jazz.;The purpose of this study is to examine various aspects of Jimmie Blanton's solo vocabulary by transcribing, analyzing, and comparing eighteen of his solo performances in their entirety. This approach identifies the melodic, harmonic and rhythmic components which comprise his vocabulary in their original context, and provides greater insight into his approach to jazz improvisation in a variety of musical settings.;The monograph consists of a review of Blanton's life and career; an overview of the development of jazz bass solos up to 1939, the year Blanton began recording; analysis and discussion of various aspects of Blanton's solo vocabulary and style; and appendices containing 18 transcriptions of complete Blanton solo performances and composite scores of ""Body and Soul"" (three versions) and ""Mr. JB Blues"" (two versions)."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Robert Nash.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: A, page: 9320."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (D.M.A.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9925541</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40885175</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990301</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920135</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 NASH</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9925541</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 NASH</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
