<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Equity issuance in Mexico</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Tandon, Arun Kumar.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Business Administration.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>v, 213 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>213 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation examines the equity issuance process from an international perspective. Specifically, it examines the underpricing, long run stock price performance and operating performance of Mexican ADR IPOs compared to that of domestic Mexican IPOs. This study also examines the share price response to global seasoned equity offerings by Mexican firms. Mexican IPOs and global seasoned equity issues by Mexican firms are further distinguished based on the nature of the foreign tranche, that is whether it is a Level III (public offering) or a 144A (private placement) issue. This distinction is maintained throughout the study owing to the differences and the unique nature of these markets.;ADR IPOs and ADR seasoned equity offerings are generally undertaken by large, well established Mexican firms and underwritten by prestigious underwriters. In addition, ADR issues incur substantial costs such as listing fees, increased disclosure of information, and costs incurred in complying with SEC rules and regulations. There are also benefits of an international listing such as increased investor recognition, an enlarged investor base and a higher degree of monitoring and certification.;This study uses data provided by the Mexican stock exchange over the period of 1989 to 1996 and finds that ADR IPOs of Mexican firms show modest underpricing and no long run stock price underperformance or decline in operating performance subsequent to the issue, in contrast to the findings for IPOs in the U.S. These findings are consistent with the well-established nature of Mexican firms that go public as well as the institutional features of ADRs. Global seasoned equity offerings and Mexican firm commitment domestic issues show the negative share price response usually associated with seasoned equity offerings in the United States."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Arun Kumar Tandon.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: A, page: 1215."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9925545</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40886082</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990301</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920144</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 TAND</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9925545</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 TAND</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
