<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Applications of band ratioing at Fort Irwin, California</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Taylor, Alexander Wright.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geology and Geophysics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1998</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 114 leaves : ill. (some col.), maps (col.) ; 29 cm. + 3 plates</extent>
      <extent>114 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation describes the results of two projects that demonstrate the power of band ratioing of remote sensing data. The first method, Band Ratio Differencing (BRD), challenges the more traditional techniques for detecting environmental disturbance of the surface in and terrains. These traditional techniques are inadequate because they cannot identify the nature of the change (physical, chemical, biological) or the processes (natural, anthropogenic) involved in causing the change. In contrast, BRD of Landsat TM data has the advantage of providing information about changes in the composition of alluvial surfaces. These compositional changes, when combined with empirical field data provides insight into the specific causes and effects of environmental change. BRD was applied at Fort Irwin, California, the U.S. Army's National Training Center (NTC) for desert warfare. Two dates of Landsat TM imagery (1985 and 1995) were acquired and BRD applied. A total of 514.5 square kilometers, or 42% of the alluvial surface at Fort Irwin has been affected by off road vehicular traffic. Two major types of change were identified: Disturbed Alluvial Surface and Continuous Dust Mantle, which can be further subdivided into six separate classes of change, related to either the cause or the effect of the disturbance.;Hyperspectral Assisted Mapping (HAM) was developed as an alternative to Spectral Signature Mapping (SSM) techniques typically applied to AVIRIS hyperspectral data. Our analysis suggests that SSM-based techniques when applied to AVIRIS provide little to no additional information about sedimentary and igneous rocks. This is because many rock forming minerals of sedimentary and igneous rocks possess little to no diagnostic spectral absorption features in the range measured by the AVIRIS sensor. The HAM method integrates the geornorphic information provided by a Digital Elevation Model (DEM) and the lithologic discrimination, but not identification, provided by hyperspectral data to produce a surface materials map. HAM was successfully applied at the North Alvord Slope study area, on the southern margin of Fort Irwin, California. Nine distinct surface materials classes were identified by the technique. All nine classes were discriminated on the basis of minor mineral constituents in the materials, such as micas and clays."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Alexander Wright Taylor.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: B, page: 1491."</note>
   <note>Plates in tube [1] 34 x 45 cm. + [2] 77 x 92 cm.</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1998.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9925551</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1998</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40650116</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990120</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1919988</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1998 TAYL 378.76 L930D 1998 TAYL TUBE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9925551</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1998 TAYL 378.76 L930D 1998 TAYL TUBE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
