<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Preparing undergraduate music majors to teach beginning instrumentalists</title>
      <subTitle>the effects of self-evaluation, teacher observation, and performance oriented instructional approaches on teacher behaviors and pupil responses</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Lethco, Leigh-Ann Marie</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1966-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Music.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <dateIssued encoding="marc" point="start">1999</dateIssued>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 202 leaves : ill., music ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>202 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of three approaches to training preservice instrumental music teachers (N = 22) for initial teaching experiences involving beginning instrumentalists ( N = 22). The three approaches---one involving intensive self-evaluation activities, a second focusing on observation of experienced instrumental music teachers, and a third evidencing a performance orientation---were administered as a four-week treatment phase in an undergraduate brass techniques course. Primarily, this study was designed to answer the question: Did instructional approach differentially affect teacher behavior across two private lessons?;Teacher (subject) and pupil behaviors were documented and categorized according to various aspects of subject/pupil activity, subject verbalizations, successful/unsuccessful performance trials, and subjects' secondary instrument (trumpet or trombone) performance competency. In addition, subject and pupil post-treatment attitudes were assessed.;Following the treatment phase, subjects taught two lessons to beginning band pupils. Forty-four lessons (totaling more than 1,000 minutes and averaging roughly 24 minutes) were videotaped and analyzed.;Certain lesson activities were timed using the behavioral observation computer application, SCRIBE. Results indicated that the self-evaluation group engaged their pupils in performance activity 44.76% of the time, which was significantly more than the teacher observation and performance orientation groups.;Using verbatim transcripts of lessons, subject verbalizations were labeled as academic information, direction-giving, information-gathering, or off-task remarks. Pupil responses were categorized as successful, unsuccessful, or no response. Overall subjects used academic verbalizations, three times more than they used direction verbalizations. When pupil responses were preceded by subject verbalizations that were, subject matter rich, pupils were more likely to respond successfully than when verbalizations were subject matter neutral, as in direction-giving (p &lt; .0001). There were no treatment group differences with regard to subject verbalization and pupil responses.;Subjects' ability to perform on the secondary instruments studied during treatment was determined by three independent judges. Results indicated no significant differences among treatment groups or between major instruments (brass and non-brass). Further, regardless of treatment, subjects' attitudes toward treatment were overwhelmingly positive."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Leigh-Ann Marie Lethco.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: A, page: 1058."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9925534</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40879039</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990301</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920138</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 LETH</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9925534</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 LETH</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
