<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Characterization of a simian hemorrhagic fever virus large envelope glycoprotein gene and its product</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Wang, Xiaochun</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1956-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 115 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>115 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The goal of this project was to determine the genome organization, replication strategy and identification of the large envelope glycoprotein (GL) gene of simian hemorrhagic fever virus (SHFV). This virus is the fourth member of the new virus family Arteriviridae.;The 3' end of the RNA genome from the prototype isolate of SHFV was cloned and sequenced. This 6,314 nucleotide (nt) sequence consisted of nine complete overlapping open reading frame (ORFs 2, 2a, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, and 9). At the 5' end of this sequence is a partial ORF, ORF 1b, and the 3' end is a noncoding region. The sequence data showed that SHFV encodes three additional ORFs as compared to the other arteriviruses. The nine SHFV 3' ORFs were presumed to be translated from separate subgenomic mRNAs (sgRNAs) produced during virus replication. However, RT-PCR analysis using leader- and ORF-specific primers identified only eight sgRNA species. The sequence, 5'-UCNUUAACC-3', was identified as the junction motif between the mRNA body and the 5' leader sequence. An ORF 2b-specific sgRNA was not detected.;The SHFV particle consists of two proteins, p15 and p20, and at least two glycoproteins, p42 and p54. Endoglycosidase treatment of purified SHF virions showed that p42 and p54 were actually four separate peptides with molecular masses between 28 and 30 kDa. Thus, the SHFV particle contains at least six structural proteins. In vitro synthesis of the ORF 7 product resulted in a peptide with a molecular mass of 31 kDa; this mass increased to 52 kDa when the in vitro product was glycosylated. However, when the glycosylated ORF 7 product was treated with endoglycosidase, the molecular weight of the peptide shifted to about 29,000. Immunoprecipitation results showed that the ORF 7 product was one of the SHFV GL proteins (p54). Four antigenic epitopes were identified using monoclonal antibodies generated by genetic immunizations of mice with the ORF 7 gene. One of these epitopes was identified as a virus neutralization site. The ORF 7 genes from two additional SHFV isolates were compared to the ORF 7 gene from the prototype isolate. No sequence difference was observed among these three isolates."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Xiaochun Wang.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: B, page: 1450."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9925547</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40886220</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990301</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920150</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 WANG</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9925547</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 WANG</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
