<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Soil phosphorus characteristics of natural and created wetlands in the Atchafalaya Delta, Louisiana</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Poach, Matthew Emerson</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1966-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Oceanography and Coastal Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 108 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>108 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Quantitative comparisons of artificially created and natural wetlands are typically confounded by differences in wetland age, with created wetlands being younger than their natural counterparts. Observed differences between these wetlands may be attributed to either age differences or an inability to reproduce natural wetland characteristics. The objectives of this research were to: compare the phosphorus characteristics of similarly aged, created and natural wetlands in the Atchafalaya Delta, Louisiana and determine the controls over phosphorus retention in these wetlands. A phosphorus fractionation procedure was used to identify the phosphorus fractions in sediments from natural and artificially created wetlands in the Atchafalaya Delta belonging to three age classes: young (&lt;1--3 years old), intermediate (5--10 years old), and old (15--20 years old).;The young, created wetland was lower in total phosphorus than its natural counterpart due to its higher sand content. The intermediate-aged, created wetland had lower phosphorus contents than its natural counterpart due to higher organic matter and lower bulk density. Phosphorus contents of the old created and natural wetlands were similar. These differences between the created wetlands and their natural counterparts can be explained by the design of the created wetlands. Bedload sediment from the Atchafalaya River, which is dredged to form the created wetlands, had lower phosphorus and oxalate-extractable iron than the river's suspended sediment, which forms the natural wetlands. Sediment recently deposited at both created and natural wetlands had similar phosphorus contents.;In the Atchafalaya Delta, wetlands created with dredge sediment will have less phosphorus upon formation than natural wetlands of the same age, but if they are built to mimic the elevation gradient, shape and orientation of the natural wetlands they can develop phosphorus characteristics similar to natural wetlands through the deposition of river sediment."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Matthew Emerson Poach.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: B, page: 1483."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9925542</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">40885258</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990301</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920136</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 POAC</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9925542</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 POAC</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
