<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Expecting women</title>
      <subTitle>constructing the pregnant woman in twentieth century U.S. and British dramatic representation</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Cuomo, Amelia Lynn.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Theatre.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 254 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>255 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Pregnancy and issues surrounding pregnancy such as paternity and legitimacy have been presented in Western Drama since its inception. Pregnancy in the modern era, however, has become a complex issue. Abortion, birth control, and the advent of new reproductive technologies (such as in vitro fertilization) alter understandings of reproduction. This study explores twentieth century British and U.S. dramatic representations of the pregnant woman and analyzes how pregnant women are constructed in drama.;The dissertation is divided into five chapters. Chapter One explores four plays by male playwrights: Harley Granville Barker's Waste, Eugene O'Neill's ""Abortion,"" and Sidney Kingsley's Men in White and Detective Story. Each playwright dramatizes the fall of a male protagonist caused by his lover's abortion, and each narrative displaces the pregnant woman, eventually removing her from the text. Chapter Two examines Mary Burrill's ""They That Sit in Darkness"" and Marie Stopes's Our Ostriches. These two plays challenge early twentieth century ideologies which in essence made birth control unavailable to working class women. Chapter Three explores feminist reconceptions of birth in Tina Howe's Birth and After Birth, Karen Malpede's  A Monster has Stolen the Sun and Judy Chicago's The Birth Project. Chapter Four compares an agitprop drama by Myrna Lamb, ""But What Have You Done for Me Lately?"" and Jane Martin's Keely and Du. The change in tone between the two plays reflects a dramatic disintegration of support of Roe v. Wade. Chapter Five investigates Michelene Wandor's Aid Thy Neighbor, an episode of the television series  Star Trek entitled ""The Child,"" and a contemporary film,  Junior. Each of these texts explores the new reproductive technologies' impact on our understanding of pregnancy.;The dissertation demonstrates that dramatic representations are part of a larger meta-narrative that constructs an ever changing understanding of pregnancy and birth. Particular emphasis is placed on how social ideologies concerning women and reproduction inform texts; therefore, narratives from newspapers and magazines are included to provide the necessary social and historical backdrop. This study also suggests that current constraints on women who are pregnant reflect a larger desire to regulate the behavior of all women."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Amelia Lynn Cuomo.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: A, page: 9410.;Directors: Lesley Ferris; Leslie Wade."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9926416</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41399609</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990518</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920272</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 CUOM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9926416</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 CUOM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
