<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Natalie Vivian Scott</title>
      <subTitle>the origins, people and times of the French Quarter Renaissance (1920-1930)</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Scott, John Wyeth</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1947-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept of History.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>2 v. (xiv, 505 leaves) : ill., photographs ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>506 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This is the interwoven story of Natalie Vivian Scott, war hero, author, adventurer and humanitarian, and the French Quarter Renaissance during the 1920s, when Natalie Scott was a vital member of the talented coterie of writers and artists whose talents prospered there, including Sherwood Anderson, William Faulkner, William Spratling, Lyle Saxon, Roark Bradford, Oliver La Farge, John Dos Passos, Hamilton Basso, Meigs Frost, among others.;This work's premise is that the decayed, crumbling French Quarter, falling into irreversible decline, was saved during the early 1920s by an outburst of local creativity and organizational energy that inspired restoration and a unique, historically significant cultural revival. The participants included a remarkable array of artists, writers, stage performers, poets and journalists, the most famous being major products of this renaissance, but not its progenitors. This artistic and literary colony was the most significant in Southern U.S. history, and among the most important of the American twentieth century.;Natalie Scott was instrumental in each of the key forces that created and shaped the French Quarter Renaissance. After being awarded France's highest medal, the Croix de Guerre, for her heroism during World War I, this Southern bred and Newcomb educated war heroine returned to New Orleans and became a feature writer, social editor, and columnist for the New Orleans  States. As a founder, playwright and performer with the Petit Theatre du Vieux Carre; a staff member of the Double Dealer literary magazine; close friend of Anderson, Spratling, Faulkner, La Farge, Saxon and other key figures; a pioneer in Vieux Carre; renewal investments and the leading social columnist in the city, Natalie Scott serves as an ideal vehicle to document the recovery of the French Quarter, and its service as the creative incubator for an astonishing array of important young talents."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by John Wyeth Scott II.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: A, page: 1297."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9926425</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41391581</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990519</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920291</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 SCOT V.1 378.76 L930D 1999 SCOT V.2</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9926425</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 SCOT V.1 378.76 L930D 1999 SCOT V.2</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
