<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Predictors of practice role commitment and practice role value for doctorally prepared nursing faculty</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Jones, Anna Karin Walker.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Educational Leadership, Research, and Counseling.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 162 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>163 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The purpose of this study was to examine the relationships between environmental, career, and personal factors and practice role commitment and practice role value of doctorally prepared full-time nursing faculty within the theoretical framework of faculty role performance by Blackburn and Lawrence (1995). A mailed survey was used to collect data related to faculty practice from 506 faculty who were members of the American Nurses Association or the National Organization of Nurse Practitioner Faculties.;Practice role commitment was level of engagement in the practice role. Practice role value was importance assigned to the practice role by the faculty. Environmental variables included institutional classification, reward structure, number of full-time faculty, programs offered, practice opportunities at a health center, administrative support, and peripheral support. Career variables included education preparation, years as a full-time professional nurse, years as a full-time faculty member, specialty, rank, and professional affiliation. Personal knowledge factors included competence, values, personality characteristics, personal preference, perceived institutional preference, work performance feedback, work load, and social contingencies.;Descriptive statistics, chi-square, factor analysis, and stepwise multiple regression methods were used for data analysis. The four personal factors of commitment/expertise in practice, institutional/personal preference for practice, credence to practice feedback from students and clinical colleagues, and placing a high score on credibility/maintaining skills as reasons for practice explained 53.2% of the variance for practice role commitment. The factors of actual and preferred practice behaviors; credence given to student, clinical colleague, and self evaluation regarding faculty practice; higher ratings for personal reasons for practice; teaching role valued; caring characteristics; view of the ideal nursing faculty; ethical/moral characteristics; and view that other faculty value practice explained 42.2% of the variance for practice role value.;Even though environmental and career factors were significantly correlated to practice role commitment and practice role value, personal factors were the most significant predictors. These findings must be utilized to create changes in academic policies to support faculty practice to ensure excellence in nursing education and nursing service."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Anna Karin Walker Jones.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-04, Section: A, page: 9570."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9926419</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41392564</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990519</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920294</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 JONE</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9926419</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 JONE</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
