<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Inequalities between pythagoras numbers and algebraic ranks in Witt rings of fields</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Hawkins, Sidney Taylor</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1938-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Mathematics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>iv, 28 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>29 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation establishes new lower bounds for the algebraic ranks of certain Witt classes of quadratic forms. Let K denote a field of characteristic different from 2 and let q be a quadratic form over K. The form q is said to be algebraic when q is Witt equivalent to the trace form   qL&amp;mid;K  of some finite algebraic field extension   L&amp;mid;K . When q is algebraic, the algebraic rank of  q is defined to be the degree of the minimal extension   L&amp;mid;K  whose trace form is Witt equivalent to q. It is an important, unsolved problem to find reasonable bounds on the algebraic rank of a given algebraic form.;This dissertation makes a beginning contribution to this problem of bounding the algebraic rank by investigating a simple, special case. Let sigma denote a totally positive square-class in a field K (characteristic different from 2, as always). Assuming that the 1-dimensional quadratic form sigma X2 is algebraic, what can be said about the algebraic rank? Even in this simple case, little was known prior to this dissertation. Let   pyKs  denote the pythagoras number of sigma relative to K. This is the smallest natural number, j, such that or can be written as a sum of j squares of elements in  K. Let n be the algebraic rank of sigma X2. In general, n is unknown, and a reasonable lower bound is sought. The main result is:   pyKs &amp;le;2n-dn+1   where d(n + 1) is the sum of the coefficients of the 2-adic expansion of n + 1. Thus, if sigma is chosen with a large pythagoras number, then the algebraic rank  n must be correspondingly large as well.;This dissertation also considers a slightly more general case."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Sidney Taylor Hawkins.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-06, Section: B, page: 2734."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9936093</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41400049</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990518</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920284</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 HAWK</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9936093</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 HAWK</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
