<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Effects of fluctuating salinity, nutritional state, and temperature on Leptasterias spp. from Little Port Walter, Alaska</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Tamplin, Jeffrey William</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1964-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Biological Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 91 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>82 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The effects of fluctuating salinity, nutritional state, and temperature on activity, oxygen consumption, feeding, and growth rates were analyzed on seasonally collected Leptasterias spp. (Echinodermata: Asteroidea) from Little Port Walter, AK. Leptasterias aspera and  L. epichlora were collected on June 10, 1994, divided into size groups, and perivisceral fluid osmolality was measured every three hours during a 12 h 30-10-30&amp;permil;S fluctuating cycle. The perivisceral fluid osmolality of larger individuals fluctuated less than that of smaller sea stars. The perivisceral fluid osmolality of small and large Leptasterias spp. closely tracks the ambient water osmolality during tidal cycles.;Leptasterias spp. were collected on August 31, 1994 and separated into three nutritional treatment groups and analyzed over 31 days. Starved individuals had lower oxygen consumption rates than fed individuals. Feeding and starvation data suggest that Leptasterias spp. from Little Port Walter can survive beyond 31 days with a negative energy budget.;For studies of temperature acclimation, Leptasterias spp. were collected at the annual temperature minimum (1&amp;deg;C; 19 November 1995, 27 February 1998) and the annual temperature maximum (12&amp;deg;C; 1 September 1996, 2 July 1997). Individuals from seasonal collections were step-wise acclimated (2&amp;deg;C every two days) or acutely exposed to 5&amp;deg;C, 7.5&amp;deg;C, 10&amp;deg;C, 12.5&amp;deg;C, 15&amp;deg;C, 17.5&amp;deg;C, 20&amp;deg;C, or 22.5&amp;deg;C. The 28-day LC50 of winter acclimatized, acutely exposed animals were 8 and 10&amp;deg;C lower than summer acclimatized, step-wise acclimated and summer acclimatized, acutely exposed individuals, respectively.;Acute exposure and step-wise acclimation to experimental temperatures above the normal environmental maximum, 12.2&amp;deg;C, resulted in suppressed feeding and elevated oxygen consumption rates. Leptasterias spp. exist near the upper limit of capacity adaptation when environmental temperatures reach the annual summer maximum and undergo seasonal acclimatization to water temperature. Leptasterias spp. are adapted to withstand sublethal temperature shifts, which occur both seasonally and diurnally in the intertidal zone.;Activity only partially correlated with environmental changes (temperature exposure, fluctuating salinity, and nutritional state of the animal). Reduced salinity negatively affected activity in Leptasterias spp. Activity coefficients varied with starved and fed feeding regimes, but were not significantly different between feeding treatments or time. Activity coefficients of Leptasterias spp. did not vary significantly with temperature."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Jeffrey William Tamplin.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-06, Section: B, page: 2559."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9936115</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41394100</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990519</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920297</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 TAMP</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9936115</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 TAMP</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
