<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Design of work-rest schedules for VDT operators</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Balci, Rana</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1972-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Programs in Engineering Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 169 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>170 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The number of musculoskeletal and psychological discomforts is increasing as a result of continuing growth of VDT work. Although ergonomic improvements in workstation design can be applied, an effective work-rest schedule is an economical way to reduce these problems. The objective of this research was to determine an effective work-rest schedule for VDT operators. In addition to a discomfort questionnaire, performance and electromyography measurements from trapezius and flexor carpi radialis were used. Three different work-rest schedules were applied: 60-minute work/10-minute rest, 30-minute work/5-minute rest, and for the third schedule, the subjects received four breaks from VDT work each hour additional to a 14-minute break after two hours. Three of these breaks were 30 seconds in length and the fourth break was 3 minutes in length. The research also considered the effect of type of VDT task. Subjects were asked to enter alphanumeric data for data entry task and to solve addition/subtraction problems as mental task.;The results indicated that effect of schedule was different on discomfort levels and performance of the subjects. Similarly, the type of task had different effects on discomfort, performance, and muscular tension levels.;The 15/micro schedule was superior to the other schedules in terms of discomfort levels of the neck, back, and elbow/arm, eyestrain, speed, accuracy, and performance for both tasks. The lowest levels of trapezius muscle tension for data entry and flexor carpi radialis for mental tasks were resulted in the 15/micro schedule. The effect of the type of task was significantly different with 60/10 schedule on discomfort in shoulder and chest, bluffed vision, and headache; with 30/5 schedule on shoulder, chest and elbow/arm discomforts; and with 15/micro on discomforts in shoulder and hand/wrist. The schedule effect was different on data entry task for neck, lower back, elbow/arm discomforts and on mental task for headache. Mental task resulted in a higher psychological discomfort, lower physical discomfort, and lower performance than data entry task. The results of the study suggest that the 15/micro schedule is superior to the longer and infrequent rest break schedules considering upper extremity discomfort, eyestrain, speed, accuracy, and performance of the subjects."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Rana Balci.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-06, Section: B, page: 2881."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9936082</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41375057</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990517</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920257</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 BALC</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9936082</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 BALC</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
