<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>historical and Cultural Geography of the Grange in Minnesota and Louisiana 1870-1880</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Thorstad, Linda Marie</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1947-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geography and Anthropology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 213 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>214 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study uses historical and geographical inquiry to examine postbellum agrarian social, political and economic unrest that in 1868 led to the formation of the first national, secret and ritualistic, fraternal agricultural society known as the Grange. The Grange was created to unite farmers through cooperative buying and selling, to promote agricultural education, and to create a social organization that encouraged both women and men to acquire and refine leadership skills. It also sought to address concerns over monopolies and promoted state regulation of railroad rates. Although Grange membership peaked in 1875 and sharply declined through 1880, it forged the way for more radical rural organizations and reform movements such as the Farmers' Alliance (1880s) and The Populist Party (1890s).;The dissertation focuses on the socioeconomic composition and geographic distribution of Grange charter members within the states of Minnesota and Louisiana during the society's initial period of organization and growth (1870--1880). Data were compiled and analyzed on Minnesota and Louisiana Subordinate Grange chapter locations, their diffusion, and certain economic attributes of charter members. Statistical tests highlighted the differences between non-Grange farmers and Grangers within and between the two states.;Grangers in both states benefitted from ""networking"". At monthly Grange meetings, educational lectures on the best methods and practices of farming, home keeping skills or economics were given and agricultural subjects were discussed. These meetings also provided the members with a sense of fraternity and community.;Social, political and economic conditions were far better in Minnesota than in Louisiana during the period 1870--1880. In Minnesota, the Grange grew, prospered and remained a viable organization beyond the years of this study. Minnesota Grangers: enjoyed economic advantages over non-Grange farmers thanks to their capital investments in land and machinery which led to increased production of wheat and corn and higher values of all farm production. In Louisiana, the organization arrived late, floundered and met its demise by the early 1880s. Louisiana Grangers fared slightly better economically than their non-Grange counterparts between 1870 and 1880, but they suffered economic losses on every variable tested except the production of corn."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Linda Marie Thorstad.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-06, Section: A, page: 2167."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9936116</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41394447</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990519</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920301</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 THOR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9936116</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 THOR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
