<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Null codon-based models of synonymous and nonsynonymous substitution from a phylogenetic perspective</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>McClellan, David A.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1966-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Biological Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>ix, 106 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>107 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation focuses on the relationship between codon composition and the molecular evolution of protein-coding DNA sequences. Chapter 1 emphasizes the role of codon structure in determining patterns of nucleotide substitution, as well as the influence codon composition has on the evolution of the structure and function of the protein. The overall purpose of Chapter 1 is to establish the need to study molecular evolution at the codon level.;In Chapter 2, the codon-degeneracy model (CDM) of molecular evolution is constructed. This model considers codon structure in terms of patterns of nucleotide site degeneracy. It allows the prediction of patterns of substitution by considering the codon compositions of protein-coding DNA sequences, and then compares these predictions to observations inferred from phylogenetic analysis using a goodness-of-fit score as an optimality criterion. Observed data derived from the accepted phylogenetic tree of five species of pocket gopher of the genus Orthogeomys are evaluated.;Chapter 3 presents a way by which the CDM can be used to choose between competing hypotheses of phylogenetic relationships. The CDM is also used to search for the optimum phylogenetic tree from among all possible topologies and configurations of phylogenetic relationship for five species of pocket gopher of the genus Orthogeomys. The CDM successfully found the accepted phylogenetic tree used in Chapter 2.;Chapter 4 concentrates on the theoretical aspects of using the effects of physicochernical properties to evaluate the influences of purifying selection on patterns of nonsynonymous substitution. Paramount to this model are the residuals between expected and observed relative frequency of substitution for several Grantham difference magnitude classes. The relative effect purifying selection has on amino acid sequence evolution is quantified by calculating the sum of the positive residuals. This model is used to evaluate the differential effects of purifying selection on the three functional domains of the pocket gopher cytochrome b gene. It was found, among other things, that the transmembrane domain evolves substantially more quickly because it is largely composed of hydrophobic amino acid residues that generally possess relatively low mean potential Grantham differences."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by David A. McClellan.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-06, Section: B, page: 2486."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9936100</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41375293</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990514</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920248</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 MCCL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9936100</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 MCCL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
