<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Effects of low oxygen atmosphere on the growth and development of Arabidopsis thaliana (L.) Heynh</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Ramonell, Katrina Maria.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Plant Pathology and Crop Physiology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 108 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>109 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Interest in the improvement of crop productivity through repression of photorespiration led to experimental growth of plants in low O2 and the surprising finding that reproduction is inhibited under these conditions. Using Arabidopsis thaliana (L.) Heynh. cv. Columbia, studies were undertaken to understand the mechanism behind oxygen control of plant development. The hypothesis that developmental changes observed in low O 2 are due to repression of the plant hormones ethylene and brassinolide (which require O2 for biosynthesis) was tested. Arabidopsis  was grown for 35 days in Sun bags in one of five altered O 2 atmospheres (210, 160, 100, 50, 25 mmol/mol) with 0.35 mmol/mol CO 2 in N2. Molecular analysis of ethylene biosynthesis was accomplished using cDNAs encoding ACC synthase and ACC oxidase in ribonuclease protection assays and in situ hybridizations. To understand if low O2 inhibition of brassinolide biosynthesis was responsible for developmental changes in low O2, brassinolide-replacement experiments were performed. Arabidopsis was grown for 10 days on nutrient agar or nutrient agar + 10-7 M brassinolide in magenta vessels coupled to gas mixtures of 210 or 25 mmol/mol O2, 0.35 mmol/mol CO2 in N2. When grown in 25 mmol/mol O2, plants exhibited dwarf morphology resembling the brassinolide-deficient mutant  det2, and this line was incorporated into the brassinolide studies at low O2 for comparison. Leaf development under low O2  resulted in changes in leaf size, stomatal density and stomatal patterning. Stomatal density increased in all low O2 treatments but was not linked to changes in ethylene or brassinolide. Low O2 changes in leaf size, however, were mediated through depression of brassinolide biosynthesis. There was a loss of ethylene biosynthesis in siliques from plants grown at 50 and 25 mmol/mol O2, and silique ACC oxidase mRNA increased as O2 was lowered. As O2 decreased, tissue-specific patterning of ACC oxidase and ACC synthase gene expression shifted from the embryo to the silique wall. Loss of ethylene in the silique was tightly correlated with loss of the embryo in seeds produced in low O2. These data show that changes in development under low oxygen can be explained by repression of O2-sensitive plant hormones."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Katrina Maria Ramonell.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-06, Section: B, page: 2556."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9936109</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">41385123</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990518</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920282</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 RAMO</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9936109</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 RAMO</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
