<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>On harmonic analysis for white noise distribution theory</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Stan, Aurel Iulian</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1969-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Mathematics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 67 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>68 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This thesis is composed of two parts, each part treating a different problem from the theory of Harmonic Analysis. In the first part we present an inequality in White Noise Analysis similar to the classical Heisenberg Inequality for functions in   L2Rn  . To do this we replace the finite dimensional space R n and its Lebesgue measure by the infinite dimensional space   E' , which is the dual of a nuclear space   E , and its Gaussian measure. Choosing an arbitrary element eta in   E , we may define the multiplication operator   Q&amp;d5;h , which is the sum between the differentiation operator   D&amp;d5;h  and its adjoint   D*h . We then use   Q&amp;d5;h  as a substitute for the multiplication operator by x from the finite dimensional case. Because the Fourier transform is a unitary operator on   L2Rn  , whose eigenvalues are powers of -i and the second quantization operator of -iI, denoted by   G-iI  , from (L2) into itself has the same properties, we replace the Fourier transform by (  G-iI  ). Here, (L2) is the space of all complex valued, square integrable functions on   E' . The proof of our Heisenberg Inequality relies on the Schwartz Inequality and the commutation relationships between any two of the following three operators:   D&amp;d5;h, D*h , and   G-iI  .;In the second part of this work, we show some results in White Noise Analysis analogous to the classical Paley-Wiener Theorem that describes functions on Rn with compact support in terms of their Fourier transform. Because the Fourier transform for a Schwartz function is defined pointwise as an inner product between that function and an exponential function and the S-transform from White Noise Analysis is defined similarly, we have chosen this time the S-transform as the natural replacement for the Fourier transform. After giving a thorough description of the weakly and strongly compact subsets of   E' , we finally characterize some classes of (L 2) functions with compact support in terms of their S-transform. As in the classical Paley-Wiener theorem two conditions are essential, namely: an analyticity and a growth condition."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Aurel Iulian Stan.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-09, Section: B, page: 4649."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9945743</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42139971</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990817</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920690</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 STAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9945743</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 STAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
