<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Quaternary benthic foraminiferal distribution in the Ross Sea, Antarctica, and its relationship to oceanography</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Perry, Pamela Jo.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geology and Geophysics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 357 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>358 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study focuses on Quaternary benthic foraminiferal distribution in the Ross Sea, and its relationship to oceanography and ice-shelf retreat. It is the first study of benthic foraminiferal distribution that takes the retreat history of the Ross Ice Shelf into account. This is also the first time foraminifera from a cold-water carbonate bank have been described. There are three foraminiferal faunas in the Ross Sea: Pleistocene carbonate-bank fauna, Modern-calcareous fauna, and Holocene agglutinated fauna. Numerically significant species in the carbonate-bank and Modern-calcareous faunas include  Angulogerina earlandi, Cibicides lobatulus, Discorbis vilardeboana, Ehrenbergina glabra, Epistominella exigua, and Globocassidulina crassa . The carbonate-bank fauna has higher diversity and greater numerical abundance than the Modern-calcareous fauna. The agglutinated fauna, which is seen in Holocene sediments, contains Bathysiphon sp. A,  Hormosinella ovicula, Miliammina earlandi, Textularia wiesneri, and  Trochammina quadricamerata. The Modern-calcareous fauna is found where Warm Core Water upwells into the photic zone, causing an increase in phytoplankton productivity. The agglutinated fauna is found in water depths below the CCD and where Warm Core Water does not upwell in the photic zone. The carbonate-bank fauna probably formed during a period of increased upwelling in the northwestern Ross Sea.;The utility of benthic foraminifera as a tool for distinguishing glacial environments is also tested. Ice-shelf proximal and distal environments could not be distinguished by benthic foraminiferal assemblages, which contained the agglutinated species Miliammina earlandi, reworked calcareous forms, and rare other agglutinated specimens. In addition, some samples with an abundant agglutinated assemblage were found in an open-water environment.;This research also included a brief study of the distribution and formation of concentrically layered opaline spherules found in Antarctic sediments. These tiny spherules are found in association with calcareous foraminifera in the Ross and Weddell Seas and appear to form through precipitation as seasonal sea ice melts, causing freshwater to mix with saltwater, thus decreasing silica solubility in surface waters."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Pamela Jo Perry.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-09, Section: B, page: 4486."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9945733</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42086231</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990816</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920678</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 PERR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9945733</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 PERR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
