<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Intervention implementation and intervention outcomes for teenage mothers in school-based treatment for social and academic problems</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Penton, Cherri Edenfield.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 121 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>122 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The effects of a strong treatment package, comprised of 2 types of performance feedback plus incentives, on the social behavior and academic progress of 9 minority teenage mothers attending an inner-city high school, was investigated. Treatment integrity of their teachers and parents was also evaluated. Research shows that academic deficits and conduct problems are strong correlates of early pregnancy, Many students experience academic failure and related disciplinary problems because no one monitors their behavior. In this study, a comprehensive treatment was developed to be used across settings (home, school and a school-based health clinic) and across treatment agents (parent, teacher, a therapist working within the school-based health clinic, and the teenage mother herself) to increase the monitoring, and self-management skills of these young mothers. Three triads of 3 participants each (teen mother, parent and teacher) were trained on specific treatment steps to be completed daily. Permanent products generated by the intervention were used to verify whether or not each treatment step was actually performed. From these outcome measures, a daily treatment integrity score was calculated for parents and teachers, while treatment compliance and academic performance were measured for teenage mothers. The results showed that all teen mothers improved their treatment compliance and their academic averages. Disciplinary referrals and absences from class were measured pre- and post-treatment for each teenage mother and it was determined that the rates of accumulation for both of these were reduced for most of the teen mothers. Treatment integrity improved for all parents of the teen mothers, and teachers maintained high levels of intervention usage throughout the study. This study contributes to the literature in that it provides a useful methodology for determining where treatment implementation is breaking down, whether with the teacher, the parent or with the student. It also provides a telephone parent-training format, via a daily telephone interview between the teenage mother and her parent/guardian, which may be used for the purpose of training the important parenting behavior of talking with a child in order to hold the child accountable for daily school progress and behavior."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Cherri Edenfield Penton.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-09, Section: B, page: 4870."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9945732</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42086064</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990816</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920677</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 PENT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9945732</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 PENT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
