<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Synthesis, characterization, and applications of chiral polymeric surfactants in micellar capillary electrophoresis</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Harrell, Crystal Williams</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1970-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xviii, 188 leaves : ill. (some col.) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>189 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Chirality is a characteristic of many synthetic and biological organic compounds. This property is particularly true in the pharmaceutical industry where a large number of drugs are marketed as racemates. One method used to monitor optical purity is capillary electrophoresis (CE). Chiral separation using CE is achieved by use of an immobilized chiral phase or through a chiral selector mobile phase additive. It is demonstrated and determined that chiral polymeric surfactants are more suitable for chiral separation in electrokinetic capillary chromatography (EKC) than conventional micelles. Polymeric surfactants eliminate the dynamic equilibrium that occurs in normal micelles, are more stable, rigid, have no critical micelle concentration (CMC), and can tolerate higher organic modifier content.;The research presented in this dissertation generally embodies the synthesis, characterization, and application of polymeric surfactants. Specifically, a nonionic glucopyranoside and anionic Valine and Phenylalanine are examined as surfactant headgroups. All headgroups are coupled to an undecylenyl hydrocarbon tail before polymerization by gamma-irradiation.;After completion of synthesis, the surfactant and/or polymeric surfactant is characterized using techniques such as elemental analysis, mass spectroscopy, nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR), optical rotation, light scattering, fluorescence spectroscopy, and analytical ultracentrilugation. From the characterization techniques, information including product identification, confirmation and purity, as well as polymer properties, such as size and microenvironment, were obtained.;Applications involved using poly(undecyl-beta-glucopyranoside) (PUG) as a transient capillary coating to separate seven tricyclic antidepressant drugs in a modified capillary zone electrophoretic (CZE) mode. Poly(sodium-N-undecyl-L-valinate) is examined as an approach for developing a universal laboratory technique and procedure as well as for gaining insights into polymeric surfactant properties and characteristics. The latter is accomplished by conducting a polymerization concentration study. The use of EKC, fluorescence, and NMR revealed the differences in polymer enantioselectivity, size, shape, and dispersity relative to polymerization concentration.;Phenylalanine monomer and dipeptide polymeric surfactants are used in EKC to examine their potential as pseudostationary phases. This study probes the possibility of enhanced enantioselectivity of binaphthyl atropisomers and benzodiazepines by increased hydrophobicity, steric, and pi-pi interactions."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Crystal Williams Harrell.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-09, Section: B, page: 4574."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9945718</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42077268</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990813</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920663</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 HARR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9945718</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 HARR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
