<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>effects of team-member attributes on team performance</title>
      <subTitle>a model of individual contribution to team performance</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Yum, Joe J.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 99 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>100 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Although team composition is one of the most frequently studied topics in team research, much remains unknown regarding what attributes to look for when selecting team-members and how these attributes affect team performance. The purpose of this study was to present and to test a theoretical model that depicts how individual attributes affect team-member performance and how team-member performance ultimately affects team performance. The proposed model is based on the integration of research on team and individual performance. From a practical standpoint, understanding the relationships among the variables in the proposed model may be important for the selection of employees in team-based organizations.;In general, the results did not support the proposed model. However, further examination of the data showed that task knowledge and skills is a separate construct from teamwork knowledge and skills, task motivation is a separate construct from teamwork motivation, and task experience is a separate construct from teamwork experience. One implication of these findings is that assessing knowledge, skills, motivation, and experience for several appropriate job performance dimensions may be useful for selecting employees who may perform well on their job specific tasks and work well with others in a team environment.;Furthermore, the data suggest that the use of peer ratings in a team setting may be problematic due to the close personal relationships among team-members. These results seem to be consistent with various studies that found that ratings in a team setting may be affected by contextual factors (e.g., Grey &amp; Kipnis, 1976; Liden &amp; Mitchell, 1983; Mitchell &amp; Liden, 1982). In addition, the problems encountered with peer ratings seem to have been magnified by the political context of the organization examined in the present study. Implications of these results are discussed."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Joe J. Yum.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-09, Section: B, page: 4947."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9945755</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42191179</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990818</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920705</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 YUM</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9945755</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 YUM</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
