<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Community structure and the effects of experimental fires on hardwood shrub species in southeastern longleaf pine savannas</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Drewa, Paul Boguslaw</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1967-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Biological Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 111 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>112 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The main objective of this dissertation is to describe and examine how altering fire regimes in southeastern longleaf pine savannas may affect the abundances and distributions of indigenous plant species.;In chapter one, I investigate whether herbs, compared to shrubs, have greater utility in delineating communities along elevation gradients of several meters in longleaf pine savannas. Herbaceous and shrub abundance data were analyzed separately for areas in Louisiana and Florida using cluster analysis and ordination. In Louisiana, three plant communities were sharply delineated and strongly correlated with gradients in elevation, surface soil moisture, and other surface soil properties. Herbaceous species indicated the existence of three communities in Florida, but species distributions and edaphic factors were less discrete than in Louisiana. In both regions, classification of shrub species clustered data into uninterpretable groups suggesting broad distributions. Shrubs were less sensitive than herbs to changes in ground level elevation and surface soil properties. Expanded distributions of shrubs may be a result of past fire suppression and dormant season burning.;In chapter two, I examine the experimental effects of fire regimes on shrubs. The effects of geographic region (Louisiana and Florida), habitat (upslope savannas and downslope seepages), fire regime (dormant versus growing season; single versus repeated fires), and species characteristics (root crown versus rhizomatous species; woody versus suffrutescent species) on resprouting of shrubs following fires were monitored over four years. Regardless of geographic region, shrubs collectively resprouted significantly more following dormant season fires than growing season fires, especially when conducted biennially in downslope seepages. In Florida downslope seepages, Hypericum microsepalum  and H. brachyphyllum, both suffrutescent species with root crowns, resprouted more following dormant season fires than growing season fires. Of the two species, only abundances of H. microsepalum  were inversely related to maximum fire temperatures. Growing season fires did not result in appreciable complete kill of shrubs; densities of shrubs were comparable to pre-bum numbers. Present abundances of shrubs may be a result of dormant season burning. Shifting fire regimes to the growing season alone will not likely result in a rapid return toward conditions once present in longleaf pine savannas."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Paul Boguslaw Drewa.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-09, Section: B, page: 4370."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9945715</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42076867</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990813</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920660</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 DREW</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9945715</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 DREW</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
