<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>A </nonSort>
      <title>novel approach to DNA sequencing employing near-IR flourescence detection coupled with micro-scale reaction vessels with capillary gel separations</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Williams, Daryl C. (Daryl Clifford)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1969-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 132 leaves : ill. (some col.) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>133 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Electropherograms of oligonucleotides labeled with near-IR fluorescent dyes, separated by capillary gel electrophoresis (CGE) and detected using an ultrasensitive near-IR fluorescence detection system will be presented. A Universal M13 sequencing primer was labeled on the 5' end with a near-IR dye containing an isothiocyanate functional group. Comparison of the on-column detection limits in capillary gel electrophoresis for the near-IR-labeled sequencing primer to that of a visible fluorescein-labeled primer indicated improved sensitivity for the near-IR case. The detection limit was found to be 3.4 x 10-20 moles (SNR = 3) for the near-IR-labeled primer while the on-column detection limit for the fluorescein analog was 1.5 x 10-18 moles (SNR = 3). The sequence of nucleotide bases in an M13mp18 template was determined using a single lane, single dye technique. The molar concentrations of the ddNTP's used during chain extension were varied in order to achieve a ratio of 4:2:1:0 (A:C:G:T) which allowed the identification of each terminal base via fluorescence intensity measurements. Comparison of the known sequence of the M13mp18 plasmid to that obtained using this protocol yielded a base-calling accuracy of 84%.;A catfish gene DNA template was attached to the interior wall of an aminoalkysilane derivatized (100 mum, 50 mum or 20 mum) fused-silica capillary tube via a biotin/streptavidin linkage. The DNA modified capillary reactor was then used to perform DNA sequencing reactions employing standard Sanger dideoxynucleotide termination protocols and the VentRTM DNA polymerase enzyme. Preliminary analysis of nano-reactor products was performed using a commercial fluorescence-based DNA sequencing instrument, the DuPont Genesis 2000. The nano-reactor was then directly interfaced to a capillary gel electrophoresis system to take advantage of the small sample requirements of CGE and create and integrated near-IR-LIF-based DNA analysis system.;An investigation of the effect of varying capillary internal diameter (i.d.) on the separation efficiency is presented. Gel-filled columns with i.d.s of 20 mum, 50 mum, 75 mum and 100 mum were tested with an oligonucleotide standard, until failure, to determine the efficiency obtainable using these columns."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Daryl C. Williams.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-11, Section: B, page: 5488."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9948318</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42190030</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">990818</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920700</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 WILL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9948318</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 WILL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
