<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Development of monoclonal antibody and enzyme linked immunosorbent assay for detection of off-flavor compound 2-methylisoborneol</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Park, Eun Sung</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1966-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Food Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 138 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>139 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"2-Methylisoborneol (MIB), a secondary metabolite of cyanobacteria and fungi, causes earthy-musty taste and odor. This is a significant problem in the aquaculture industry and large scale water supplies. Especially it is a major problem for the channel catfish industry. To monitor the levels of this compound for quality control and abatement, rapid, sensitive and inexpensive methods are needed.;This research reports the development of an indirect enzyme linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) for MIB using monoclonal antibodies. For the preparation of monoclonal antibodies against MIB, MIB-Limulus polyphemus hemocyanin (LPH) and borneol-LPH were synthesized as an immunogen. Borneol-bovine serum albumin (BSA), isoborneol-BSA, and MIB-BSA were synthesized as a solid phase protein conjugate to compare and optimize the effect of solid phase conjugate structure. To produce monoclonal antibodies, two mice were immunized with borneol-LPH protein conjugate and another two mice were immunized with MIB-LPH. Hybridoma cells were made by the fusion of myeloma cells and spleen cells of the mice that showed high antibody titer and specificity. Hybridoma cells secreting high affinity monoclonal antibodies were cloned by the limiting dilution method three times to ensure clonality. For the optimization of ELISA, different Ab concentrations and different solid phase conjugate concentrations were tested. At lower concentrations of antibody and solid phase conjugate, the sensitivity was greatest, however the signal also began to decrease. The effect of solid phase conjugate structure was studied by comparing the sensitivity of ELISA using borneol-BSA, isoborneol-BSA, and MIB-BSA as a solid phase conjugate. When MIB-BSA was used as a solid phase conjugate, the affinity for the free MIB was improved against the affinity to MIB-BSA and the sensitivity of ELISA was greatest. By using anti-borneol monoclonal antibody (1/250) and MIB-BSA (0.5mug/ml) as a solid phase conjugate, standard curve was constructed from 100mg/L to 0.1ng/L range. The linear range of this standard curve was found to occur between 1 ng/L and 1 mg/L MIB. The detection limit, defined as the MIB concentration giving an A/Ao value of 0.8, was found to be approximately 1ng/L."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Eun Sung Park.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-11, Section: B, page: 5266."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9951614</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42693250</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">991022</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920871</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 PARK</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9951614</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 PARK</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
