<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Characterization of solidification/stabilization of chromium wastes in cement matrix</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Zhang, Aijun</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1957-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 172 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>173 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A cement-based solidification/stabilization (S/S) system of Cr wastes treatment has been studied in this program. A combination of the two techniques; namely reduction of Cr(VI) to Cr(III) and simultaneous immobilization within a cement matrix, has been found to be effective and practical to treat Cr wastes.;Cr(VI) can not be easily and effectively-immobilized in the S/S system unless being reduced to Cr(III). Ferrous compounds are used as reducing reagents. The reduction not only removes the toxic Cr(VI) species but also results in the low-solubility precipitation of (CrxFe 1-x) (OH)3(s) in the S/S system. Long-term and short-term samples were tested through TCLP procedure. For appropriate contents and time, the leachate concentrations can be brought below the EPA characteristic limit of 5 mg/L. Usually, the long-term samples show higher leaching concentration of Cr.;Many metal ions have a profound influence on the cementitious matrix formed during the curing process of Portland cement. There is a consensus view, based on calorimetric studies, that Cr species are accelerators for early hydration of cement. This program has been investigating the system in most detail with 29Si MAS NMR, which shows retarded hydration by Cr salts alone, or by ferrous chloride (or sulfate) alone or in combination with Cr species. In addition to retarded hydration, the added Cr species and ferrous salts results in enhanced amounts of chain-lengthening and chain-branching silicates.;X-ray absorption fine structure (XAS) was successfully applied in speciation of Cr(III) and Cr(VI) in this program. The ratio of Cr(VI) to total Cr in a cement-based S/S system was measured, and the effectiveness of different Fe(II) reductants is determined from XANES and compared to leachability results. EXAFS analyses revealed a complex situation in the structural picture of the product (or products) of the Cr wastes treatment system in the OPC cement matrix."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Aijun Zhang.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-11, Section: B, page: 5489."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9951622</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42687330</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">991022</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920882</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 ZHAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9951622</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 ZHAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
