<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Heinrich von Herzogenberg's Zwei Biblische Scenen</title>
      <subTitle>a conductor's study</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Boozer, John Elbert</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1948-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Music.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 216 leaves : music ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>217 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Heinrich Herzogenberg was born into nobility in Graz, Austria, on June 10, 1843. He began studying music at the University of Vienna in 1862, and at the home of one of his teachers, Herzogenberg was often in the company of Brahms. In the years that followed, Herzogenberg and his wife Elisabet became close friends of Brahms and actively promoted his music. Through this close association with Brahms, Herzogenberg's compositional style was greatly influenced. Herzogenberg studied harmony and counterpoint with Simon Sechter, and in 1875, along with others, founded the Leipzig Bachverein (Leipzig Bach Society). This association with the Bach Society and the studies with Sechter encouraged Herzogenberg's interest in contrapuntal music.;After the death of Herzogenberg's wife in 1892, his music was influenced by the theologian and church musician Friedrich Spitta. Among the suggestions Friedrich Spitta gave to Herzogenberg were ideas for ten ""biblical scenes."" Herzogenberg completed settings of two of the ten scenes, entitled  Zwei biblische Scenen. This work was published posthumously in 1903 as opus 109 after Friedrich Spitta brought the work to the attention of publisher J. Rieter-Biedermann. The first biblical scene, entitled ""Der Seesturm"" (The Sea Storm), is scored for tenor and baritone soloists, mixed chorus, violins, cellos, basses, and organ. The second, ""Das kananaische Weib"" (The Canaanite Woman), is written for soprano and baritone soloists, men's chorus, and organ.;This document consists of four chapters. The first considers the life of Herzogenberg, including the relationship and influence of Johannes Brahms and Friedrich Spitta. Chapter two surveys the historical context of  Zwei biblische Scenen, including discussions concerning the church music reformation movements of the Prussian Revival of the Lutheran Church and the Cecilian Movement of the Catholic Church. The third chapter includes an examination of the texts of Zwei biblische Scenen. Chapter four discusses observations on the music and performance considerations of  Zwei biblische Scenen. A score of the music, edited and transcribed from a microfilm of the autograph score and the first published score, is provided with this document."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by John Elbert Boozer.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-11, Section: A, page: 3835."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (D.M.A.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9951596</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42664796</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">991018</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920833</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 BOOZ</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9951596</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 BOOZ</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
