<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>"A </nonSort>
      <title>perfect war:" politics and parties in Louisiana, 1824-1861</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Sacher, John Michael</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1970-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of History.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>2 v. (vii, 469 leaves) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>470 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"My dissertation explores Louisiana's political development from 1824 to 1861. Many antebellum state studies have been written, but none focus specifically on Louisiana. While sharing the rest of the South's commitment to slavery and cotton, Louisiana possessed atypical attributes including: a unique ethnic composition, a sugar cane crop dependent upon a protective tariff, and the presence of New Orleans, the South's foremost commercial city. Louisiana's antebellum political situation resulted from the interaction of these distinctive traits with the characteristics that Louisiana shared in common with the rest of the United States.;The primary focus of this political narrative is the development of parties and the interaction between parties and the electorate. During the 1820s and 1830s, Louisianans moved from a political system based on personality and ethnicity to a distinct party system with Democrats competing against Whigs. These parties, which were evenly matched, battled until the Whig party collapsed in the 1850s. Subsequently, the nativist Know Nothing party rose and fell. And, in 1861, after an increase in tension over the slavery issue, Louisiana seceded from the Union.;Through its examination of Louisiana politics, my dissertation addresses several key historiographical questions. I investigate the relationship between state and federal parties and the role of individuals in party politics. I also explore the impact of both the ideology of republicanism and of the politics of slavery. Moreover, I probe the role played by ethnic diversity, which often overshadowed partisan allegiance. Additionally, I analyze the differences and similarities among the parties' programs---especially concerning the value of governmental activism.;My dissertation also discusses the rise of Jacksonian democracy. Louisiana's 1812 constitution restricted voting and office-holding. Later constitutions, written in 1845 and 1852, adopted universal white male suffrage and decreased office-holding requirements. Furthermore, extensive campaigning provided an opportunity for voters and non-voters, including women, to participate in the political process. Despite these changes, elites continued to occupy the main positions of power. Though elites served in state government and as party leaders, I contend that political power remained in the hands of their constituents throughout the antebellum period."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by John Michael Sacher.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-11, Section: A, page: 4155."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9951616</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42685850</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">991022</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920875</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 SACH V.1 378.76 L930D 1999 SACH V.2</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9951616</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 SACH V.1 378.76 L930D 1999 SACH V.2</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
