<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Risk management of aflatoxin through mutagenic potential modification and toxin formation by intrinsic components in food</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Ali, Syed Shahid</namePart>
      <namePart type="termsOfAddress">1968-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Food Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xv, 238 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>239 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Aflatoxins are the secondary metabolites of Aspergillus flavus  and their presence in food and feed crops is unavoidable. This study evaluates the antimutagenic properties of phytic and linoleic acids in aflatoxin-affected food.;A reduction in the number of revertants was a function of an increased concentration of phytic/linoleic acids and phosphotidylinositol in the  Salmonella/microsomal mutagenicity assay (tester strains TA-100 and TA-98) with and without metabolic activation (S-9). Linoleic acid (10 and 100 mug/plate) and phosphotidylinositol (25mug/plate) were antimutagenic against most of the mutagens tested. Although a reduction in the number of revertants was observed in the phytic acid treatments, the results, however, do not suggest phytic acid as antimutagenic in this assay.;The inhibition of AFB1 biosynthesis in the A. flavus  inoculated Czapek-Dox liquid medium was observed as the concentration of phytic acid was increased in a 25 day study. A complete inhibition of AFB 1 production was recorded at phytic acid levels of 0.5 and 1 mg/100ml. The role of metal ions was also tested under similar conditions. In the absence of Fe++ and Zn++ ions, a complete inhibition of AFB1 production was observed; however, Cu++ and Mg++ ions did not exhibit the same response.;In a 35 day storage study of corn the aflatoxin levels in the  A. flavus inoculated ground and whole kernels were higher than the treatments. The reduction in the AFB1 levels was observed after 14 days of inoculation in both the treatment and controls. Phytic acid extended the most reduction among the treatments regardless of substrate type; however, not a complete inhibition in the biosynthesis of AFB1 was exhibited. The production of AFB1 and AFB2 was significantly lower (&gt;50%) than the Aspergillus-dependent and -independent controls. The production of AFB1 in linoleic acid-treated corn was also found significantly lower (&gt;50%) than the controls. No such observations were recorded in the combination treatment of phytic and linoleic acid. However, the production of AFB1 was like the linoleic acid treatment.;Phytic acid and linoleic acid have been reported as antimutagenic  in vitro. More research is warranted to evaluate their potential antimutagenic role in vivo."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Syed Shahid Ali.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 60-11, Section: B, page: 5474."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9951594</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">42663779</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">991018</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920835</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 ALI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9951594</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 ALI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
