<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Machine-cell location problems for multi-product flowlines</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Yu, Junfang</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1961-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Engineering Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 368 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>369 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Jobs (parts) and machines are usually grouped into part-families and machine-cells in a flexible, cellular manufacturing system to minimize the flows of all work-in-processes (WIP). As a result of this grouping, some parts may need processing on some machines that are not in their own cells. The parts requiring machines in other cells are called 'exceptional parts,' and the corresponding machines are called ' bottleneck machines.' Usually, there are two ways to deal with this inter-cell flow problem: using a material handling system to move the exceptional parts among the cells or duplicating the bottleneck machine(s) for the corresponding exceptional part(s). The objective of this research is to minimize the total costs of these inter-cell flows. A two-phase procedure, machine-cell location (MCL) and duplication of bottleneck machines (DBM), is presented in this research to achieve this goal. The MCL problem covers both one-dimensional layout and two-dimensional layout, especially dealing with one-dimensional equidistant (1DE), one-dimensional non-equidistant (1DNE) and two-dimensional non-equidistant (2DNE) machine-cell location problems. All versions of the MCL problem fall under the general class of quadratic assignment problem (QAP) which is NP-hard and it is difficult to solve a large problem optimally. The DBM problem, which arises as a natural extension to the MCL problem, may be classified as an  integer linear programming (ILP) problem and a solution to it may provide an alternative way to reduce the total inter-cell flow costs. The 1DE problem is solved first by using a simple depth-first heuristic (SDH) which is later modified to a directional decomposition heuristic (DDH) for a better quality of solution. The directional decomposition of inter-cell flow, the core foundation of the DDH algorithm, is then extended to the one-dimensional non-equidistant (1DNE) and the two-dimensional non-equidistant (2DNE) problems. This leads to the development of the modified directional decomposition heuristic (MDDH) and the quadra-directional decomposition heuristic (QDDH), respectively. Based on the solutions to various facets of the MCL problem, a binary ILP model is proposed for solving the DBM problem optimally. Empirical tests show that heuristic DDH and its extensions, MDDH and QDDH, are more efficient than most other comparable heuristics."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Junfang Yu.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: B, page: 1024."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960107</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43370163</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000131</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921044</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 YU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960107</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 YU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
