<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Territoriality and commerce</title>
      <subTitle>political conflict over the Panama Canal in geographic perspective</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Aguirre, Robert</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1968-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geography and Anthropology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>2 v. (xiii, 392) leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>393 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation examines the recurring conflict between the United States and the Republic of Panama regarding the Canal and the Canal Zone by analyzing three salient geographic issues: first, the extent to which international commerce or national security required the building of a canal in Central America; second, ambiguities arising out of notions of sovereignty and extraterritoriality in United States constitutional law; and third, the political controversies between an inland society and a maritime society in Panama itself The theoretical implications of Edward Fox's work in his geographic history of French politics and the works of Panamanian historians and sociologists studying eighteenth and nineteenth-century Panama were used to offer an explanation of Panama's contemporary political relations with the United States. Panama has historically been divided between an inland and a maritime society, with the maritime society tending to be the more politically and economically dominant one. After its independence in 1903, Panama's internal political competition created a situation where all sides felt compelled to assume an antagonistic posture with the United States and demand treaty concessions beyond what might even seem to be within Panama's reasonable national economic interest.;The interpositionist role of the United States in Panamanian affairs is the product of a longstanding commitment. The United States has assumed sole responsibility for protecting the neutrality of interoceanic communication across Panama since the middle of the nineteenth century. The goal was to prevent European powers from threatening a maritime choke point affecting U.S. national security and potential commercial expansion. The project to construct an American Panama Canal was, therefore, a product of commercial as well as military concerns. Contrary to conventional thinking about the nature of U.S.-Panamanian relations, this dissertation examines how the influence of the United States, at times, became the means by which Panamanian opposition leaders leveraged political pressure against internal rivals."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Robert Aguirre.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: A, page: 7190."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960035</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43331585</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000121</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920965</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 AGUI V.1 378.76 L930D 1999 AGUI V.2</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960035</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 AGUI V.1 378.76 L930D 1999 AGUI V.2</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
