<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Toxicity of neem-based insecticides on aquatic animals and cell lines</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Goktepe, Ipek</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1970-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Food Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 145 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>146 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The impact of pure azadirachtin (AZA) and neem-based insecticides (Neemix(TM) and Bioneem(TM)) on eight aquatic animals (crayfish, white shrimp, grass shrimp, blue crab, water fleas, oyster, freshwater snails, and mosquito) and two cells (hybridoma and oyster) were assessed by short term acute toxicity tests of 48 and 96 h. The LC50 (in vivo bioassays) and IC50 (in vitro bioassays) were determined for each species. Stability of (Neemix(TM) and Bioneem(TM)) was tested under light, air, and heat (24 and 37&amp;deg;C) for 1, 3, 6, and 9 days. Neemix(TM) and Bioneem(TM)) were fractionated into two fractions (volatiles and nonvolatiles) and toxicities of each were tested on water fleas. AZA showed less toxicity than Neemix(TM) and Bioneem(TM)) on all species tested. The toxic and molt inhibitory activity of the insecticides were species, dose and time dependent. Among the test animals, water fleas was the most sensitive to Neemix(TM), Bioneem(TM)) and pure AZA with LC50 of 0.071, 0.034, and 0.382 mug AZA/mL, respectively. Next to water fleas, mosquito, oyster and blue crab were found to be very sensitive to Neemix(TM) and Bioneem(TM)) with low LC50 values. Crayfish and freshwater snails showed the least sensitivity to Neemix(TM) Bioneem(TM) and pure AZA. The LC50 values of (Neemix(TM) were 4.705 mug AZA/mL for crayfish and 4.257 mug AZA/mL for snails. (Neemix(TM) and Bioneem(TM)) were found to be toxic to both hybridoma and oyster cells at concentration 1 mug AZA/mL and higher. The toxicity of both insecticides decreased with higher temperature, light, and time, but Bioneem(TM)) remained more toxic at 37&amp;deg;C than Neemix(TM) and appears to be less sensitive to environmental factors. Nonvolatile fractions exhibited significantly lower LC50 values (1.023 muL fraction/mL) than the full formulations of both insecticides. The volatile fraction of Bioneem(TM) showed lower toxicity than that of corresponding nonvolatile fractions. Whereas, the volatile fraction from Neemix(TM) was not toxic to water fleas.;These results suggest that increased use of neem-based insecticides, resulting in increased agricultural run-off, may have direct adverse effects on aquatic organisms, contrary to the common belief that plant-derived insecticides (e.g. Neemix(TM) and Bioneem(TM)) pose no risk to the ecosystem."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Ipek Goktepe.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: B, page: 6050."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960055</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43354280</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000127</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920999</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 GOKT</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960055</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 GOKT</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
