<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Understanding congressional responsiveness</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Ardoin, Phillip Jude.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Political Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 124 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>125 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This dissertation addresses a simple question: Why are some members of congress very responsive to the ideological preferences of their constituency while others appear to ignore their constituency? Although numerous scholars have explored this issue, they have consistently: (1) limited their analyses to the influence of member characteristics while ignoring the potentially significant influence of constituent factors and (2) failed to test a single comprehensive model of congressional responsiveness that considers the full range of member and constituent factors hypothesized to influence variation in congressional responsiveness.;This dissertation directly addresses these two problems by developing and testing a comprehensive model of congressional representation that focuses on both the influence of constituent and member conditions on variation in congressional representation. Specifically, I examine the influence of electoral margins, congressional retirement, electoral proximity, congressional seniority, constituency homogeneity, and constituency political engagement.;My analyses suggest that constituent conditions play a significant role in explaining variation in congressional responsiveness. In particular, I find that members from relatively homogeneous and politically engaged constituencies are significantly more responsive to the preferences of their constituents. I argue that this is because relatively homogeneous constituencies send relatively consistent signals regarding their preferences, while politically engaged constituencies are more likely to make their preferences known and punish members of congress who are not responsive to them. Surprisingly, I find that the influence of member conditions on variation in congressional responsiveness appears to be minimal and their influence varies between chambers of congress. Ultimately, I conclude, much of the variation exhibited in congressional representation is not random, but rather systematically associated with various member and constituent characteristics. Moreover, constituent factors play a vital role in this process and future research by congressional scholars must recognize this role if they are to fully understand the factors that influence congressional representation."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Phillip Jude Ardoin.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: A, page: 7470."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960037</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43332149</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000124</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920967</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 ARDO</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960037</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 ARDO</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
