<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Phase equilibria of ethylene copolymers in sub- and supercritical fluids</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Chan, Ka Chun</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1972-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemical Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 171 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>172 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Phase equilibria of polyethylene and ethylene-copolymers in sub- and supercritical solutions are investigated in this work. Fluid-liquid and fluid-solid phase transitions data are measured for tetracontane, a prototype of linear polyethylene, in sub- and supercritical propane, poly(ethylene-co -hexene-1) in suband supercritical. propane and ethylene + 1-hexene mixture, and poly(ethylene-co-octene-1) in sub- and supercritical propane and ethylene. The experiments are carried out in a batch optical cell equipped with a transmitted-light probe. The experimental data are correlated and predicted using two equations of state derived from of the Statistical Associating Fluid Theory (SAFT).;In the case of tetracontane + propane, increasing the tetracontane concentration and increasing pressure increase the fluid-solid transition temperature. Also, increasing the long-chain-n-alkane molecular weight increases the fluid-liquid transition pressure. The SAFT predictions are in a reasonable agreement with the experimental data for both fluid-liquid and fluid-solid transitions.;For poly(ethylene-co-hexene-1), both poly(ethylene- co-hexene-1) concentration and molecular weight have a relatively weak effect on the phase behavior. The fluid-liquid pressure and fluid-solid temperature decrease as branch density increases. The fluid-liquid pressure depends strongly on the solvent type. When the ethylene concentration increases in poly(ethylene-co-hexene-1)+ethylene+hexene-1 mixtures, the fluid-liquid pressure increases, whereas the fluid-solid temperature decreases.;For poly(ethylene-co-octene-1)+propane, the poly(ethylene- co-octene-1) concentration has a weak effect on both fluid-liquid and fluid-solid transitions in the range of 0.01 to 0.1 polymer fraction. Increasing the poly(ethylene-co-octene-1) molecular weight increases both fluid-liquid and fluid-solid transitions, whereas increasing the poly(ethylene-co-octene-1) branch density decreases both transitions in poly(ethylene-co-octene-1)+propane system. Only fluid-liquid, cloud-point pressure, is measured for poly(ethylene- co-octene-1)+ethylene. Furthermore, the fluid-liquid pressure strongly depends on molecular weight and short-chain branch density, but weakly on polymer concentration in the range from 0.05 to 0.15 polymer fraction. Poly(ethylene- co-octene-1) solutions in ethylene exhibit upper- and lower-critical-solution-temperature behavior only. Once again, SAFT calculations are in reasonable agreement with the experimental data."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Ka Chun Chan.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: B, page: 9580."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960043</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43349767</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000126</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920979</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 CHAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960043</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 CHAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
