<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Synthesis, thermodynamic stability and enzymic behavior of oligonucleotides containing pyrazole nucleobase analogs</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Saurage, Andrea Sapp</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1971-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Chemistry.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xviii, 99 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>100 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Non-hydrogen bonding nucleosides with iodo, nitro, propynyl and thiazolyl substituted at the 4-position of pyrazole were prepared. These nucleosides were converted to their corresponding nucleoside phosphoramidites and incorporated into a series of complementary oligonucleotides in order to determine the effect that varying size, charge distribution and polarizability has on duplex stability and structure. The self-complementary Dickerson dodecamer sequence 5'-CGCXAATTYGCG-3', as well as the non-self complementary sequence 5'-CAAAATGGTGGCCAAGT-3 ' previously investigated by Brown, were used to determine the duplex stabilization and thermodynamic consequences of placing 5-nitroindole and 4-substituted pyrazole nucleosides across from each natural base. In the pyrazole series, the largest and smallest duplex destabilization in all cases studied was found with cytosine and adenosine, respectively, while the 4-thiazolyl substitution was determined to form the most stable duplex regardless of the complementary base. We investigated the directing ability of the pyrazole analogs for incorporation of dNTP's. The DNA polymerases chosen were Taq and Pfu exo-, which lack 3' --5' proofreading exonuclease activity, and Vent, Deep Vent, Pfu which contain exonuclease activity. The enzymes were able to incorporate natural nucleotides across from our modification as detected using the polymerase chain reaction. The Sanger method of dideoxysequencing was used to determine the natural base incorporated across from the modification. The non-proofreading enzymes mainly incorporated deoxyadenosine across from our modification where as the proofreading enzymes removed our modification but not with total efficiency.;Automated DNA synthesis procedures might modifying the 5-nitroindole base via electrophilic aromatic substitution by replacing the nitro group or addition of iodine to the ring system. An alternative oxidation reagent, CSO, was used to prepare a series of sequences for comparison with sequences prepared using standard oxidation conditions. Results from MALDI-MS did not provide conclusive evidence for either substitution or iodination of the bicyclic ring system.;Examination of the thermodynamic results led to the preparation of thiazole-C-nucleoside, which historically is more difficult to synthesize. The thiazole ring offers a site for the formation of an N-oxide. It has been suggested this group is responsible for enzyme recognition. We prepared the thiazole and thiazole-N-oxide nucleosides for incorporation into oligonucleotides for thermodynamic and enzymic investigations."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Andrea Sapp Saurage.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: B, page: 8610."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960094</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43368776</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000131</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921033</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 SAUR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960094</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 SAUR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
