<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Increasing accuracy in children's verbal self-report of reinforcers</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>DiGiovanni, Gina Michelle.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 109 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>110 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Several studies have examined the relationship between self-report of behavior and actual behavior (Baer, Williams, Osnes, &amp; Stokes, 1985; Bernstein &amp; Michael, 1990; Risley &amp; Hart, 1968). Results from such studies indicate poor correspondence between verbal self-report and actual behavior. This finding is particularly true for children (Guevremont, Osnes, &amp; Stokes, 1986). However, few studies have examined conditions under which the accuracy of self-report procedures can be increased. The current study evaluated whether the accuracy of children's verbal self-report of reinforcers could be increased by modifying antecedent conditions. Specifically, the current study examined the effects of two antecedent variables (i.e., mode of preference assessment and type of instruction) on the accuracy of verbal identification of reinforcers.;Participants were thirty children in grades one through four, who had been referred to an outpatient pediatric behavioral health clinic for non-compliance. Participants were administered two preference assessments: (a) survey and (b) stimulus paired-choice questionnaire with three different types of instructions (contingency unspecified, vague contingency specified, and exact contingency specified). Subsequently, participants were allowed to choose actual reinforcers for completing easy math problems (token coupons). The coupons that were chosen represented the true criterion for comparisons with the results of the verbal self-reports.;A main effect was found for type of instruction and mode of preference assessment. An interaction was also found such that the unspecified survey resulted in significantly less accurate responses than any other group (i.e., vague survey, exact survey, unspecified paired-choice questionnaire, vague paired-choice questionnaire, and exact paired-choice questionnaire).;Results indicated that accuracy was higher when contingencies that were either vague or exact were specified in the instructions, and accuracy was higher for the paired-choice method than the survey. Overall, accuracy of the survey was increased when instructions specified vague or exact contingencies. The accuracy of the paired-choice method of assessment did not vary with instructions. Finally, when vague or exact contingencies were specified in the instructions, responses on the survey were comparable to those of the paired-choice."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Gina Michelle DiGiovanni.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: B, page: 1078."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960049</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43351467</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000126</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920989</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 DIGI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960049</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 DIGI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
