<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Molecular genetics and functions of Herpes Simplex Virus Type 1 (HSV-1) glycoprotein K (gK) in the morphogenesis of infectious virion particles</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Foster, Timothy P.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1972-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Veterinary Medical Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xxi, 254 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>255 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) specifies at least 11 glycoproteins that are expressed in infected cells and in virions. HSV-1 enters into cells via fusion of the viral envelope with cellular membranes and can spread to adjacent cells via fusion of cellular membranes. Glycoproteins gB, gD, gH, and gL are known to be essential for virus entry, virus spread, and virus induced cell-to-cell fusion. The majority of spontaneous single amino acid changes that cause extensive cell fusion map within the UL53 gene encoding glycoprotein K (gK); however, the role of gK in virus entry and virus egress had not been defined. Specific antibodies against portions of gK expressed in E. coli were raised in mice and detected gK as a 40-kDa protein in purified virions. To investigate the effect of gK in virus entry via the known HSV-1 HveAh and HveCh receptors, two recombinant viruses were constructed, KOS/EGFP (wild-type) and DeltagK/EGFP (gK null) expressing the enhanced green fluorescent protein (EGFP) constitutively. The simian homolog of HveA (HveAs) was cloned, sequenced, and CHO/HveAs transformed cell-lines were isolated. The DeltagK/EGFP virus failed to enter into CHO/HveAs, while DeltagK/EGFP prepared in complementing Vero (VK302) cells entered efficiently. In contrast, DeltagK/EGFP entered efficiently into CHO/HveAh and CHO/HveCh cells. A series of hybrid receptors were made expressing different portions of HveAh and HveAs and were used to map a short region of HveAh that conferred receptor-mediated entry to an HveAs receptor background. The role of gK in virion morphogenesis and egress was addressed by constructing a panel of recombinant viruses expressing gK carboxyl-terminal truncations and single amino acid substitutions. Two cellular vesicular transport motifs, a cysteine-rich motif and a tyrosine-based motif were found to be essential for infectious virus production, intracellular virion transport, and virus egress. Therefore, gK may interact with vesicular transport pathways during virion morphogenesis and egress. The overall results from this research suggest that HSV-1 gK is a multifunctional protein involved in receptor utilization during virus entry and transport of virion particles to extracellular spaces through cellular vesicular transport pathways during virus egress."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Timothy P. Foster.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: B, page: 6900."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960053</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43353957</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000126</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920994</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 FOST</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960053</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 FOST</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
