<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Instantaneous learning neural networks</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Tang, Kun Won.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 129 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>130 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Instantaneous learning is a desirable feature in neural networks. This type of learning enables the network to be trained very quickly, typically in just one or two passes of the training set as opposed to hundreds or even thousands of passes for networks trained by an iterative process, such as the error backpropagation (BP) algorithm. This dissertation first reviews several existing types of neural networks with instantaneous learning capability. It then proposes a new network called the Fuzzy Classification (FC) Neural Network that can be trained with two passes of the training samples. The first pass assigns the synaptic weights for the input and output layers. The second pass determines the radius of generalization r for each training sample. The network exhibits fuzziness in two regards: (1) by fuzzification of the location of each training vector in the input space; and (2) by assigning fuzzy memberships of output classes to new input vectors.;The operation of the FC network is analyzed from different perspectives, namely, separability of patterns, curve fitting and kernel regression. It is shown that one mode of operation of the FC network can be made to behave like a Radial Basis Function (RBF) network by proper choice of membership function and network parameter. The performance of the FC network as a pattern classifier is also discussed in a statistical framework.;The generalization performance of the FC network is compared against that of the CC4 Comer Classification Neural Network, the RBF network, and the Multilayer Perceptron network trained by the BP algorithm. Experiments involving a Henon map time series, a Mackey-Glass time series, and a spiral pattern are used in the comparison. The performance of the FC network is found to be comparable to that of RBF and BP networks, and better than that of the CC4 network. Its performance is also more scalable than those of CC4 and RBF networks. Further, the time taken to design an FC network for any given problem is much shorter compared to the other three networks."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Kun Won Tang.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: B, page: 1008."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960101</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43370032</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000131</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921041</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 TANG</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960101</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 TANG</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
