<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Production of transgenic eastern oysters</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Buchanan, John Terrell</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1969-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Oceanography and Coastal Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 255 leaves : ill. (some col.) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>256 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The eastern oyster, Crassostrea virginica, supports a valuable industry in the United States and Louisiana. In recent years this industry has been plagued by diseases, creating interest in the use of gene transfer to produce oysters capable of eliminating pathogens. The goal of this work was to develop techniques for laboratory research of eastern oysters, and for transfer of genes to oyster gametes, larvae, and adults.;Cell culture provides an effective alternative to work in whole animals. Cell attachment and spreading on various culture substrates was improved, and poly-D-lysine was identified as a superior substrate. Toxicity of the antibiotic G418 to oyster cells was determined for use as a selective agent, and techniques for gene transfer in cells were identified.;Adult oysters were conditioned for spawning in a recirculating system, although declines in physiological condition were noted. Electroporation of oyster sperm did not affect larval production, but did allow transfer of the gene for red-shifted green fluorescent protein (rsGFP). Larvae expressing rsGFP were observed with fluorescent microscopy and presence of the gene was verified by the polymerase chain reaction (PCR).;Transgenic oyster larvae were also produced by electroporation and chemically mediated transfection (with SuperFect(TM); Qiagen Inc.) of embryos. Transfer of the aminoglycoside phosphotransferase II gene (neo ') by both methods resulted in increased larval survival by conferring resistance to G418. Larvae expressing rsGFP were observed with fluorescent microscopy, and presence of the gene was verified by PCR.;Transgenic oyster adults were produced by injection of rsGFP  or the cecropin B gene complexed with SuperFect(TM) into the adductor muscle sinus. Presence of the gene in DNA of treated oysters was verified by PCR after 4 d (87%) and 10 d (96%). Significant differences in green fluorescence were detected by flow cytometry in hemocytes after 4 d, but not after 10 d, and hemocytes expressing rsGFP were observed with fluorescent microscopy.;These studies improved culture conditions and gene transfer in oyster cells, improved maintenance of oysters in the laboratory, and documented gene transfer and gene expression in oyster gametes, larvae, and adults. This is the first report of gene transfer in the eastern oyster."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by John Terrell Buchanan.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: B, page: 6600."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960042</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43349550</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000126</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1920978</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 BUCH</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960042</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 BUCH</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
