<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Effects of the 4 X 4 block schedule on teacher behavior and student engagement rate at the high school level</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Soniat, Karen Meredith</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1954-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Educational Leadership, Research and Counseling.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>1999</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 252 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>253 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Numerous educators have suggested that traditional scheduling practices in the nation's schools have contributed to the inability of teachers to utilize ""proven"" instructional techniques. This study examined the effects of the 4 x 4 block schedule on teaching behavior and student engagement rate in four core curriculum areas in 21 Louisiana high schools.;This causal-comparative, ex-post facto study involved three group of schools matched to the extent possible on student population, free/reduced lunch, and community type. The 250 teachers in the Phase I (quantitative study) sample were randomly selected and measured via classroom observations.;MANOVA results relating to differences on effective teaching behaviors among the three established groups of teachers revealed a significant multivariate effect for scheduling type (Group 1, Three + Years Block Scheduling; Group 2, Two Years Block Scheduling; Group 3, Traditional Scheduling). Teachers across the three groups differed significantly in use of effective teaching behaviors when all effective teaching items were considered together.;Univariate ANOVA results on 15 effective teaching items provided evidence of a significant effect for two dependent variables: ""Appropriately Uses Student Grouping"" and ""Number of Transitions in Modes of Instruction."" Post hoc analysis regarding ""Number of Transitions in Modes of Instruction"" revealed that teachers in both block scheduled groups differed significantly from teachers in traditionally scheduled schools in that block scheduled schools had more transitions, as predicted.;Phase II (qualitative study) involved case study development in two Group 1 schools scoring at the extreme levels on the effective teaching instrument. Six school-level factors were found to have differentially influenced implementation of block scheduling in the two schools: High Expectations; Clear, Articulated Academic Focus; Atmosphere of Professionalism; Spirit of Innovation; Shared Leadership and Decision Making; and Faculty Cohesiveness.;Four recommendations for practice include: (1) certain school-level factors such as school discipline must be controlled so that teachers may focus on improving instruction; (2) shared leadership appears to be necessary for creating accountability and sustaining innovations such as block scheduling; (3) teachers must be provided time to plan professional development activities which are specific to core content areas and research-based if practice is to improve; and (4) there must be agreement on objectives for each course/subject."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Karen Meredith Soniat.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-02, Section: A, page: 4520."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 1999.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9960100</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 1999</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43369836</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000131</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921039</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 1999 SONI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9960100</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 1999 SONI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
