<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>What goes on in cross-language encounters</title>
      <subTitle>the tactics and strategies of interactional grammar</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Stewart, Stuart Lee.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Linguistics.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 324 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>325 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This investigation involves analysis of cross-language encounters (CLEs), spoken discourse between native speakers (NSs) and non-native speakers (NNSs) of Spanish involved in two types of interactions: simulated service encounters and free conversation. I use a multi-tiered framework comprised of: (1) Schiffrin's (1994) functionalist approach, (2) a model of interactional grammar adapted from Ochs, Schegloff and Thompson (1996), and (3) one of the principal assumptions from conversation analysis, which focuses on the organization of interaction, while maintaining that participants' behavior provides evidence for the units, patterns and rules that are a part of all spoken interaction.;Tactics and strategies examined include repetition, repair, and laughter. Repetition is discussed on five levels: (1) production, (2) comprehension, (3) discourse, (4) interpersonal, and (5) interactional (Tannen 1989). Grammatical and pragmatic aspects of repair are reinterpreted in the Vygotskyan (1986) tradition as regulation of speech and are discussed within the framework of accommodation theory (Giles 1973; Giles et al. 1987). Analysis of laughter results in the development of a new typological framework, which reveals an orderly diversity of roles of laughter in spoken interaction and highlights the relationship between laughter and 'face' (Brown and Levinson 1983; Goffman 1967). As with regulation, the face threat of laughter is shown to be contingent upon the nature of the interaction, the relationship between interlocutors and the accommodation level of participants.;A central tenet of my investigation is the notion of the dialogic, which showcases the direct relationship of utterances to interlocutors, as well as to other utterances. Analysis of the negotiated interaction in these CLEs provides information that is vital to understanding the process of second language acquisition because it demonstrates: (1) how NNSs accept unknown input and how they react to feedback on their production, (2) the role of NSs in expediting the acquisition process and their contributions to a learner's developing grammar, and (3) how use of particular tactics and strategies (de Certeau 1984) can influence the balance of power in CLEs."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Stuart Lee Stewart.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-03, Section: A, page: 9670."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9963965</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43685169</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000322</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921206</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 STEW</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9963965</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 STEW</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
