<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Mapping quantitative trait loci controlling the early height growth of longleaf pine and slash pine</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Weng, Changren</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>School of Forestry, Wildlife, and Fisheries.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 116 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>117 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The delay in early height growth (EHG) known as the ""grass stage"" has been one important factor that limits the artificial regeneration of longleaf pine (Pinus palstris Mill.). Genetic improvement of the ""grass stage"" by interspecific hybridization between longleaf pine and slash pine (Pinus elliottii Engelm) followed by recurrent backcrosses aiming at the introgression of genes controlling the EHG from slash pine into longleaf pine may be a solution. Developing markers tightly linked to these genes and using them in backcross breeding programs may speed the process of the introgression. Random amplified polymorphic DNA (RAPD) markers were employed to map the genorne of longleaf pine and slash pine in a (longleaf pine x slash pine) x slash pine BC1 family consisting of 258 progeny. A total of 266 RAPD markers were identified for both the F1 parent and the slash pine parent. One hundred and thirteen of the 150 F1 parent-specific markers were mapped into 17 linkage groups covering a genetic distance of 1338.2cM. Eighty-three of the 116 slash pine parent-specific markers were mapped into 19 linkage groups covering a genetic distance of 994.6cM. Single marker regression and MapMaker/QTL were used to detect QTLs. The two methods gave similar results. By using MapMaker/QTL, a total of 19 putative QTLs were detected for 6 height growth measurements and 6 collar diameter measurements at three growth stages using a LOD threshold of 2.0. Seventeen of the 19 putative QTLs were from the F1 parent and only two were from the slash pine parent. The amount of phenotypic variance explained by the putative QTLs ranged from 3.6 to 11.0%. The derivation of sequence characterized amplified region (SCAR) markers from random amplified polymorphic DNAs (RAPDs) were demonstrated to be feasible. Nine RAPD fragments that segregate in a longleaf pine x slash pine F1 family were cloned and end sequenced. A total of 13 SCAR primer pairs, with lengths between 17 and 24 nucleotides, were developed. Six of the 13 SCARs were found to be polymorphic. The segregation of four of the six polymorphic SCARs was confirmed in 64 longleaf x slash F1 individuals."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Changren Weng.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-03, Section: B, page: 1151."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9963968</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43687280</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000322</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921210</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 WENG</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9963968</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 WENG</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
