<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Optimization of gas well completion and production practices</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>McMullan, John H.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Petroleum Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 101 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>102 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"In water drive gas reservoirs, wells can be completed with a long perforated interval and produced at high rates to minimize abandonment pressure and maximize recovery. Alternatively, the perforations can be limited to the top of the productive interval and the well produced at a low rate in an effort to prevent coning which results in high abandonment pressures if the strength of the aquifer is adequate to support reservoir pressure. This study uses a reservoir simulation coning model to evaluate these two conflicting completion and production practices. The impact of completion interval, gas production rate, and reservoir permeability were evaluated.;Ultimate gas recovery was found to be largely insensitive to variations in perforated interval and production rate in high permeability systems. Ultimate water production, however, was found to increase at high gas rates and lengthened perforated intervals. In lower permeability systems, ultimate gas recovery was found to increase significantly as production rates were increased, while ultimate water production was actually observed to fall. Sensitivity analysis of vertical to horizontal permeability ratio, fluid density contrast, relative permeability, and formation dip did not alter these conclusions.;The conclusion that elevated production rates can be expected to have no detrimental impact on ultimate gas recovery suggests that gas rates should be maximized in low water disposal cost situations. This finding favors the completion of an interval sufficiently long to maximize production rate and thereby insure that gas recovery and present value of gas reserves are maximized. In high water disposal cost situations, however, it should be recognized that this strategy might result in elevated water production in high permeability systems."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by John H. McMullan.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-03, Section: B, page: 1612."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9963954</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43677214</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000321</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921188</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 MCMU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9963954</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 MCMU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
