<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Developing students' understanding of similar figures</title>
      <subTitle>a perceptual approach</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>McNabb, Danny Ray</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1953-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Currriculum &amp; Instruction.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>vii, 134 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>134 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Children encounter and recognize similar figures in their everyday experiences with such things as basketballs, soccer balls, tennis balls, ping-pong balls; or a candy bar that comes in various sizes of the same shape. Yet their school experience with the mathematics of similarity generally does not build on these perceptual intuitions. Traditional mathematics curricula bypass students' visual intuitions and their quantitative understandings, proceeding directly to set piece problems solved by formal algebraic methods. The result for many students is that the topic of similarity contributes to their evolving view of mathematics as a domain of complex procedural methods divorced from their intuitive sense of quantity and space.;The purpose of this study was to explore how to develop students' mathematical understandings of similarity by having quantitative methods evolve from students' visual intuitions about similar figures. The foundation of this curricular approach was a perceptual analysis of similarity consisting of within relationships which are the static relationships within one figure that may be recognized in another, and between relationships which stem from the dynamic perception of one figure as resulting from uniform growth of the other. The curricular strategy encouraged students to verbalize and quantify these perceptual attributes of similar figures, eventually applying quantitative methods to the standard problems encountered in traditional curricula.;The subjects were secondary school students enrolled in two separate geometry classes (one classified as college-bound) which were taught by the researcher over a period of three weeks. Qualitative data were collected and analyzed from video recordings, students' work, and journals.;The results indicated that the students were generally able to represent their perceptual orientations quantitatively, and to utilize quantitative methods to solve problems. However, the between representation was selected by the plurality of students even when a within strategy would have been computationally more convenient. This highlights the observations of other researchers concerning the difficulty of static representations, and suggests a developmental model in which the more accessible dynamic representations of similarity should precede the static approaches. The students in the college-bound class exhibited more overall flexibility than the students in the non-college-bound class."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Danny Ray McNabb.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-03, Section: A, page: 9230."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9963955</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43678131</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000321</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921190</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 MCNA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9963955</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 MCNA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
