<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>An </nonSort>
      <title>investigation of intra-strategic group profiles, performance and reputation</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Ferguson, Tamela Dawn.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Business Administration.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 164 leaves : ill. (some col.) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>164 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Current strategic group research generally provides collectively meaningful assessments of strategic group averages or median-based profiles. While this approach facilitates inter-group contrasts and performance predictions, potentially valuable information contained in intra-group differences (i.e., core-periphery-fringe zones) typically is overlooked. This multi-study research adopts a more fine-grained approach to strategic group analysis by investigating intra-group competitive profile and performance differences across such zones, both within and across groups. Study I of this series identifies intra-strategic group zones that differ in strategic competitive profile and performance. Study II assesses how strategic groups and related intra-group zones might change over time, the stability of groups as cohesive units over time, and the performance implications of type, level and distance of firm movement in and out of these strategic group zones. Study III investigates the dynamics of the reputation-strategic competitive position relationships. Ninety-five companies in the property/casualty sector of the insurance industry were studied for the period 1993--1996. Some intra-group zones were found to possess homogeneous segments relative to competitive position and performance, indicating the existence of intra-strategic group structure. Two of three identified strategic groups evidenced isomorphic type activity as competitive profiles of these groups became more alike over the course of the study, perhaps as the result of fundamental environmental changes. Lastly, changes in reputation can be important in understanding causes of strategic competitive profile change."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Tamela Dawn Ferguson.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-03, Section: A, page: 1067.;Directors:  David L. Deephouse; Paul A. Jarley."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9963947</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43696303</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000323</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921237</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 FERG</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9963947</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 FERG</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
