<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Cancer mortality and environment in Louisiana</title>
      <subTitle>a geographical inquiry</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Bark, Mihye</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1963-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Geography and Anthropology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 327 leaves : ill., maps ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>328 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Cancer is one of the most serious health problems in the U.S. Louisiana mortality rates for all sites of cancer have exceeded national rates since 1950. Even though concern about the issues of environmental cancer is growing, conclusive results have not been reported. Previous studies differed in data source, data quality, time of observation, and statistical procedure, making comparison of results problematic.;The spatial patterns of the most common cancer sites in Louisiana (from 1953 to 1993) and their relationships with environmental factors were investigated, using GIS software and statistical software. To provide a clear understanding of how the spatial distributions of cancer mortality rates in Louisiana compared with those in the nation, this research was conducted using data at different geographic levels.;Cancer mortality rates for most parishes in South Louisiana were higher than those of the entire U.S. for all sites combined as well as lung and stomach cancer, individually. Spatial clusterings of cancer mortality rates were tested using factor analysis, spatial autocorrelation and correlograms, and scan statistic. Cancers of all sites combined, lung, and stomach exhibited the strongest positive spatial autocorrelation. In searching for the presence of geographical clusters for lung cancer deaths at parish and census tract levels from 1988 to 1993, results revealed that there was a statistically significant and geographically distinct cluster of lung cancer deaths in southeastern Louisiana from 1988 to 1993.;Stepwise regression analyses were applied to data to examine the relationships between environmental factors and cancer mortality rates. Results showed a positive relationship between cancer (all sites combined) and urban population and a negative relationship between cancer and persons employed in health and education services. Breast cancer mortality rates were significantly positively related to urban residence and education level. Colorectal cancer mortality rates were associated with the type of drinking water. Lung cancer mortality rates were more closely related to occupational variables and agricultural chemicals than any other types of cancer mortality rates. Prostate and stomach cancer mortality rates were positively associated with nonwhite populations."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Mihye Bark.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-03, Section: A, page: 1110."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9963935</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">43678775</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000321</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921198</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 BARK</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9963935</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 BARK</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
