<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Development and evaluation of a mass spectrometer-based continuous emission monitor for organic compound emissions from combustion devices</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Wada, Emmanuel Tijani</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1958-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Engineering Science.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 150 leaves : ill. [2] fold. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>150 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The Mass Spectrometer-based Continuous Emission Monitor (MS-CEM) for organic compounds was developed and evaluated at the Louisiana State University (LSU) Pilot-Scale Rotary Kiln Incinerator (RKI). The MS-CEM consists of stack probe, heat traced sampling line, vacuum pump, particulate filter, Nafion dryer and Extrel mass spectrometer. The Nafion dryer is a special type of dryer that has the ability to remove moisture from the gas sample without removing organic compounds of interest. The mass spectrometer is a quadrupole mass filter. The mass spectrometer includes a computer that controls and optimizes the operation of the unit.;The MS-CEM was tested by injecting a mixture of benzene, toluene, trichloroethylene and dichloroethylene into the baghouse inlet, and a gas sample was continuously extracted from the stack and analyzed for the concentration of these compounds simultaneously on real-time basis. The same procedure was repeated by injecting the organic compounds into a sampling line instead of the baghouse.;The expected concentrations of each component in the stack gas, for the baghouse injection experiment, were calculated and compared with the concentration of each component obtained from the MS-CEM. The results obtained from the MS-CEM, for sampling line injection, were used to calculate the amount of each component detected and quantified. The amount of each component detected and quantify by MS-CEM was compared with the amount of each component in the liquid mixture that was injected into the sampling fine. The Calibration Drift (CD) and the response time were also evaluated. The MS-CEM results were also used to perform modeling of non-ideal flow in the RKI."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Emmanuel Tijani Wada.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3727."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979298</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44274823</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000609</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921348</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 WADA</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979298</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 WADA</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
