<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Evaluation of insecticide resistance in Louisiana adult mosquitoes and the efficacies of selected larvicides</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Bearden, Stacy Lee</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1971-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Entomology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiv, 163 leaves : ill., map ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>164 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Pesticide resistance in Louisiana mosquitoes has never been examined on a state-wide basis. In 1996, first component of this monitoring program examined selected pesticide efficacies and documented current pesticide resistance. Ground ULV-applied FyfanonRTM (96.8% malathion and Pyrocide RTM (96.8% + 1% natural pyrethrum) were applied to caged  Culex quinquefasciatus adults (Denham Springs [Livingston Parish] and Lake Charles [Calcasieu Parish]) and Aedes sollicitans (Vermilion Parish). FyfanonRTM caused significantly different (p &lt; 0.05) mortalities among each species and strain within 24hrs (95%  Aedes, 48% Denham Springs, and 14% Lake Charles). Pyrocide RTM also produced significantly different mortalities (99%, 70%, and 38%, respectively).;Malathion and permethrin were topically applied to 3--5 day old adult mosquitoes from 14 parishes. St. Martin parish Cx. quinquefasciatus  was most susceptible to malathion (2.58 mug/mul), and the Vermilion strain was most resistant (417.05 mug/mul). Resistance is based on a &amp;ge;5-fold resistance ratio. Calcasieu parish strain was least resistant to permethrin (1.93 mug/mul), and the St. Tammany parish strain was most resistant (40.86 mug/mul).;Detecting pesticide resistance by bottle bioassay technique was compared to topical bioassay. Both techniques were effective in detecting resistance for selected Aedes, Anopheles, and Culex species in Louisiana.;Ground ULV 97% malathion was applied to caged Cx. quinquefasciatus  adults from a mosquito abatement district, agrichemical farmland, and a susceptible colony. No significance (p &gt; 0.05) existed in mosquito mortality between the agrichemical area and the abatement district.;Bacillus thuringiensis var. israeliensis (VectoBacRTM WDG and VectoBacRTM 12AS) and Bacillus sphaericus  (VectoLexRTM WDG and VectoLexRTM CG) were applied by air and ground in ratoon rice against Culex larvae. Aerial VectoBac WDG produced poor control (&lt;22%) of Cx. salinarius but excellent control (95%) at 24 hrs by ground application. Except for Day 9 (91% mortality), VectoBac 12AS caused &lt;60% control of  Culex. Aerial VectoLex WDG produced poor control (&lt;45%) of  Culex, but the ground-applied VectoLex WDG resulted in significantly greater Culex mortality (&gt;70%) than the VectoBac formulations. Ground VectoLex CG produced the greatest Culex mortality (75--100% mortality for nine days), whereas aerial VectoLex CG resulted in poor control (&lt;40% for the same period)."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Stacy Lee Bearden.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3385."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979243</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44176155</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000605</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921298</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 BEAR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979243</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 BEAR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
