<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Systematics of the polymorphic North American rat snake (Elaphe obsoleta)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Burbrink, Frank T.</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1970-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Biological Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xiii, 187 leaves : ill., maps ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>188 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The North American rat snake (Elaphe obsoleta) complex is composed of seven uniquely colored subspecies of E. obsoleta and the sister species E. bairdi. Maximum parsimony (MP) and maximum likelihood (ML) analysis of two mitochondrial DNA genes from 73  E. obsoleta and E. bairdi, produced well-supported trees that do not conform to the currently accepted subspecies. Both ML and MP trees were significantly shorter than the trees in which each subspecies was constrained to be monophyletic. The subspecies of E. obsoleta  do not represent genetic lineages. Instead, molecular evidence revealed the existence of four well-supported mtDNA clades confined to particular geographic areas in North America. Lack of genetic variability in each clade of  E. obsoleta may indicate that the lineages expanded from southern glacial refugia recently.;Univariate and multivariate analysis of 67 morphological characters scored from 1006 specimens provided additional statistical support for the existence of the same four evolutionary lineages identified in the molecular phylogeographic study. Specimens could be classified using canonical discriminant function analysis into the four molecular clades better than they could be partitioned into subspecific categories. Moreover, the identification of these subspecies proved difficult when using the traditional characters ascribed to them.;In light of the corroborating molecular and morphological evidence, it is suggested that the recognition of the subspecies of Elaphe obsoleta  be discontinued. Instead, the four molecular clades should be recognized as four species: E. alleghaniensis, E. spiloides, E. obsoleta, and E. bairdi. This research demonstrates that the recognition of subspecies from one or two characters may be detrimental to understanding evolutionary history."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Frank T. Burbrink.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3460."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979251</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44179157</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000605</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921306</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 BURB</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979251</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 BURB</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
