<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Comparative biology and ecology of the Formosan subterranean termite, Coptotermes formosanus Shiraki (Isoptera: Rhinotermitidae) in Louisiana</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Fei, Huixin</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1964-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Entomology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 118 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>119 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"A laboratory study was conducted to investigate the effects of sibship patterns and different origins of colonies on mate mortality and growth of incipient colonies in the subterranean termite, Coptotermes formosanus  Shiraki. Primary reproductives from New Orleans in nonsibling pairs had significantly higher mortality than sibling pairs. The average egg production for sibling and nonsibling pairs showed no overall significance in the first oviposition period, however, the average number of larvae was consistently higher in nonsibling than in sibling-founded colonies from New Orleans. After two years, the average number of eggs or larvae present in nonsibling-founded colonies was significantly higher than sibling-founded colonies from New Orleans. Colonies headed by sibling pairs from Lake Charles showed the highest number of larvae. Either sibling- or nonsibling-founded colonies from Lake Charles had a significantly higher survival rate than colonies from New Orleans. The high mortality of outbred pairs may be an effect of outbreeding depression or disease. The heterozygous offspring by outbred pairs may provide advantages to environmental fluctuations and harbor greater protozoan populations. Differences on survival and production of brood between two areas may represent regional preadaptations.;In a second series of tests, it was determined that termite survival and wood consumption were affected by a complex of factors. Termite cohort at 30&amp;deg;C with initial soldier proportions of 0 up to 10% produced a higher soldier proportion than those at 20, 25, or 33&amp;deg;C. There was a significant interaction of temperature by soldier proportion on termite survival. These two variables could not be isolated in our termite bioassay. C. formosanus  did not significantly increase wood consumption rate as termite density increased. Termite survival and wood consumption rate declined significantly when termite exceeded a density &gt;300 individuals. Termite survival and wood consumption rate significantly increased as wood volume increased. However, there was no significant influence of wood surface area on consumption rate and survival, given a constant wood volume. Moisture is a precondition for colonization by C. formosanus queens and kings. Nitrogenous compounds of urea or L-glutamic acid in the moist substrate did not increase nest site preference."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Huixin Fei.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3387."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979258</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44190334</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000606</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921316</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 FEI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979258</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 FEI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
