<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Advanced oxidation processes for remediation of explosives-contaminated soils</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Fleming, Elizabeth C. (Elizabeth Covington)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1965-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Civil and Environmental Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>2 v. (xvi, 448) leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>449 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Explosives contamination in soils is an environmental concern for the public due to their toxic effects. The United States Department of Defense (DoD) is particularly concerned with explosives contamination in soils due to the thousands of sites for which it is responsible for remediating. To date, the most common technology utilized for remediating explosives contamination in soils has been incineration. However, costs for incineration have been estimated to range from approximately $250 to $3250 per ton and are generally inversely related to the volume of soil.;The use of advanced oxidation processes (AOPs), including dark and illuminated forms, was evaluated as an alternative to incineration. The dark processes involve the use of oxidizers without ultraviolet illumination. Dark AOPs evaluated during this study were Fenton's reagent (hydrogen peroxide and ferrous salts), peroxone (a mixture of hydrogen peroxide and ozone), and ultrasonics. The illuminated processes involve the use of ultraviolet illumination which supplies the photon energy to break chemical bonds. Two types of ultraviolet lights were evaluated during this study; low pressure ultraviolet light (LPUV) and medium pressure ultraviolet light (MPUV).;Only soils from the Yorktown Naval Weapons Station (YNWS), Newport News, Virginia, were used. They contained approximately 1430 mg/kg trinitrotoluene (TNT), 4.5 mg/kg trinitrobenzene (TNB), 35.4 mg/kg cyclotetramethylene-tranitrainine (HMX), and 36.8 mg/kg hexahydro-1,3,5-trinitro-1,3,5-triazine (RDX). Since HMX and RDX concentrations were below the treatment criteria prior to testing, TNT and TNB were the main focus. Dark AOPs were applied to soil slurries and filtrate from soil slurries while illuminated AOPs were applied to raw soil and filtrate from soil slurries.;Based on preliminary evaluations, peroxone and LPUV/ozone treatment of filtrate from a YNWS soil slurry were selected for optimization. Optimization involved evaluation of treatment time, three solids loadings, and two oxidizer concentrations for each oxidizer. The optimal LPUV/ozone treatment was 20% solids and 2% ozone. The optimal peroxone treatment was 20% solids, 100 parts per million (ppm) hydrogen peroxide, and 2% ozone. Degradation rates were first order with respect to TNT, HMX, and RDX and were first order intermediate with respect to TNB."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Elizabeth C. Fleming.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3731."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979260</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44192714</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000607</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921318</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 FLEM V.1 378.76 L930D 2000 FLEM V.2</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979260</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 FLEM V.1 378.76 L930D 2000 FLEM V.2</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
