<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Multiple bus networks for binary-tree algorithms</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Dharmasena, Hettihewage P. (Hettihewage Prasanna)</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 147 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>148 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Multiple bus networks (MBN) connect processors via buses. This dissertation addresses issues related to running binary-tree algorithms on MBNs. These algorithms are of a fundamental nature, and reduce inputs at leaves of a binary tree to a result at the root. We study the relationships between running time, degree (maximum number of connections per processor) and loading (maximum number of connections per bus). We also investigate fault-tolerance, meshes enhanced with MBNs, and VLSI layouts for binary-tree MBNs.;We prove that the loading of optimal-time, degree-2, binary-tree MBNs is non-constant. In establishing this result, we derive three loading lower bounds   Wn  ,   W&amp;parl0;n23&amp;parr0;   and   W&amp;parl0;nlogn&amp;parr0;  , each tighter than the previous one. We also show that if the degree is increased to 3, then the loading can be a constant. A constant loading degree-2 MBN exists, if the algorithm is allowed to run slower than the optimal.;We introduce a new enhanced mesh architecture (employing binary-tree MBNs) that captures features of all existing enhanced meshes. This architecture is more flexible, allowing all existing enhanced mesh results to be ported to a more implementable platform.;We present two methods for imparting tolerance to bus and processor faults in binary-tree MBNs. One of the methods is general, and can be used with any MBN and for both processor and bus faults. A key feature of this method is that it permits the network designer to designate a set of buses as ""unimportant"" and consider all faulty buses as unimportant. This minimizes the impact of faulty elements on the MBN. The second method is specific to bus faults in binary-tree MBNs, whose features it exploits to produce faster solutions.;We also derive a series of results that distill the lower bound on the perimeter layout area of optimal-time, binary-tree MBNs to a single conjecture. Based on this we believe that optimal-time, binary-tree MBNs require no less area than a balanced tree topology even though such MBNs can reuse buses over various steps of the algorithm."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by H. P. Dharmasena.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3747."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979254</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44179591</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000605</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921309</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 DHAR</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979254</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 DHAR</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
