<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <nonSort>The </nonSort>
      <title>effects of comparative advertising format on consumer responses</title>
      <subTitle>the moderating effects of brand image and attribute relevance</subTitle>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Yagci, Mehmet Ismail.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Interdepartmental Program in Business Administration (Marketing)</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xii, 194 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>195 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Comparative advertising has become a popular and powerful promotion tactic for companies competing in a highly competitive marketplace. While most research examined comparison advertisements, focusing on one brand being compared to a competitor brand, ""within-brand comparison"" advertising has been neglected. Within-brand comparison advertising compares the attributes of an extension brand with the attributes of an original or replaced brand.;This dissertation examines the relative effectiveness of two forms of comparative advertising tactics, ""within-brand comparison"" versus ""across-brand comparison"". The moderating effects of ""brand image"" and ""attribute relevance"" and the mediating effect of ""ad believability"" are also assessed by an experiment.;Based on the Persuasion Knowledge Model and the Characterization-Correction Model, the results revealed that across-brand comparison ads resulted in lower ad believability, attitude toward the ad, attitude toward the brand, purchase intention, and more counterargurnents and tactics-related cognitions than within-brand comparison ads under low brand image and attribute irrelevance conditions. Interaction effects were assessed under the conditions of high brand image and attribute relevance. The findings implied that high-image brands enjoy the flexibility of using both types of comparative ads as long as they are employing relevant attributes. On the other hand, low-image brands are more likely to benefit from only within-brand comparison ads employing relevant attributes. It was also found that the within-brand comparison ads resulted in more favorable consumer responses than the across-brand comparison ads irrespective of attribute relevance. However, the results also suggest that low-image brands should prefer within-brand comparison ads to across-brand comparison ads and avoid using irrelevant attributes.;Overall, within-brand comparison ads seem to result in more favorable outcomes than across-brand comparison ads while avoiding the potential risks of legal problems, competitor retaliations, and brand confusion."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Mehmet Ismail Yagci.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: A, page: 2819."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979302</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44194050</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000607</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921322</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 YAGC</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979302</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 YAGC</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
