<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Ecology of seagrass fishes and macroinvertebrates on Guatemala's Atlantic coast</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Arrivillaga, Alejandro</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1960-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Oceanography and Coastal Sciences.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 155 leaves : ill., maps ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>156 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The ecology of fishes and macroinvertebrates inhabiting shallow seagrass beds was studied at Bahia La Graciosa, located in Amatique Bay in the Caribbean coast of Guatemala. The study area included extensive turtle grass, Thalassia testudinum, meadows over muddy substrate, whereas a more exposed shoreline also supported turtle grass meadows over sandy substrates outside the bay. A total of 166 samples were collected across two seasons and habitat types in three sampling trips to the area with a cylindrical drop sampler. Diversity and abundance of fishes and macroinvertebrates inhabiting seagrass and adjacent bare-sand sites were described to assess the relative importance of seagrasses as nurseries. Utilization of seagrass meadows by fishes and decapod crustaceans was also described for exposed (beach) and protected (bay) habitat types. Seagrass fish and decapod crustacean community structure was compared between beach and bay habitat types during rainy and dry season months. Total crustacean and fish densities, species diversity, and evenness were several times higher in seagrass beds compared to bare-sand substrates, with no significant differences in gastropod densities between habitats. The majority of the fishes collected on seagrass were juveniles, supporting the hypothesis that seagrass is an important nursery habitat. When comparing beach and bay habitat sites, total fish and decapod crustacean densities were similar, but densities of individual species differed significantly between habitat types. Over half of the species were present in both seasons and almost half of the species were present in both habitat types; however, significant interactions were detected between season and habitat for densities of the most abundant species. Significant differences in fish and decapod crustacean community structures were detected with analyses of similarities between habitat types, but the same analyses between seasons were significant only for fishes. An analysis of complex ecological gradients revealed that the highest variability was related, in decreasing order, to seagrass abundance, habitat type, and seasonal variables."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Alejandro Arrivillaga.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3374."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979241</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44175951</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000605</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921296</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 ARRI</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979241</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 ARRI</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
