<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Magnetic measurements of rare earth hexaborides</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Teklu, Alem (Alem Abraha)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1962-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Physics and Astronomy.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 113 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>114 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"The de Haas van Alphen (dHvA) effect is used, using the field modulation method, to study the orientation dependence of the extremal cross-sectional areas of the Fermi surface (FS) and effective masses of CexLa 1--xB6 alloys for x between 0 and 0.05.;Previous measurements on these samples, using the pulsed field method, up to x = 1 showed that the FS was spin polarized at very low Ce concentration, at x = 0.05, indicating a spin polarity-dependent scattering mechanism. Moreover, the effective mass was enhanced by the increase of Ce concentration. This was the motivation for the present work which is to study in detail the topology of the FS and measure effective masses at these low Ce concentrations. The dHvA frequency corresponding to the alpha3 orbit of pure LaB 6 for the magnetic field parallel to the [100] axis has a value of (7.89 +/- 0.004)kT, which is in very good agreement with the original measurements on this sample. The effective mass of such an orbit is also found to be (0.66 +/- 0.03)me, which agrees with these measurements. The measurements on all samples 0 &amp;le; x &amp;le; 0.05, for this field direction, indicate that the frequencies corresponding to the alpha3 and alpha 1,2 orbits increase in a simple way with the increase of Ce concentration up to 5%. Similarly, the effective mass and the charge carrier density exhibit such behavior showing the gradual transformation of the ground state from light metal LaB6 to heavy Fermion CeB6.;The angular dependence of the dHvA frequencies corresponding to the (alpha 3 and alpha1,2 orbits confirms the assumption that the FS is an ellipsoid of revolution centered at the X points of the Brillouin zone.;The development of the FS from spin unpolarized LaB6 to complete polarization to the spin up state at 5% Ce in LaB6 is shown in great detail. This is in agreement with one of the existing theories.;Similar measurements were performed on ferromagnetic EuB6, and the FS and effective masses were determined."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Alem Teklu.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3657."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979296</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44227155</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000607</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921334</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 TEKL</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979296</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 TEKL</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
