<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Effects of suggestive questioning on women's self-report of pain information following colposcopy</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Guth, Jodie Rabalais.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Psychology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 191 leaves ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>192 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"This study examined the effects of suggestive questioning on women's retrospective ratings of pain and anxiety experienced during colposcopy. The wording of questions was varied between participants (Pain Suggesting, Pain Denying, or No Suggestion). Number of recall sessions was also varied between participants in that some participants completed two ratings (Immediate and Delayed Recall) while others completed only one rating (Delayed Recall). Trait anxiety, pain severity at the time of the memory task, and medical procedure (whether or not the patient underwent a biopsy) were included in the analyses as covariates. Ratings of sensory and affective pain severity as well as pain frequency were the primary dependent variables in MANCOVA. Survey information was also collected regarding patients' suggestions for improving compliance with medical follow-up. Results indicated that the multivariate Suggestion effect was weak at Delayed Recall (p &lt; .077) when the entire sample was included, but was highly significant when participants were excluded who were either incorrect or unsure as to whether or not they had undergone a biopsy (p &lt; .005). Specifically, suggestive information was found to significantly alter ratings of affective pain severity in the direction of the suggestive information. No main effect of Number of Recall Sessions was noted, nor was there a significant Suggestion by Number of Recall Sessions interaction. Correlational data indicated significant associations between pain ratings and anxiety, but the relationship between current pain and retrospective ratings was not supported. Survey data indicated that women want more information about what to expect during colposcopic examination. Problems with the study are discussed, and suggestions for practical applications of the findings are offered."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Jodie Rabalais Guth.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-07, Section: B, page: 3844."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9979263</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44261530</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000608</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921340</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 GUTH</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9979263</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 GUTH</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
