<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Theoretical and experimental studies of flame-generated agglomerates using light scattering</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Shu, Guocai</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1967-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Mechanical Engineering.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>viii, 230 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>231 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Knowledge of optical properties and morphological characteristics of aggregated aerosols is important for pollution control, material synthesis through the aerosol route, oxidation of particulate matters, as well as understanding the mechanism of particulate formation and growth. However, the limitations of current light scattering theories as well as the lack of robust data inversion schemes render the complete characterization of the agglomerated structures difficult and time consuming.;The objective of present work is to develop robust experimental and theoretical methods to characterize the aggregated aerosols from in-situ classical light scattering (CLS) as well as dynamic light scattering (DLS) measurements.;In the context of classical light scattering, the following have been accomplished: (a) The theoretical formulation of light scattering for agglomerates consisting of Rayleigh particles developed by Lou and Charalampopoulos (LC) was evaluated through the use of reciprocity theorem and by comparison with the exact solution such as T-matrix method for aggregates; (b) A new robust criterion for determining the suitable number of orientations for calculating the averages of scattering properties has been introduced; (c) Based on the framework of LC, a data inversion scheme has been developed to infer the optical properties and the morphological parameters of combustion generated chain-like aggregates from classical light scattering measurements; (d) This methodology has been extended to incorporate the effect of polydispersity of the aggregates in the data inversion; and (e) Experimental investigations in iron pentacarbonyl seeded CO diffusion flames have been performed and good agreements with ex situ TEM analysis have been achieved using the data inversion scheme.;In the context of dynamic light scattering, polarized and depolarized dynamic light scattering measurements have been conducted and the behavior of the experimental results has been analyzed. Moreover, the morphological parameters of chain-like agglomerates have been obtained from the measured diffusion coefficients of the agglomerates. It was demonstrated that the effects of the Gaussian term in the analysis of the measured correlation function may not be neglected."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Guocai Shu.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-08, Section: B, page: 4367."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9984365</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44787781</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000815</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921509</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 SHU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9984365</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 SHU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
