<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Boron-uptake mechanisms and boron nutrition of rice</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Yu, Xiaohe</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1963-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Agronomy.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>xi, 146 leaves : ill. (some col.) ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>147 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"There are very few studies on B deficiency in rice (Oryza sativa  L.). Reported critical values of B deficiency in rice are contradictory and mechanisms of B uptake by plant are not understood. Objectives of this study were to determine B effects on rice grown in hydroponics and soil; to determine critical values of B deficiency in rice tissues, hydroponic solution and soil; and to explore B-uptake mechanisms in both monocots (rice) and dicots (soybean (Glycine max L.)).;Rice was grown to maturity in an acid Caddo silt loam at 0 and 1 kg B ha--1 in a greenhouse study, which provided the first report of B deficiency in rice grown on a soil from the USA. Boron increased B concentrations in new leaves, pollen vitality, and grain yields by 11%. Critical value of B deficiency in new rice leaves at tillering or booting is likely 6.0 +/- 1.0 mg B kg--1. A Ca/B ratio above 550 in rice leaves at booting would also indicate B deficiency. Retarded panicle development and delayed heading were observed at tillering and booting. Hydroponic studies indicated that B deficiency occurred when there was &lt;7.3 mg B kg --1 in new leaves and &lt;0.2 muM in solutions. Whitish and twisted new leaf tips occurred at &amp;le;0.05 muM B, and pale bands 2--3 mm wide exhibited on leaves of moderately B-deficient plants. The membrane permeability coefficient of H3BO3 was determined to be 0.488 x 10--6 cm s--1 for rice roots and 1.81 x 10--1 cm s--1  for soybean roots.;Estimating boron diffusion during the six-hour assay is a novel and accurate technique for determining the importance of diffusion, transpirational flow, and active uptake mechanisms. It was estimated that 59% of total B uptake for rice and 39% for soybean were due to active uptake for B-deficient plants. Significant effects were found from respiration inhibitors (0.05 mM DNP) on B uptake by B-deficient rice grown in solutions at four levels of B (0.2, 0.5, 2.5 and 10 muM) during a six-hour assay."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Yu,Xiaohe.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-08, Section: B, page: 3927."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9984377</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44791163</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000815</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921518</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 YU</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9984377</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 YU</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
