<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Insecticide resistance and resistance mechanisms in the southern house mosquito, Culex quinquefasciatus</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary" nameTitleGroup="1">
      <namePart>Stancil, Jeffrey D. (Jeffrey Dwayne)</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1970-</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)</namePart>
      <namePart>Dept. of Entomology.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator"/>
         <roleTerm type="code" authority="marcrelator"/>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</typeOfResource>
   <genre authority="marcgt">theses</genre>
   <genre authority="marcgt">government publication</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <place>
         <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">-us</placeTerm>
      </place>
      <dateCreated>2000</dateCreated>
      <issuance>monographic</issuance>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
      <reformattingQuality>access</reformattingQuality>
      <internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType>
      <extent>x, 122 leaves : ill. ; 29 cm.</extent>
      <extent>123 p.</extent>
   </physicalDescription>
   <abstract type="Abstract">"Significant resistance to malathion and resmethrin was found in insecticide-treated field populations of adult Culex quinquefasciatus , Say, compared with a laboratory and non-treated field strain. Resistance to both insecticides varied during the active control season and was associated with the frequency of insecticide application. Geographic variations in resistance levels were noted, and significant differences occurred between separate populations within the same mosquito control districts.;Four model substrates were assessed for their suitability in detecting elevated esterase activity associated with malathion resistance. Esterase activities towards all substrates were significantly higher in field stains than a laboratory strain. Esterase activities toward the widely used substrates, alpha and beta-naphthyl acetates, were equivalent or significantly higher than activities toward the alternative substrates alpha and beta-naphthyl propionates, suggesting that the naphthyl acetates provide a more sensitive measure of esterase activities in mosquito populations.;Synergist and biochemical assays were used to study mechanisms associated with malathion and resmethrin resistance in field populations of  Cx. quinquefasciatus. Pretreatment with an esterase inhibitor (DEF) significantly reduced malathion resistance. Resmethrin resistance was completely suppressed in mosquitoes pretreated with the oxidase inhibitor, piperonyl butoxide. Results of biochemical assays suggest the involvement of enhanced esterase and oxidase activities in malathion and resmethrin resistance, respectively. Additionally, malathion resistance was associated with reduced inhibition of acetylcholinesterase (AChE), the target site of organophosphate and carbamate insecticides. Selection with malathion resulted in a significant increase in esterase activities and reduced AChE inhibition.;The effects of developmental stage, sex, age, and blood feeding on expression of malathion and resmethrin resistance was also evaluated. Significant variations in resistance and expression of resistance mechanisms occurred between larvae and adults and male and female adults. In female Cx. quinquefasciatus , malathion resistance declined with age and was associated with a decrease in esterase activity. Resmethrin resistance also declined with age, but was not related to a reduction in peroxidase activity. Results of this study indicate that life history characteristics can have significant effects on the expression of insecticide resistance and suggests that their impact on field control should be further evaluated."</abstract>
   <note type="statement of responsibility" altRepGroup="00">by Jeffrey D. Stancil.</note>
   <note>"Source: Dissertation Abstracts International, Volume: 61-08, Section: B, page: 3973."</note>
   <note type="thesis">Thesis (Ph.D.)--Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, 2000.</note>
   <location>
      <url displayLabel="electronic resource" usage="primary display">http://gateway.proquest.com/openurl?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:dissertation&amp;res_dat=xri:pqm&amp;rft_dat=xri:pqdiss:9984367</url>
   </location>
   <relatedItem type="series">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Dissertation (Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.)) ; 2000</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="oclc">44781823</identifier>
   <recordInfo>
      <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
      <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">000814</recordCreationDate>
      <recordIdentifier source="SIRSI">u1921503</recordIdentifier>
      <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <identifier type="dewey">378.76 L930D 2000 STAN</identifier>
   <identifier type="dewey">9984367</identifier>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>LUU</physicalLocation>
      <physicalLocation>LSU Libraries</physicalLocation>
      <url>http://www.lib.lsu.edu</url>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <subLocation>Middleton Stacks</subLocation>
            <shelfLocator>378.76 L930D 2000 STAN</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <note type="ownership">
            LSU Libraries, Baton Rouge, La., http://lib.lsu.edu/
        </note>
   <accessCondition type="restriction on access">
            Physical rights are retained by LSU Libraries. LSU makes no claim to the intellectual property contained within.
            The user must assume full responsibility for any use of the materials, including but not limited to,
            infringement of copyright and publication rights of reproduced materials. Any materials used for academic 
            research or otherwise should be fully credited with the source.
        </accessCondition>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">
            To provide comments about this digital project, email lsudiglib@lsu.edu. To inquire about ordering 
            copies of these images, email libilb@lsu.edu. Mention the "Identifier" in your request. Providing 
            reproductions does not constitute permission to publish or reproduce images in print or electronic form.
        </accessCondition>
</mods>
